<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="different[1]"><ew>different</ew><hw hindex="1">dif*fer*ent</hw><sound><wav>differ04.wav</wav></sound><pr>ˈdi-fərnt, ˈdi-f(ə-)rənt</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English, from Latin <it>different-, differens,</it> present participle of <it>differre</it> <dx_ety>(see <dxt>differ</dxt>)</dx_ety></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:partly or totally <d_link>unlike</d_link> in nature, form, or quality :<sx>dissimilar</sx> <vi>could hardly be more <it>different</it></vi> <un>often followed by <it>from, than,</it> or chiefly British <it>to</it> <vi>small, neat hand, very <it>different</it> from the captain's tottery characters <aq>R. L. Stevenson</aq></vi> <vi>vastly <it>different</it> in size than it was twenty-five years ago <aq>N. M. Pusey</aq></vi> <vi>a very <it>different</it> situation to the … one under which we live <aq>Sir Winston Churchill</aq></vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt> :not the same: as</dt>  <sn>a</sn> <dt>:<sx>distinct</sx> <vi><it>different</it> age groups</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>various</sx> <vi><it>different</it> members of the class</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:<sx>another</sx> <vi>switched to a <it>different</it> TV program</vi> </dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:<sx>unusual</sx> <sx>special</sx> <vi>she was <it>different</it> and superior</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>dif*fer*ent*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>different</sc> <sc>diverse</sc> <sc>divergent</sc> <sc>disparate</sc> <sc>various</sc> mean unlike in kind or character. <sc>different</sc> may imply little more than separateness but it may also imply contrast or contrariness <vi><it>different</it> foods</vi>. <sc>diverse</sc> implies both distinctness and marked contrast <vi>such <it>diverse</it> interests as dancing and football</vi>. <sc>divergent</sc> implies movement away from each other and unlikelihood of ultimate meeting or reconciliation <vi>went on to pursue <it>divergent</it> careers</vi>. <sc>disparate</sc> emphasizes incongruity or incompatibility <vi><it>disparate</it> notions of freedom</vi>. <sc>various</sc> stresses the number of sorts or kinds <vi>tried <it>various</it> methods</vi>.</pt><pl>usage</pl><pt>Numerous commentators have condemned <it>different than</it> in spite of its use since the 17th century by many of the best-known names in English literature. It is nevertheless standard and is even recommended in many handbooks when followed by a clause, because insisting on <it>from</it> in such instances often produces clumsy or wordy formulations. <it>Different from,</it> the generally safe choice, is more common especially when it is followed by a noun or pronoun.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="different[2]"><ew>different</ew><hw hindex="2">dif*fer*ent</hw><sound><wav>differ04.wav</wav></sound><pr>ˈdi-fərnt, ˈdi-f(ə-)rənt</pr><fl>adverb</fl><et><dx_ety>(see <dxt>different</dxt>)</dx_ety></et><def><date>1744</date><dt>:<sx>differently</sx></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>