<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="free[1]"><ew>free</ew><subj>GR-11d#NA-13#LG-6#SG-8d#GV-4#LW-4#BZ-4a#AC-11a(2)#GV-1#LW-1#GV-14#SP-8e#EC-10#CH-11b,c#GR-12a#LN-12a#PY-8c#PY-11c</subj><hw hindex="1">free</hw><sound><wav>free0001.wav</wav><wpr>!frE</wpr></sound><pr>ˈfrē</pr><fl>adjective</fl><in><if>fre*er</if></in><in><if>fre*est</if></in><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>frēo;</it> akin to Old High German <it>frī</it> free, Welsh <it>rhydd,</it> Sanskrit <it>priya</it> own, dear</et><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:having the legal and political rights of a citizen</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:enjoying civil and political liberty <vi><it>free</it> citizens</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:enjoying political independence or <fw>freedom</fw> from outside domination</dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:enjoying personal freedom :not subject to the control or domination of another</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:not determined by anything beyond its own nature or being :choosing or capable of choosing for itself</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:determined by the choice of the actor or performer <vi><it>free</it> actions</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:made, done, or given voluntarily or spontaneously</dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:relieved from or lacking something and especially something unpleasant or burdensome <vi><it>free</it> from pain</vi> <vi>a speech <it>free</it> of political rhetoric</vi> <un>often used in combination <vi>error<it>-free</it></vi></un></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not bound, confined, or detained by force</dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:having no trade restrictions</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not subject to government regulation</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <ssl>of foreign exchange</ssl> <dt>:not subject to restriction or official control</dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:having no obligations (as to work) or commitments <vi>I'll be <it>free</it> this evening</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not taken up with commitments or obligations <vi>a <it>free</it> evening</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:having a scope not restricted by qualification <vi>a <it>free</it> variable</vi></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt>:not obstructed, restricted, or impeded <vi><it>free</it> to leave</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not being used or occupied <vi>waved with his <it>free</it> hand</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:not hampered or restricted in its normal operation</dt> <sn>8 a</sn> <dt>:not fastened <vi>the <it>free</it> end of the rope</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not confined to a particular position or place <vi>in twelve-tone music, no note is wholly <it>free</it> for it must hold its place in the series <aq>J. L. Stewart</aq></vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:capable of moving or turning in any direction <vi>a <it>free</it> particle</vi></dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:performed without apparatus <vi><it>free</it> tumbling</vi></dt>  <sn>e</sn> <dt>:done with artificial aids (as pitons) used only for protection against falling and not for support <vi>a <it>free</it> climb</vi></dt> <sn>9 a</sn> <dt>:not parsimonious <vi><it>free</it> spending</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>outspoken</sx></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:availing oneself of something without stint</dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:<sx>frank</sx> <sx>open</sx></dt>  <sn>e</sn> <dt>:overly familiar or forward in action or attitude</dt>  <sn>f</sn> <dt>:<sx>licentious</sx></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:not costing or charging anything</dt> <sn>11 a <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:not united with, attached to, combined with, or mixed with something else :<sx>separate</sx> <vi><it>free</it> ores</vi> <vi>a <it>free</it> surface of a bodily part</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:<sx>freestanding</sx> <vi>a <it>free</it> column</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:chemically uncombined <vi><it>free</it> oxygen</vi> <vi><it>free</it> acids</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:not permanently attached but able to move about <vi>a <it>free</it> electron in a metal</vi></dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:capable of being used alone as a meaningful linguistic form <vi>the word <it>hats</it> is a <it>free</it> form</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>bound <dxn>7</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>12 a</sn> <dt>:not literal or exact <vi><it>free</it> translation</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not restricted by or conforming to conventional forms <vi><it>free</it> skating</vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt>:<sx>favorable</sx> <un>used of a wind blowing from a direction more than six points from dead ahead</un></dt> <sn>14</sn> <dt>:not allowing slavery</dt> <sn>15</sn> <dt>:open to all comers</dt></def><uro><ure>free*ness</ure><sound><wav>free0002.wav</wav><wpr>!frE-nus</wpr></sound> <pr>-nəs</pr> <fl>noun</fl></uro><dro><drp>for free</drp> <def><dt>:without charge</dt></def></dro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>free</sc> <sc>independent</sc> <sc>sovereign</sc> <sc>autonomous</sc> mean not subject to the rule or control of another. <sc>free</sc> stresses the complete absence of external rule and the full right to make all of one's own decisions <vi>you're <it>free</it> to do as you like</vi>. <sc>independent</sc> implies a standing alone; applied to a state it implies lack of connection with any other having power to interfere with its citizens, laws, or policies <vi>the colony's struggle to become <it>independent</it></vi>. <sc>sovereign</sc> stresses the absence of a superior power and implies supremacy within a thing's own domain or sphere <vi>separate and <it>sovereign</it> armed services</vi>. <sc>autonomous</sc> stresses independence in matters pertaining to self-government <vi>in this denomination each congregation is regarded as <it>autonomous</it></vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="free[2]"><ew>free</ew><hw hindex="2">free</hw><fl>verb</fl><in><if>freed</if></in><in><if>free*ing</if></in><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to cause to be free</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to relieve or rid of what restrains, confines, restricts, or embarrasses <vi><it>free</it> a person from debt</vi> <un>often used with <it>up</it> <vi><it>free</it> up space on the hard drive</vi></un></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:<sx>disentangle</sx> <sx>clear</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>obsolete</ssl> <dt>:<sx>banish</sx></dt></def><uro><ure>fre*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>free</sc> <sc>release</sc> <sc>liberate</sc> <sc>emancipate</sc> <sc>manumit</sc> mean to set loose from restraint or constraint. <sc>free</sc> implies a usually permanent removal from whatever binds, confines, entangles, or oppresses <vi><it>freed</it> the animals from their cages</vi>. <sc>release</sc> suggests a setting loose from confinement, restraint, or a state of pressure or tension, often without implication of permanent liberation <vi><it>released</it> his anger on a punching bag</vi>. <sc>liberate</sc> stresses particularly the resulting state of liberty <vi><it>liberated</it> their country from the tyrant</vi>. <sc>emancipate</sc> implies the liberation of a person from subjection or domination <vi>labor-saving devices <it>emancipated</it> us from household drudgery</vi>. <sc>manumit</sc> implies emancipation from slavery <vi>the document <it>manumitted</it> the slaves</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="free[3]"><ew>free</ew><subj>NA-3</subj><hw hindex="3">free</hw><fl>adverb</fl><def><date>1559</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:in a free manner</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:without charge</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:with the wind more than six points from dead ahead <vi>sailing <it>free</it></vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="freer"><ew>freer</ew><hw>freer</hw><cx><cl>comparative of</cl> <ct>free</ct></cx></entry>
	<entry id="freest"><ew>freest</ew><hw>freest</hw><cx><cl>superlative of</cl> <ct>free</ct></cx></entry>
	<entry id="free agent"><ew>free agent</ew><subj>SP</subj><hw>free agent</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1955</date><dt>:a professional athlete (as a baseball player) who is free to negotiate a contract with any team</dt></def><uro><ure>free agency</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="free alongside ship"><ew>free alongside ship</ew><grp>free alongside</grp><grp>free ship</grp><grp>alongside ship</grp><subj>TN</subj><hw>free alongside ship</hw><fl>adverb or adjective</fl><def><date>1888</date><dt>:with delivery at the side of the ship free of charges and the buyer's liability then beginning</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="free and easy"><ew>free and easy</ew><grp>free and</grp><grp>free easy</grp><grp>and easy</grp><hw>free and easy</hw><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1699</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:marked by informality and lack of constraint <vi>the <it>free and easy,</it> open-air life of the plains <aq>Allan Murray</aq></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:not observant of strict demands <vi>too <it>free and easy</it> in accepting political contributions</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>free–and–eas*i*ness</ure><sound><wav>free0003.wav</wav><wpr>+frE-un-!(d)E-zE-nus</wpr></sound> <pr>ˌfrē-ən(d)-ˈē-zē-nəs</pr> <fl>noun</fl></uro><uro><ure>free and easy</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="free association"><ew>free association</ew><subj>PS</subj><hw>free association</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1899</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:the expression (as by speaking or writing) of the content of consciousness without censorship as an aid in gaining access to unconscious processes especially in psychoanalysis</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the reporting of the first thought that comes to mind in response to a given stimulus (as a word)</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an idea or image elicited by free association</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a method using free association</dt></def><uro><ure>free–as*so*ci*ate</ure><sound><wav>free0004.wav</wav><wpr>+frE-u-!sO-sE-+At</wpr></sound> <pr>ˌfrē-ə-ˈsō-s(h)ē-ˌāt</pr> <fl>intransitive verb</fl></uro><uro><ure>free–as*so*ci*at*ive</ure><sound><wav>free0005.wav</wav><wpr>+frE-u-!sO-sE-+A-tiv</wpr></sound> <pr>-s(h)ē-ˌā-tiv, -shə-tiv</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="free beach"><ew>free beach</ew><hw>free beach</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1975</date><dt>:a beach at which nudity is permitted</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>