<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="material[1]"><ew>material</ew><subj>PH-1b</subj><hw hindex="1">ma*te*ri*al</hw><sound><wav>materi01.wav</wav><wpr>mu-!tir-E-ul</wpr></sound><pr>mə-ˈtir-ē-əl</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English <it>materiel,</it> from Middle French &amp; Late Latin; Middle French, from Late Latin <it>materialis,</it> from Latin <it>materia</it> matter <ma>matter</ma></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:relating to, derived from, or consisting of matter</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:<sx>physical</sx> <vi>the <it>material</it> world</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:<sx>bodily</sx> <vi><it>material</it> needs</vi></dt>  <sn>b <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:of or relating to matter rather than form <vi><it>material</it> cause</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:of or relating to the subject matter of reasoning</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:<sx>empirical</sx> <vi><it>material</it> knowledge</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:having real importance or great consequences <vi>facts <it>material</it> to the investigation</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:being of a physical or worldly nature</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:relating to or concerned with physical rather than spiritual or intellectual things <vi><it>material</it> progress</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>ma*te*ri*al*ly</ure><sound><wav>materi02.wav</wav><wpr>mu-!tir-E-u-lE</wpr></sound> <pr>-ē-ə-lē</pr> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><uro><ure>ma*te*ri*al*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>material</sc> <sc>physical</sc> <sc>corporeal</sc> <sc>phenomenal</sc> <sc>sensible</sc> <sc>objective</sc> mean of or belonging to actuality. <sc>material</sc> implies formation out of tangible matter; used in contrast with <it>spiritual</it> or <it>ideal</it> it may connote the mundane, crass, or grasping <vi><it>material</it> values</vi>. <sc>physical</sc> applies to what is perceived directly by the senses and may contrast with <it>mental, spiritual,</it> or <it>imaginary</it> <vi>the <it>physical</it> benefits of exercise</vi>. <sc>corporeal</sc> implies having the tangible qualities of a body such as shape, size, or resistance to force <vi>artists have portrayed angels as <it>corporeal</it> beings</vi>. <sc>phenomenal</sc> applies to what is known or perceived through the senses rather than by intuition or rational deduction <vi>scientists concerned with the <it>phenomenal</it> world</vi>. <sc>sensible</sc> stresses the capability of readily or forcibly impressing the senses <vi>the earth's rotation is not <it>sensible</it> to us</vi>. <sc>objective</sc> may stress material or independent existence apart from a subject perceiving it <vi>no <it>objective</it> evidence of damage</vi>.</pt><sa>relevant</sa></entry>
	<entry id="material[2]"><ew>material</ew><subj>TX-1d#CL-1d#ML-2b#PH-1c#ED-1b(2)#ET-1b(3)</subj><hw hindex="2">material</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1556</date> <sn>1 a <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:the elements, constituents, or substances of which something is composed or can be made</dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:matter that has qualities which give it individuality and by which it may be categorized <vi>sticky <it>material</it></vi> <vi>explosive <it>material</it><it>s</it></vi></dt>  <sn>b <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:something (as data) that may be worked into a more finished form <vi><it>material</it> for a biography</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:something used for or made the object of study <vi><it>material</it> for the next semester</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(3)</snp></sn> <dt>:a performer's repertoire <vi>a comedian's <it>material</it></vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:<sx>matter <sxn>3b</sxn></sx></dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:<sx>cloth</sx></dt>  <sn>e</sn> <dt>:a person potentially suited to some pursuit <vi>varsity <it>material</it></vi> <vi>leadership <it>material</it></vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:apparatus necessary for doing or making something <vi>writing <it>material</it><it>s</it></vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>matériel</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="raw material"><ew>raw material</ew><subj>IE</subj><hw>raw material</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1796</date><dt>:crude or processed material that can be converted by manufacture, processing, or combination into a new and useful product <vi>wheat … is <it>raw material</it> for the flour mill <aq>C. A. Koepke</aq></vi></dt> <sd>broadly</sd> <dt>:something with a potential for improvement, development, or elaboration <vi>perplexities are often the <it>raw material</it> of discoveries <aq>Agnes M. Clerke</aq></vi></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>