<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="new[1]"><ew>new</ew><subj>LN-7#AS-4c</subj><hw hindex="1">new</hw><sound><wav>new00001.wav</wav><wpr>!nU</wpr><wav>new00002.wav</wav><wpr>!nyU</wpr></sound><pr>ˈnü, <it>chiefly British</it> ˈnyü, <it>in place names usually</it> (ˌ)nu̇ <it>or</it> nə <it>or</it> (ˌ)ni</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>nīwe;</it> akin to Old High German <it>niuwi</it> new, Latin <it>novus,</it> Greek <it>neos</it></et><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:having recently come into existence :<sx>recent</sx> <sx>modern</sx></dt> <sn>2 a <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:having been seen, used, or known for a short time :<sx>novel</sx> <vi>rice was a <it>new</it> crop for the area</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:<sx>unfamiliar</sx> <vi>visit <it>new</it> places</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:being other than the former or old <vi>a steady flow of <it>new</it> money</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:having been in a relationship or condition but a short time <vi><it>new</it> to the job</vi> <vi>a <it>new</it> wife</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:beginning as the resumption or repetition of a previous act or thing <vi>a <it>new</it> day</vi> <vi>the <it>new</it> edition</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:made or become fresh <vi>awoke a <it>new</it> person</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:relating to or being a new moon</dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:different from one of the same category that has existed previously <vi><it>new</it> realism</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:of dissimilar origin and usually of superior quality <vi>a <it>new</it> strain of hybrid corn</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <slb>capitalized</slb> <dt>:<sx>modern <sxn>3</sxn></sx></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:having been in use after medieval times</dt></def><uro><ure>new*ish</ure><sound><wav>new00003.wav</wav><wpr>!nU-ish</wpr></sound> <pr>ˈnü-ish, ˈnyü-</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><uro><ure>new*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>new</sc> <sc>novel</sc> <sc>original</sc> <sc>fresh</sc> mean having recently come into existence or use. <sc>new</sc> may apply to what is freshly made and unused <vi><it>new</it> brick</vi> or has not been known before <vi><it>new</it> designs</vi> or not experienced before <vi>starts the <it>new</it> job</vi>. <sc>novel</sc> applies to what is not only new but strange or unprecedented <vi>a <it>novel</it> approach to the problem</vi>. <sc>original</sc> applies to what is the first of its kind to exist <vi>a man without one <it>original</it> idea</vi>. <sc>fresh</sc> applies to what has not lost its qualities of newness such as liveliness, energy, brightness <vi>a <it>fresh</it> start</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="new[2]"><ew>new</ew><hw hindex="2">new</hw><fl>adverb</fl><def><date>before 12th century</date><dt>:<sx>newly</sx> <sx>recently</sx> <un>usually used in combination</un></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="new age[1]"><ew>new age</ew><subj>MU-1#RE-1#OC-1#SY-1</subj><hw hindex="1">new age</hw><fl>adjective</fl><lb>often capitalized N&amp;A</lb><def><date>1949</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:of, relating to, or being New Age</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>contemporary</sx> <sx>modern</sx> <vi><it>new age</it> grocery stores</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="new age[2]"><ew>new age</ew><subj>OC-1#PH-1#MU-2#RE-1#SY-1</subj><hw hindex="2">new age</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1971</date> <sn>1</sn> <slb>capitalized</slb> <dt>:an eclectic group of cultural attitudes arising in late 20th century Western society that are adapted from those of a variety of ancient and modern cultures, that emphasize beliefs (as reincarnation, holism, pantheism, and occultism) outside the mainstream, and that advance alternative approaches to spirituality, right living, and health</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a soft soothing form of instrumental music often used to promote relaxation</dt></def><uro><ure>New Ager</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><uro><ure>New Agey</ure><sound><wav>newag01v.wav</wav><wpr>!nU-!A-jE</wpr></sound> <pr>-ˈā-jē</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="new blood"><ew>new blood</ew><hw>new blood</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1851</date><dt>:persons who are accepted into a group or organization and are expected to provide fresh ideas and vitality</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="New Criticism"><ew>New Criticism</ew><subj>LT</subj><hw>New Criticism</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1941</date><dt>:an analytic literary criticism that is marked by concentration on the language, imagery, and emotional or intellectual tensions in literary works</dt></def><uro><ure>New Critic</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><uro><ure>New Critical</ure> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="New Deal"><ew>New Deal</ew><subj>GV#HI</subj><hw>New Deal</hw><fl>noun</fl><et>from the supposed resemblance to the situation of freshness and equality of opportunity afforded by a fresh deal in a card game</et><def><date>1932</date><dt>:the legislative and administrative program of President F. D. Roosevelt designed to promote economic recovery and social reform during the 1930s</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:the period of this program</dt></def><uro><ure>New Dealer</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><uro><ure>New Deal*ish</ure><sound><wav>newcom02.wav</wav><wpr>!nU-!dE-lish</wpr></sound> <pr>-ˈdē-lish</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><uro><ure>New Deal*ism</ure><sound><wav>newcom03.wav</wav><wpr>!nU-!dE(u)-+li-zum</wpr></sound> <pr>-ˈdē(ə)-ˌli-zəm</pr> <fl>noun</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="new drug"><ew>new drug</ew><subj>RX</subj><hw>new drug</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>circa 1951</date><dt>:a drug that has not been declared safe and effective by qualified experts under the conditions prescribed, recommended, or suggested in the label and that may be a new chemical formula or an established drug prescribed for use in a new way</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="new economics"><ew>new economics</ew><subj>EC</subj><hw>new economics</hw><fl>noun plural but usually singular in construction</fl><def><date>1928</date><dt>:an economic concept that is a logical extension of Keynesianism and that holds that appropriate fiscal and monetary maneuvering can maintain healthy economic growth and prosperity indefinitely</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="New English Bible"><ew>New English Bible</ew><grp>New English</grp><grp>New Bible</grp><grp>English Bible</grp><subj>RC#BB</subj><hw>New English Bible</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1957</date><dt>:a translation of the Bible by a British interdenominational committee first published in its entirety in 1970</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>