<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="serious"><ew>serious</ew><hw>se*ri*ous</hw><sound><wav>seriou01.wav</wav><wpr>!sir-E-us</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsir-ē-əs</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English <it>seryows,</it> from Anglo-French or Late Latin; Anglo-French <it>serious,</it> from Late Latin <it>seriosus,</it> alteration of Latin <it>serius</it> weighty, serious; probably akin to Old English <it>swǣr</it> heavy, sad</et><def><date>15th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:thoughtful or subdued in appearance or manner :<sx>sober</sx> <vi>a quiet, <it>serious</it> girl</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:requiring much thought or work <vi><it>serious</it> study</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:of or relating to a matter of importance <vi>a <it>serious</it> play</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:not joking or trifling :being in earnest <vi>a <it>serious</it> question</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:<sx>pious</sx></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:deeply interested :<sx>devoted</sx> <vi>a <it>serious</it> musician</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:not easily answered or solved <vi><it>serious</it> objections</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having important or dangerous possible consequences <vi>a <it>serious</it> injury</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:excessive or impressive in quality, quantity, extent, or degree <vi><it>serious</it> stereo equipment</vi> <vi>making <it>serious</it> money</vi> <vi><it>serious</it> drinking</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>se*ri*ous*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>serious</sc> <sc>grave</sc> <sc>solemn</sc> <sc>sedate</sc> <sc>staid</sc> <sc>sober</sc> <sc>earnest</sc> mean not light or frivolous. <sc>serious</sc> implies a concern for what really matters <vi>a <it>serious</it> play about social injustice</vi>. <sc>grave</sc> implies both seriousness and dignity in expression or attitude <vi>read the proclamation in a <it>grave</it> voice</vi>. <sc>solemn</sc> suggests an impressive gravity utterly free from levity <vi>a sad and <it>solemn</it> occasion</vi>. <sc>sedate</sc> implies a composed and decorous seriousness <vi>remained <it>sedate</it> amid the commotion</vi>. <sc>staid</sc> suggests a settled, accustomed sedateness and prim self-restraint <vi>a quiet and <it>staid</it> community</vi>. <sc>sober</sc> stresses seriousness of purpose and absence of levity or frivolity <vi>a <it>sober</it> look at the state of our schools</vi>. <sc>earnest</sc> suggests sincerity or often zealousness of purpose <vi>an <it>earnest</it> reformer</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="serious-minded"><ew>serious-minded</ew><hw>se*ri*ous–mind*ed</hw><sound><wav>seriou02.wav</wav><wpr>+sir-E-us-!mIn-dud</wpr></sound><pr>ˌsir-ē-əs-ˈmīn-dəd</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1845</date><dt>:having a serious disposition or trend of thought</dt></def><uro><ure>se*ri*ous–mind*ed*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><uro><ure>se*ri*ous–mind*ed*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro></entry>
</entry_list>