<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="special[1]"><ew>special</ew><hw hindex="1">spe*cial</hw><sound><wav>specia01.wav</wav><wpr>!spe-shul</wpr></sound><pr>ˈspe-shəl</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French or Latin; Anglo-French <it>especial,</it> from Latin <it>specialis</it> individual, particular, from <it>species</it> species</et><def><date>13th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:distinguished by some unusual quality</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:being in some way superior <vi>our <it>special</it> blend</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:held in particular esteem <vi>a <it>special</it> friend</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:readily distinguishable from others of the same category :<sx>unique</sx> <vi>they set it apart as a <it>special</it> day of thanksgiving</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:of, relating to, or constituting a <fw>species</fw> :<sx>specific</sx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:being other than the usual :<sx>additional</sx> <sx>extra</sx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:designed for a particular purpose or occasion</dt></def><uro><ure>spe*cial*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>special</sc> <sc>especial</sc> <sc>specific</sc> <sc>particular</sc> <sc>individual</sc> mean of or relating to one thing or class. <sc>special</sc> stresses having a quality, character, identity, or use of its own <vi><it>special</it> ingredients</vi>. <sc>especial</sc> may add implications of preeminence or preference <vi>a matter of <it>especial</it> importance</vi>. <sc>specific</sc> implies a quality or character distinguishing a kind or a species <vi>children with <it>specific</it> nutritional needs</vi>. <sc>particular</sc> stresses the distinctness of something as an individual <vi>a ballet step of <it>particular</it> difficulty</vi>. <sc>individual</sc> implies unequivocal reference to one of a class or group <vi>valued each <it>individual</it> opinion</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="special[2]"><ew>special</ew><subj>BR-2#ET-2</subj><hw hindex="2">special</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1866</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:one that is used for a special service or occasion <vi>caught the commuter <it>special</it> to work</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something (as a television program) that is not part of a regular series</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a featured dish at a restaurant <vi>the <it>special</it><it>s</it> of the day</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="special assessment"><ew>special assessment</ew><subj>EC</subj><hw>special assessment</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1875</date><dt>:a specific tax levied on private property to meet the cost of public improvements that enhance the value of the property</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="special delivery"><ew>special delivery</ew><subj>PO</subj><hw>special delivery</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1870</date><dt>:expedited messenger delivery of mail matter for an extra fee</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="special district"><ew>special district</ew><subj>GV</subj><hw>special district</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1950</date><dt>:a political subdivision of a state established to provide a single public service (as water supply or sanitation) within a specific geographic area</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="special drawing rights"><ew>special drawing rights</ew><grp>special drawing</grp><grp>special rights</grp><grp>drawing rights</grp><subj>EC</subj><hw>special drawing rights</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1967</date><dt>:a means of exchange used by governments to settle their international indebtedness</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="special education"><ew>special education</ew><subj>ED</subj><hw>special education</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1921</date><dt>:classes or instruction designed for students with special educational needs</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="special effects"><ew>special effects</ew><subj>BR#ET</subj><hw>special effects</hw><fl>noun plural</fl><def><date>1937</date><dt>:visual or sound effects introduced into a motion picture, video recording, or taped television production</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="Special Forces"><ew>Special Forces</ew><subj>ML</subj><hw>Special Forces</hw><fl>noun plural</fl><def><date>1955</date><dt>:a branch of the United States Army composed of soldiers specially trained in guerrilla warfare</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="special handling"><ew>special handling</ew><subj>PO</subj><hw>special handling</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1928</date><dt>:the handling of parcel-post or mail as first-class but not as special-delivery matter for an extra fee</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>