<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="attack[1]"><ew>attack</ew><subj>GA-vt5#SP-vi#MD-vt3</subj><hw hindex="1">at*tack</hw><sound><wav>attack01.wav</wav><wpr>u-!tak</wpr></sound><pr>ə-ˈtak</pr><fl>verb</fl><et>Middle French <it>attaquer,</it> from Old Italian <it>*estaccare</it> to attach, from <it>stacca</it> stake, of Germanic origin; akin to Old English <it>staca</it></et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>1562</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to set upon or work against forcefully</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to assail with unfriendly or bitter words</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to begin to affect or to act on injuriously <vi>plants <it>attack</it><it>ed</it> by aphids</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to set to work on <vi><it>attack</it> a problem</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to threaten (a piece in chess) with immediate capture</dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <dt>:to make an attack</dt></def><uro><ure>at*tack*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>attack</sc> <sc>assail</sc> <sc>assault</sc> <sc>bombard</sc> <sc>storm</sc> mean to make an onslaught upon. <sc>attack</sc> implies taking the initiative in a struggle <vi>plan to <it>attack</it> the town at dawn</vi>. <sc>assail</sc> implies attempting to break down resistance by repeated blows or shots <vi><it>assailed</it> the enemy with artillery fire</vi>. <sc>assault</sc> suggests a direct attempt to overpower by suddenness and violence of onslaught <vi>commandos <it>assaulted</it> the building from all sides</vi>. <sc>bombard</sc> applies to attacking with bombs or shells <vi><it>bombarded</it> the city nightly</vi>. <sc>storm</sc> implies attempting to break into a defended position <vi>preparing to <it>storm</it> the fortress</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="attack[2]"><ew>attack</ew><subj>SP-4#MU-7#MD-3a</subj><hw hindex="2">attack</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1655</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the act of <fw>attacking</fw> with physical force or unfriendly words :<sx>assault</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a belligerent or antagonistic action</dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:a fit of sickness</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:an active episode of a chronic or recurrent disease</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a period of being strongly affected by something (as a desire or mood)</dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:an offensive or scoring action <vi>won the game with an 8-hit <it>attack</it></vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:offensive players or the positions taken up by them</dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:the setting to work on some undertaking <vi>made a new <it>attack</it> on the problem</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:the beginning of destructive action (as by a chemical agent)</dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:the act or manner of beginning a musical tone or phrase</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="attack[3]"><ew>attack</ew><subj>ML</subj><hw hindex="3">attack</hw><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1899</date><dt>:designed, planned, or used for carrying out a military attack <vi>an <it>attack</it> helicopter</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="attack dog"><ew>attack dog</ew><hw>attack dog</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1970</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a dog trained to attack on command or on sight</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a person noted for harsh, personal, and usually public verbal attacks against others <vi>a political <it>attack dog</it></vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="angle of attack"><ew>angle of attack</ew><grp>angle of</grp><grp>angle attack</grp><grp>of attack</grp><subj>AE</subj><hw>angle of attack</hw><def><date>1908</date><dt>:the acute angle between the direction of the relative wind and the chord of an airfoil</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="banzai attack"><ew>banzai attack</ew><subj>ML#HI</subj><hw>banzai attack</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1944</date><dt>:a mass attack by Japanese soldiers in World War II</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:an all-out usually desperate attack</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="brain attack"><ew>brain attack</ew><subj>MD</subj><hw>brain attack</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1990</date><dt>:<sx>stroke<sxn>5</sxn></sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="heart attack"><ew>heart attack</ew><subj>MD</subj><hw>heart attack</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1928</date><dt>:an acute episode of heart disease marked by the death or damage of heart muscle due to insufficient blood supply to the heart usually as a result of a coronary thrombosis or a coronary occlusion and that is characterized especially by chest pain <ca>called also <cat>myocardial infarction</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="panic attack"><ew>panic attack</ew><subj>PS</subj><hw>panic attack</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1966</date><dt>:an episode of intense fear or apprehension that is of sudden onset</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="transient ischemic attack"><ew>transient ischemic attack</ew><grp>transient ischemic</grp><grp>transient attack</grp><grp>ischemic attack</grp><subj>MD</subj><hw>transient ischemic attack</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1966</date><dt>:a brief episode of cerebral ischemia that is usually characterized by temporary blurring of vision, slurring of speech, numbness, paralysis, or syncope and is often predictive of a serious stroke <un>abbreviation <it>TIA</it></un> <ca>called also <cat>ministroke</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>