<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="effect[1]"><ew>effect</ew><subj>ET-7c(2)</subj><hw hindex="1">ef*fect</hw><sound><wav>effect01.wav</wav></sound><pr>i-ˈfekt, e-, ē-, ə-</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French &amp; Latin; Anglo-French, from Latin <it>effectus,</it> from <it>efficere</it> to bring about, from <it>ex-</it> + <it>facere</it> to make, do <ma>do</ma></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:<sx>purport</sx> <sx>intent</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:basic meaning :<sx>essence</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something that inevitably follows an <d_link>antecedent</d_link> (as a cause or agent)</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:an outward sign :<sx>appearance</sx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:<sx>accomplishment</sx> <sx>fulfillment</sx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:power to bring about a result :<sx>influence</sx> <vi>the content itself of television … is therefore less important than its <it>effect</it> <aq><it>Current Biography</it></aq></vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <sin><spl>plural</spl></sin> <dt>:movable property :<sx>goods</sx> <vi>personal <it>effect</it><it>s</it></vi></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt>:a distinctive impression <vi>the color gives the <it>effect</it> of being warm</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the creation of a desired impression <vi>her tears were purely for <it>effect</it></vi></dt>  <sn>c <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:something designed to produce a distinctive or desired impression <un>usually used in plural</un></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <sin><spl>plural</spl></sin> <dt>:<sx>special effects</sx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:the quality or state of being operative :<sx>operation</sx> <vi>the law goes into <it>effect</it> next week</vi></dt></def><dro><drp>in effect</drp> <def><dt>:in substance :<sx>virtually</sx> <vi>the … committee agreed to what was <it>in effect</it> a reduction in the hourly wage <aq><it>Current Biography</it></aq></vi></dt></def></dro><dro><drp>to the effect</drp> <def><dt>:with the meaning <vi>issued a statement <it>to the effect</it> that he would resign</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>
	<entry id="effect[2]"><ew>effect</ew><hw hindex="2">ef*fect</hw><sound><wav>effect01.wav</wav></sound><pr>i-ˈfekt, e-, ē-, ə-</pr><fl>verb</fl><et><dx_ety>(see <dxt>effect</dxt>)</dx_ety></et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>1533</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to cause to come into being</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to bring about often by <d_link>surmounting</d_link> obstacles :<sx>accomplish</sx> <vi><it>effect</it> a settlement of a dispute</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to put into operation <vi>the duty of the legislature to <it>effect</it> the will of the citizens</vi></dt><ss>perform</ss></def><pl>usage</pl><pt><it>Effect</it> and <it>affect</it> are often confused because of their similar spelling and pronunciation. The verb <it>affect</it> usually has to do with pretense <vi>she <it>affected</it> a cheery disposition despite feeling down</vi>. The more common <it>affect</it> denotes having an effect or influence <vi>the weather <it>affected</it> everyone's mood</vi>. The verb <it>effect</it> goes beyond mere influence; it refers to actual achievement of a final result <vi>the new administration hopes to <it>effect</it> a peace settlement</vi>. The uncommon noun <it>affect</it>, which has a meaning relating to psychology, is also sometimes mistakenly used for the very common <it>effect.</it> In ordinary use, the noun you will want is <it>effect</it> <vi>waiting for the new law to take <it>effect</it></vi> <vi>the weather had an <it>effect</it> on everyone's mood</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="Auger effect"><ew>Auger effect</ew><subj>PY</subj><hw>Au*ger effect</hw><sound><wav>auger_01.wav</wav><wpr>(+)O-!zhA-i-!fekt</wpr></sound><pr>(ˌ)ō-ˈzhā-</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Pierre V. <it>Auger</it> †1993 French physicist</et><def><date>1931</date><dt>:a process in which an atom that has been ionized through the emission of an electron with energy in the X-ray range undergoes a transition in which a second electron is emitted rather than an X-ray photon <ca>called also <cat>Auger process</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="Bohr effect"><ew>Bohr effect</ew><subj>PI#BC</subj><hw>Bohr effect</hw><sound><wav>bohre01w.wav</wav><wpr>!bOr-i-!fekt</wpr></sound><pr>ˈbȯr-</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Christian <it>Bohr</it> †1911 Danish physiologist</et><def><date>1939</date><dt>:the decrease in the oxygen affinity of a respiratory pigment (as hemoglobin) in response to decreased blood pH resulting from increased carbon dioxide concentration in the blood</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="butterfly effect"><ew>butterfly effect</ew><subj>PY#MA</subj><hw>butterfly effect</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1984</date><dt>:a property of chaotic systems (as the atmosphere) by which small changes in initial conditions can lead to large-scale and unpredictable variation in the future state of the system</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="Coriolis effect"><ew>Coriolis effect</ew><subj>AT#PY</subj><hw>Co*ri*o*lis effect</hw><sound><wav>coriol01.wav</wav><wpr>+kOr-E-!O-lus-i-!fekt</wpr></sound><pr>ˌkȯr-ē-ˈō-ləs-</pr><fl>noun</fl><def><date>circa 1946</date><dt>:the apparent deflection of a moving object that is the result of the Coriolis force</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="domino effect"><ew>domino effect</ew><hw>domino effect</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1966</date><dt>:a cumulative effect produced when one event initiates a succession of similar events <dx>compare <dxt>ripple effect</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="Doppler effect"><ew>Doppler effect</ew><subj>PY</subj><hw>Doppler effect</hw><fl>noun</fl><et>Christian J. <it>Doppler</it></et><def><date>1905</date><dt>:a change in the frequency with which waves (as of sound or light) from a given source reach an observer when the source and the observer are in motion with respect to each other so that the frequency increases or decreases according to the speed at which the distance is decreasing or increasing</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="edge effect"><ew>edge effect</ew><subj>EO</subj><hw>edge effect</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1933</date><dt>:the effect of an abrupt transition between two quite different adjoining ecological communities on the numbers and kinds of organisms in the marginal habitat</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="field-effect transistor"><ew>field-effect transistor</ew><subj>EE</subj><hw>field–ef*fect transistor</hw><sound><wav>field_01.wav</wav><wpr>!fEl-du-+fekt-tran-!zis-tur</wpr></sound><pr>ˈfēld-ə-ˌfekt-</pr><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1953</date><dt>:a transistor in which the output current is controlled by a variable electric field</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>