<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="guide[1]"><ew>guide</ew><subj>ML-3#HF-2b#ME-2a</subj><hw hindex="1">guide</hw><sound><wav>guide001.wav</wav><wpr>!gId</wpr></sound><pr>ˈgīd</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English <it>gide, guide,</it> from Anglo-French, from Old Occitan <it>guida,</it> of Germanic origin; akin to Old English <it>wītan</it> to look after, <it>witan</it> to know <ma>wit</ma></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:one that leads or directs another's way</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a person who exhibits and explains points of interest</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:something that provides a person with <fw>guiding</fw> information</dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:<sx>signpost <sxn>1</sxn></sx></dt>  <sn>e</sn> <dt>:a person who directs another's conduct or course of life</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a device for steadying or directing the motion of something</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a ring or loop for holding the line of a fishing rod in position</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a sheet or a card with projecting tab for labeling inserted in a card index to facilitate reference</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a member of a unit on whom the movements or alignments of a military command are regulated <un>used especially in commands <vi><it>guide</it> right</vi></un></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="guide[2]"><ew>guide</ew><hw hindex="2">guide</hw><fl>verb</fl><in><if>guid*ed</if></in><in><if>guid*ing</if></in><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to act as a guide to :direct in a way or course</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to direct, supervise, or influence usually to a particular end</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to superintend the training or instruction of</dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <dt>:to act or work as a guide</dt></def><uro><ure>guid*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>guide</sc> <sc>lead</sc> <sc>steer</sc> <sc>pilot</sc> <sc>engineer</sc> mean to direct in a course or show the way to be followed. <sc>guide</sc> implies intimate knowledge of the way and of all its difficulties and dangers <vi><it>guided</it> the scouts through the cave</vi>. <sc>lead</sc> implies showing the way and often keeping those that follow under control and in order <vi><it>led</it> his team to victory</vi>. <sc>steer</sc> implies an ability to keep to a course and stresses the capacity of maneuvering correctly <vi><it>steered</it> the ship through a narrow channel</vi>. <sc>pilot</sc> suggests guidance over a dangerous or complicated course <vi><it>piloted</it> the bill through the Senate</vi>. <sc>engineer</sc> implies finding ways to avoid or overcome difficulties in achieving an end or carrying out a plan <vi><it>engineered</it> his son's election to the governorship</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="guide dog"><ew>guide dog</ew><subj>ZM#AH</subj><hw>guide dog</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1932</date><dt>:a dog trained to lead the blind</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="guide word"><ew>guide word</ew><subj>PU</subj><hw>guide word</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>circa 1928</date><dt>:either of the terms at the head of a page of an alphabetical reference work (as a dictionary) indicating the alphabetically first and last words on the page</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="field guide"><ew>field guide</ew><hw>field guide</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1934</date><dt>:an illustrated manual for identifying natural objects, flora, or fauna in nature</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="Girl Guide"><ew>Girl Guide</ew><subj>YA</subj><hw>Girl Guide</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1909</date><dt>:a member of a worldwide scouting movement for girls 7 to 18 years of age that is equivalent to the Girl Scouts in the United States</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="light guide"><ew>light guide</ew><subj>TL#PX</subj><hw>light guide</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1951</date><dt>:an optical fiber used especially for telecommunication</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>