<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="agree"><ew>agree</ew><subj>GR-vi5</subj><hw>agree</hw><sound><wav>agree001.wav</wav><wpr>u-!grE</wpr></sound><pr>ə-ˈgrē</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>agreed</if></in><in><if>agree*ing</if></in><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French <it>agreer,</it> from <it>a gre</it> at will, from <it>a</it> (from Latin <it>ad</it>) + <it>gre</it> will, pleasure, from Latin <it>gratum,</it> neuter of <it>gratus</it> pleasing, agreeable <ma>grace</ma></et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>15th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to concur in (as an opinion) :<sx>admit</sx> <sx>concede</sx> <vi><it>agree</it><it>s</it> that he is right</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to consent to as a course of action <vi><it>agreed</it> to sell him the house</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>chiefly British</ssl> <dt>:to settle on by common consent :<sx>arrange</sx> <vi>I <it>agreed</it> rental terms with him <aq>Eric Bennett</aq></vi></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to accept or concede something (as the views or wishes of another) <vi><it>agree</it> to a plan</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to achieve or be in harmony (as of opinion, feeling, or purpose) <vi>we <it>agree</it> in our taste in music</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to get along together</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to come to terms <vi><it>agree</it> on a fair division of profits</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to be similar :<sx>correspond</sx> <vi>both copies <it>agree</it></vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be consistent <vi>the story <it>agree</it><it>s</it> with the facts</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to be fitting, pleasing, or healthful :<sx>suit</sx> <vi>this climate <it>agree</it><it>s</it> with him</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to have an inflectional form denoting identity or other regular correspondence in a grammatical category (as gender, number, case, or person)</dt></def><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>agree</sc> <sc>concur</sc> <sc>coincide</sc> mean to come into or be in harmony regarding a matter of opinion. <sc>agree</sc> implies complete accord usually attained by discussion and adjustment of differences <vi>on some points we all can <it>agree</it></vi>. <sc>concur</sc> tends to suggest cooperative thinking or acting toward an end but sometimes implies no more than approval (as of a decision reached by others) <vi>if my wife <it>concurs,</it> it's a deal</vi>. <sc>coincide,</sc> used more often of opinions, judgments, wishes, or interests than of people, implies an agreement amounting to identity <vi>their wishes <it>coincide</it> exactly with my desire</vi>.</pt><sa>assent</sa></entry>
</entry_list>