<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="anger[1]"><ew>anger</ew><hw hindex="1">an*ger</hw><sound><wav>anger02w.wav</wav><wpr>!aN-gur</wpr></sound><pr>ˈaŋ-gər</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>an*gered</if></in><in><if>an*ger*ing</if><sound><wav>anger01w.wav</wav><wpr>!aN-g(u-)riN</wpr></sound> <pr>-g(ə-)riŋ</pr></in><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>13th century</date> <dt>:to make angry <vi>he was <it>anger</it><it>ed</it> by the decision</vi></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <dt>:to become angry</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="anger[2]"><ew>anger</ew><hw hindex="2">anger</hw><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English, affliction, anger, from Old Norse <it>angr</it> grief; akin to Old English <it>enge</it> narrow, Latin <it>angere</it> to strangle, Greek <it>anchein</it></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a strong feeling of displeasure and usually of antagonism</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>rage <sxn>2</sxn></sx></dt></def><uro><ure>an*ger*less</ure><sound><wav>anger03w.wav</wav><wpr>!aN-gur-lus</wpr></sound> <pr>-ləs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>anger</sc> <sc>ire</sc> <sc>rage</sc> <sc>fury</sc> <sc>indignation</sc> <sc>wrath</sc> mean an intense emotional state induced by displeasure. <sc>anger,</sc> the most general term, names the reaction but in itself conveys nothing about intensity or justification or manifestation of the emotional state <vi>tried to hide his <it>anger</it></vi>. <sc>ire,</sc> more frequent in literary contexts, may suggest greater intensity than <it>anger,</it> often with an evident display of feeling <vi>cheeks flushed dark with <it>ire</it></vi>. <sc>rage</sc> suggests loss of self-control from violence of emotion <vi>screaming with <it>rage</it></vi>. <sc>fury</sc> is overmastering destructive rage that can verge on madness <vi>in her <it>fury</it> she accused us all of betrayal</vi>. <sc>indignation</sc> stresses righteous anger at what one considers unfair, mean, or shameful <vi>a comment that caused general <it>indignation</it></vi>. <sc>wrath</sc> is likely to suggest a desire or intent to revenge or punish <vi>rose in his <it>wrath</it> and struck his tormentor</vi>.</pt></entry>
</entry_list>