<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="apology"><ew>apology</ew><hw>apol*o*gy</hw><sound><wav>apolog08.wav</wav><wpr>u-!p@-lu-jE</wpr></sound><pr>ə-ˈpä-lə-jē</pr><fl>noun</fl><in><il>plural</il> <if>apol*o*gies</if></in><et>Middle French or Late Latin; Middle French <it>apologie,</it> from Late Latin <it>apologia,</it> from Greek, from <it>apo-</it> + <it>logos</it> speech <ma>legend</ma></et><def><date>1533</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a formal justification :<sx>defense</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>excuse <sxn>2a</sxn></sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an admission of error or discourtesy accompanied by an expression of regret <vi>a public <it>apology</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a poor substitute :<sx>makeshift</sx></dt></def><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>apology</sc> <sc>apologia</sc> <sc>excuse</sc> <sc>plea</sc> <sc>pretext</sc> <sc>alibi</sc> mean matter offered in explanation or defense. <sc>apology</sc> usually applies to an expression of regret for a mistake or wrong with implied admission of guilt or fault and with or without reference to mitigating or extenuating circumstances <vi>said by way of <it>apology</it> that he would have met them if he could</vi>. <sc>apologia</sc> implies not admission of guilt or regret but a desire to make clear the grounds for some course, belief, or position <vi>his speech was an <it>apologia</it> for his foreign policy</vi>. <sc>excuse</sc> implies an intent to avoid or remove blame or censure <vi>used illness as an <it>excuse</it> for missing the meeting</vi>. <sc>plea</sc> stresses argument or appeal for understanding or sympathy or mercy <vi>her usual <it>plea</it> that she was nearsighted</vi>. <sc>pretext</sc> suggests subterfuge and the offering of false reasons or motives in excuse or explanation <vi>used any <it>pretext</it> to get out of work</vi>. <sc>alibi</sc> implies a desire to shift blame or evade punishment and imputes mere plausibility to the explanation <vi>his <it>alibi</it> failed to stand scrutiny</vi>.</pt></entry>
</entry_list>