<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="ask"><ew>ask</ew><hw>ask</hw><sound><wav>ask00002.wav</wav><wpr>!ask</wpr><wav>ask00001.wav</wav><wpr>!1sk</wpr></sound><pr>ˈask, ˈäsk; <it>dialect</it> ˈaks</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>asked</if><sound><wav>ask00003.wav</wav><wpr>!as(k)t</wpr></sound> <pr>ˈas(k)t, ˈäs(k)t, ˈask; <it>dialect</it> ˈakst</pr></in><in><if>ask*ing</if></in><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>āscian;</it> akin to Old High German <it>eiscōn</it> to ask, Lithuanian <it>ieškoti</it> to seek, Sanskrit <it>icchati</it> he seeks</et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to call on for an answer <vi>she <it>ask</it><it>ed</it> him about his trip</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to put a question about <vi><it>ask</it><it>ing</it> her whereabouts</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:<sx>speak</sx> <sx>utter</sx> <vi><it>ask</it> a question</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to make a request of <vi>she <it>ask</it><it>ed</it> her teacher for help</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to make a request for <vi>she <it>ask</it><it>ed</it> help from her teacher</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to call for :<sx>require</sx> <vi>a challenge that will <it>ask</it> much of us</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to set as a price <vi><it>ask</it><it>ed</it> $3000 for the car</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:<sx>invite</sx></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to seek information</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to make a request <vi><it>ask</it><it>ed</it> for food</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:<sx>look</sx> <un>often used in the phrase <it>ask for trouble</it></un></dt></def><uro><ure>ask*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>ask</sc> <sc>question</sc> <sc>interrogate</sc> <sc>query</sc> <sc>inquire</sc> mean to address a person in order to gain information. <sc>ask</sc> implies no more than the putting of a question <vi><it>ask</it> for directions</vi>. <sc>question</sc> usually suggests the asking of series of questions <vi><it>questioned</it> them about every detail of the trip</vi>. <sc>interrogate</sc> suggests formal or official systematic questioning <vi>the prosecutor <it>interrogated</it> the witness all day</vi>. <sc>query</sc> implies a desire for authoritative information or confirmation <vi><it>queried</it> a librarian about the book</vi>. <sc>inquire</sc> implies a searching for facts or for truth often specifically by asking questions <vi>began to <it>inquire</it> of friends and teachers what career she should pursue</vi>.</pt><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>ask</sc> <sc>request</sc> <sc>solicit</sc> mean to seek to obtain by making one's wants known. <sc>ask</sc> implies no more than the statement of the desire <vi><it>ask</it> a favor of a friend</vi>. <sc>request</sc> implies greater formality and courtesy <vi><it>requests</it> the pleasure of your company</vi>. <sc>solicit</sc> suggests a calling attention to one's wants or desires by public announcement or advertisement <vi>a letter <it>soliciting</it> information</vi>.</pt></entry>
</entry_list>