<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="awkward"><ew>awkward</ew><hw>awk*ward</hw><sound><wav>awkwar01.wav</wav></sound><pr>ˈȯ-kwərd</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English <it>awkeward</it> in the wrong direction, from <it>awke</it> turned the wrong way, from Old Norse <it>ǫfugr;</it> akin to Old High German <it>abuh</it> turned the wrong way</et><def><date>1530</date> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>obsolete</ssl> <dt>:<sx>perverse</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:<sx>unfavorable</sx> <sx>adverse</sx></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:lacking <d_link>dexterity</d_link> or skill (as in the use of hands) <vi><it>awkward</it> with a needle and thread</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:showing the result of a lack of expertness <vi><it>awkward</it> pictures</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:lacking ease or grace (as of movement or expression) <vi><it>awkward</it> writing</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:lacking the right proportions, size, or <d_link>harmony</d_link> of parts :<sx>ungainly</sx> <vi>an <it>awkward</it> design</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:lacking social grace and assurance <vi>an <it>awkward</it> newcomer</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:causing embarrassment <vi>an <it>awkward</it> moment</vi></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:not easy to handle or deal with :requiring great skill, <d_link>ingenuity</d_link>, or care <vi>an <it>awkward</it> load</vi> <vi>an <it>awkward</it> diplomatic situation</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>awk*ward*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><uro><ure>awk*ward*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>awkward</sc> <sc>clumsy</sc> <sc>maladroit</sc> <sc>inept</sc> <sc>gauche</sc> mean not marked by ease (as of performance, movement, or social conduct). <sc>awkward</sc> is widely applicable and may suggest unhandiness, inconvenience, lack of muscular control, embarrassment, or lack of tact <vi>periods of <it>awkward</it> silence</vi>. <sc>clumsy</sc> implies stiffness and heaviness and so may connote inflexibility, unwieldiness, or lack of ordinary skill <vi>a <it>clumsy</it> mechanic</vi>. <sc>maladroit</sc> suggests a tendency to create awkward situations <vi>a <it>maladroit</it> politician</vi>. <sc>inept</sc> often implies complete failure or inadequacy <vi>a hopelessly <it>inept</it> defense attorney</vi>. <sc>gauche</sc> implies the effects of shyness, inexperience, or ill breeding <vi>felt <it>gauche</it> and unsophisticated at formal parties</vi>.</pt></entry>
</entry_list>