<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="calm[1]"><ew>calm</ew><subj>AT-1</subj><hw hindex="1">calm</hw><sound><wav>calm0001.wav</wav><wpr>!k@m</wpr><wav>calm0002.wav</wav><wpr>!kolm</wpr></sound><pr>ˈkäm, ˈkälm, ˈkam, ˈkȯ(l)m</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English <it>calme,</it> probably ultimately from Old Spanish <it>calma,</it> from Late Latin <it>cauma</it> heat, from Greek <it>kauma,</it> from <it>kaiein</it> to burn</et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a period or condition of freedom from storms, high winds, or rough activity of water</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:complete absence of wind or presence of wind having a speed no greater than one mile (1.6 kilometers) per hour <dx>see <dxt>beaufort scale <dxn>table</dxn></dxt></dx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a state of tranquillity</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="calm[2]"><ew>calm</ew><hw hindex="2">calm</hw><fl>verb</fl><def><vt>intransitive verb</vt><date>14th century</date><dt>:to become calm <un>usually used with <it>down</it></un></dt><vt>transitive verb</vt> <dt>:to make calm <un>often used with <it>down</it></un></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="calm[3]"><ew>calm</ew><hw hindex="3">calm</hw><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:marked by calm :<sx>still</sx> <vi>a <it>calm</it> sea</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:free from agitation, excitement, or disturbance</dt></def><uro><ure>calm*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><uro><ure>calm*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>calm</sc> <sc>tranquil</sc> <sc>serene</sc> <sc>placid</sc> <sc>peaceful</sc> mean quiet and free from disturbance. <sc>calm</sc> often implies a contrast with a foregoing or nearby state of agitation or violence <vi>the protests ended, and the streets were <it>calm</it> again</vi>. <sc>tranquil</sc> suggests a very deep quietude or composure <vi>the <it>tranquil</it> beauty of a formal garden</vi>. <sc>serene</sc> stresses an unclouded and lofty tranquillity <vi>watched the sunset of a <it>serene</it> summer's evening</vi>. <sc>placid</sc> suggests an undisturbed appearance and often implies a degree of complacency <vi>remained <it>placid</it> despite the criticism</vi>. <sc>peaceful</sc> implies a state of repose in contrast with or following strife or turmoil <vi>grown <it>peaceful</it> in old age</vi>.</pt></entry>
</entry_list>