<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="citizen"><ew>citizen</ew><subj>GV#LW</subj><hw>cit*i*zen</hw><sound><wav>citize01.wav</wav><wpr>!si-tu-zun</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsi-tə-zən <it>also</it> -sən</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English <it>citizein,</it> from Anglo-French <it>citezein,</it> alteration of <it>citeien,</it> from <it>cité</it> city</et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an inhabitant of a city or town</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:one entitled to the rights and privileges of a freeman</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a member of a state</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a native or naturalized person who owes allegiance to a government and is entitled to protection from it</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a civilian as distinguished from a specialized servant of the state</dt></def><uro><ure>cit*i*zen*ly</ure><sound><wav>citize02.wav</wav><wpr>!si-tu-zun-lE</wpr></sound> <pr>-zən-lē <it>also</it> -sən-</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>citizen</sc> <sc>subject</sc> <sc>national</sc> mean a person owing allegiance to and entitled to the protection of a sovereign state. <sc>citizen</sc> is preferred for one owing allegiance to a state in which sovereign power is retained by the people and sharing in the political rights of those people <vi>the rights of a free <it>citizen</it></vi>. <sc>subject</sc> implies allegiance to a personal sovereign such as a monarch <vi>the king's <it>subjects</it></vi>. <sc>national</sc> designates one who may claim the protection of a state and applies especially to one living or traveling outside that state <vi>American <it>nationals</it> working in the Middle East</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="citizen's arrest"><ew>citizen's arrest</ew><subj>LW</subj><hw>citizen's arrest</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1941</date><dt>:an arrest made not by a law officer but by a citizen who derives authority from the fact of being a citizen</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="senior citizen"><ew>senior citizen</ew><hw>senior citizen</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1938</date><dt>:an elderly person</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:one who has retired</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>