<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="conquer"><ew>conquer</ew><hw>con*quer</hw><sound><wav>conque01.wav</wav></sound><pr>ˈkäŋ-kər</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>con*quered</if></in><in><if>con*quer*ing</if> <sound><wav>conque02.wav</wav></sound><pr>-k(ə-)riŋ</pr> </in><et>Middle English, to acquire, conquer, from Anglo-French <it>conquerre,</it> from Vulgar Latin <it>*conquaerere,</it> alteration of Latin <it>conquirere</it> to search for, collect, from <it>com-</it> + <it>quaerere</it> to ask, search</et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to gain or acquire by force of arms :<sx>subjugate</sx> <vi><it>conquer</it> territory</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to overcome by force of arms :<sx>vanquish</sx> <vi><it>conquer</it><it>ed</it> the enemy</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to gain <d_link>mastery</d_link> over or win by overcoming obstacles or opposition <vi><it>conquer</it><it>ed</it> the mountain</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to overcome by mental or moral power :<sx>surmount</sx> <vi><it>conquer</it><it>ed</it> her fear</vi></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <dt>:to be victorious</dt></def><uro><ure>con*quer*or</ure> <sound><wav>conque03.wav</wav></sound><pr>-kər-ər</pr>  <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>conquer</sc> <sc>vanquish</sc> <sc>defeat</sc> <sc>subdue</sc> <sc>reduce</sc> <sc>overcome</sc> <sc>overthrow</sc> mean to get the better of by force or strategy. <sc>conquer</sc> implies gaining mastery of <vi>Caesar <it>conquered</it> Gaul</vi>. <sc>vanquish</sc> implies a complete overpowering <vi><it>vanquished</it> the enemy and ended the war</vi>. <sc>defeat</sc> does not imply the finality or completeness of <sc>vanquish</sc> which it otherwise equals <vi>the Confederates <it>defeated</it> the Union forces at Manassas</vi>. <sc>subdue</sc> implies a defeating and suppression <vi><it>subdued</it> the native tribes after years of fighting</vi>. <sc>reduce</sc> implies a forcing to capitulate or surrender <vi>the city was <it>reduced</it> after a month-long siege</vi>. <sc>overcome</sc> suggests getting the better of with difficulty or after hard struggle <vi><it>overcame</it> a host of bureaucratic roadblocks</vi>. <sc>overthrow</sc> stresses the bringing down or destruction of existing power <vi>violently <it>overthrew</it> the old regime</vi>.</pt></entry>
</entry_list>