<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="continue"><ew>continue</ew><subj>LW-vt4</subj><hw>con*tin*ue</hw><sound><wav>contin15.wav</wav><wpr>kun-!tin-(+)yU</wpr></sound><pr>kən-ˈtin-(ˌ)yü</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>con*tin*ued</if></in><in><if>con*tinu*ing</if></in><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French <it>continuer,</it> from Latin <it>continuare,</it> from <it>continuus</it></et><def><vt>intransitive verb</vt><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to maintain without interruption a condition, course, or action <vi>the boat <it>continued</it> downstream</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to remain in existence :<sx>endure</sx> <vi>the tradition <it>continue</it><it>s</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to remain in a place or condition :<sx>stay</sx> <vi>cannot <it>continue</it> here much longer</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to resume an activity after interruption <vi>we'll <it>continue</it> after lunch</vi></dt><vt>transitive verb</vt> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:<sx>keep up</sx> <sx>maintain</sx> <vi><it>continue</it><it>s</it> walking</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to keep going or add to :<sx>prolong</sx> <vi><it>continue</it> the battle</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:to resume after intermission</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to cause to continue <vi>chose not to <it>continue</it> her subscription</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to allow to remain in a place or condition :<sx>retain</sx> <vi>the trustees were <it>continued</it></vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to postpone (a legal proceeding) by a <fw>continuance</fw></dt></def><uro><ure>con*tinu*er</ure><sound><wav>contin16.wav</wav><wpr>kun-!tin-yU-ur</wpr></sound> <pr>-yü-ər</pr> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>continue</sc> <sc>last</sc> <sc>endure</sc> <sc>abide</sc> <sc>persist</sc> mean to exist over a period of time or indefinitely. <sc>continue</sc> applies to a process going on without ending <vi>the search for peace will <it>continue</it></vi>. <sc>last,</sc> especially when unqualified, may stress existing beyond what is normal or expected <vi>buy shoes that will <it>last</it></vi>. <sc>endure</sc> adds an implication of resisting destructive forces or agencies <vi>in spite of everything, her faith <it>endured</it></vi>. <sc>abide</sc> implies stable and constant existing especially as opposed to mutability <vi>a love that <it>abides</it> through 40 years of marriage</vi>. <sc>persist</sc> suggests outlasting the normal or appointed time and often connotes obstinacy or doggedness <vi>the sense of guilt <it>persisted</it></vi>.</pt></entry>
</entry_list>