<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="decay[1]"><ew>decay</ew><subj>CH-vt2#PY-vi2#MB-vi5#MB-vt2#BC-vi5#BC-vt2#EO-vi5</subj><hw hindex="1">de*cay</hw><sound><wav>decay001.wav</wav><wpr>di-!kA</wpr></sound><pr>di-ˈkā</pr><fl>verb</fl><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French <it>decaïr,</it> from Late Latin <it>decadere</it> to fall, sink, from Latin <it>de-</it> + <it>cadere</it> to fall <ma>chance</ma></et><def><vt>intransitive verb</vt><date>15th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to decline from a sound or prosperous condition</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to decrease usually gradually in size, quantity, activity, or force</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to fall into ruin</dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to decline in health, strength, or vigor</dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to undergo decomposition <vi><it>decay</it><it>ing</it> fruit</vi></dt><vt>transitive verb</vt> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>obsolete</ssl> <dt>:to cause to decay :<sx>impair</sx> <vi>infirmity that <it>decay</it><it>s</it> the wise <aq>Shakespeare</aq></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to destroy by decomposition</dt></def><uro><ure>de*cay*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>decay</sc> <sc>decompose</sc> <sc>rot</sc> <sc>putrefy</sc> <sc>spoil</sc> mean to undergo destructive dissolution. <sc>decay</sc> implies a slow change from a state of soundness or perfection <vi>a <it>decaying</it> mansion</vi>. <sc>decompose</sc> stresses a breaking down by chemical change and when applied to organic matter a corruption <vi>the strong odor of <it>decomposing</it> vegetation</vi>. <sc>rot</sc> is a close synonym of <sc>decompose</sc> and often connotes foulness <vi>fruit was left to <it>rot</it> in warehouses</vi>. <sc>putrefy</sc> implies the rotting of animal matter and offensiveness to sight and smell <vi>corpses <it>putrefying</it> on the battlefield</vi>. <sc>spoil</sc> applies chiefly to the decomposition of foods <vi>keep the ham from <it>spoiling</it></vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="decay[2]"><ew>decay</ew><subj>EO-4#BI-4#MB-4#BC-4#MD-5#PY-6#CH-6a</subj><hw hindex="2">decay</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>15th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:gradual decline in strength, soundness, or prosperity or in degree of excellence or perfection</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a wasting or wearing away :<sx>ruin</sx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>obsolete</ssl> <dt>:<sx>destruction</sx> <sx>death</sx></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:<sx>rot</sx></dt> <sd>specifically</sd> <dt>:aerobic decomposition of proteins chiefly by bacteria</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the product of decay</dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:a decline in health or vigor</dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt> :decrease in quantity, activity, or force: as</dt>  <sn>a</sn> <dt>:spontaneous decrease in the number of radioactive atoms in radioactive material</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:spontaneous disintegration (as of an atom or a particle) </dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="beta decay"><ew>beta decay</ew><subj>PY</subj><hw>beta decay</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1931</date><dt>:a radioactive nuclear transformation governed by the weak force in which a nucleon (as a neutron) changes into a nucleon (as a proton) of the other type with the emission of either an electron and an antineutrino or a positron and a neutrino</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>