<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="defend"><ew>defend</ew><subj>LW-vt3#LW-vt4#SP-vt1c#SP-vi2#GA-vi3</subj><hw>de*fend</hw><sound><wav>defend01.wav</wav><wpr>di-!fend</wpr></sound><pr>di-ˈfend</pr><fl>verb</fl><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French <it>defendre,</it> from Latin <it>defendere,</it> from <it>de-</it> + <it>-fendere</it> to strike; akin to Old English <it>gūth</it> battle, war, Greek <it>theinein</it> to strike</et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to drive danger or attack away from <vi><it>defend</it> our shores</vi></dt>  <sn>b <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:to maintain or support in the face of argument or hostile criticism <vi><it>defend</it> a theory</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:to prove (as a doctoral thesis) valid by answering questions in an oral exam</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to attempt to prevent an opponent from scoring at <vi>elects to <it>defend</it> the south goal</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:<sx>prevent</sx> <sx>forbid</sx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to act as attorney for</dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to deny or oppose the right of a plaintiff in regard to (a suit or a wrong charged) :<sx>contest</sx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to retain or seek to retain (as a title or position) against a challenge in a contest <vi>they successfully <it>defend</it><it>ed</it> their championship</vi></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to take action against attack or challenge</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to play or be on <fw>defense</fw> <vi>playing deep to <it>defend</it> against a pass</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to play against the high bidder in a card game</dt></def><uro><ure>de*fend*able</ure><sound><wav>defend02.wav</wav><wpr>!di-fen-du-bul</wpr></sound> <pr>ˈfen-də-bəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>defend</sc> <sc>protect</sc> <sc>shield</sc> <sc>guard</sc> <sc>safeguard</sc> mean to keep secure from danger or against attack. <sc>defend</sc> denotes warding off actual or threatened attack <vi><it>defend</it> the country</vi>. <sc>protect</sc> implies the use of something (as a covering) as a bar to the admission or impact of what may attack or injure <vi>a hard hat to <it>protect</it> your head</vi>. <sc>shield</sc> suggests protective intervention in imminent danger or actual attack <vi><it>shielded</it> her eyes from the sun with her hand</vi>. <sc>guard</sc> implies protecting with vigilance and force against expected danger <vi>White House entrances are well <it>guarded</it></vi>. <sc>safeguard</sc> implies taking precautionary protective measures against merely possible danger <vi>our civil liberties must be <it>safeguarded</it></vi>.</pt><sa>maintain</sa></entry>
</entry_list>