<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="each[1]"><ew>each</ew><hw hindex="1">each</hw><sound><wav>each0001.wav</wav><wpr>!Ech</wpr></sound><pr>ˈēch</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English <it>ech,</it> from Old English <it>ǣlc;</it> akin to Old High German <it>iogilīh</it> each; both from West Germanic <it>*aiw-</it> ever, always (whence Old English <it>ā</it> always) + <it>*galīkaz</it> having the same form, like (whence Old English <it>gelīc</it> like) <ma>aye, like</ma></et><def><date>before 12th century</date><dt>:being one of two or more distinct individuals having a similar relation and often constituting an aggregate</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="each[2]"><ew>each</ew><hw hindex="2">each</hw><fl>pronoun</fl><def><date>before 12th century</date><dt>:each one <vi>to <it>each</it> his own</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="each[3]"><ew>each</ew><hw hindex="3">each</hw><fl>adverb</fl><def><date>before 12th century</date><dt>:to or for each :<sx>apiece</sx> <vi>cost a dollar <it>each</it></vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="each other"><ew>each other</ew><hw>each other</hw><fl>pronoun</fl><def><date>before 12th century</date><dt>:each of two or more in reciprocal action or relation <vi>looked at <it>each other</it> in surprise</vi></dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt>Some handbooks and textbooks recommend that <it>each other</it> be restricted to reference to two and <it>one another</it> to reference to three or more. The distinction, while neat, is not observed in actual usage. <it>Each other</it> and <it>one another</it> are used interchangeably by good writers and have been since at least the 16th century.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="throat[1]"><ew>throat</ew><subj>CL-2b#SC-2c#BI-2a#BT-2a#AN-1#NA-3</subj><hw hindex="1">throat</hw><sound><wav>throat01.wav</wav><wpr>!thrOt</wpr></sound><pr>ˈthrōt</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English <it>throte,</it> from Old English; akin to Old High German <it>drozza</it> throat</et><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1 a <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:the part of the neck in front of the spinal column</dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:the passage <fw>through</fw> the neck to the stomach and lungs</dt>  <sn>b <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:<sx>voice</sx></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:the seat of the voice</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt> :something resembling the throat especially in being an entrance, a passageway, a constriction, or a narrowed part: as</dt>  <sn>a</sn> <dt>:the orifice of a tubular organ especially of a plant</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the opening in the vamp of a shoe at the instep</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the part of a tennis racket that connects the head with the shaft </dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the curved part of an anchor's arm where it joins the shank <dx>see <dxt>anchor <dxn>illustration</dxn></dxt></dx></dt></def><dro><drp>at each other's throats</drp> <def><dt>:in open and aggressive conflict</dt></def></dro></entry>
</entry_list>