<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="elastic[1]"><ew>elastic</ew><subj>PY-1</subj><hw hindex="1">elas*tic</hw><sound><wav>elasti01.wav</wav><wpr>i-!las-tik</wpr></sound><pr>i-ˈlas-tik</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>New Latin <it>elasticus,</it> from Late Greek <it>elastos</it> ductile, beaten, from Greek <it>elaunein</it> to drive, beat out; probably akin to Greek <it>ēlythe</it> he went, Old Irish <it>luid</it></et><def><date>1674</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>of a solid</ssl> <dt>:capable of recovering size and shape after deformation</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:relating to or being a collision between particles in which the total kinetic energy of the particles remains unchanged</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:capable of recovering quickly especially from depression or disappointment <vi>my <it>elastic</it> spirits revived <aq>Wilkie Collins</aq></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:capable of being easily stretched or expanded and resuming former shape :<sx>flexible</sx> <vi>an <it>elastic</it> bandage</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:capable of ready change or easy expansion or contraction :not rigid or constricted <vi>an <it>elastic</it> concept</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:receptive to new ideas :<sx>adaptable</sx> <vi>an <it>elastic</it> mind</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>elas*ti*cal*ly</ure><sound><wav>elasti02.wav</wav><wpr>i-!las-ti-k(u-)lE</wpr></sound> <pr>-ti-k(ə-)lē</pr> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>elastic</sc> <sc>resilient</sc> <sc>springy</sc> <sc>flexible</sc> <sc>supple</sc> mean able to endure strain without being permanently injured. <sc>elastic</sc> implies the property of resisting deformation by stretching <vi>an <it>elastic</it> waistband</vi>. <sc>resilient</sc> implies the ability to recover shape quickly when the deforming force or pressure is removed <vi>a <it>resilient</it> innersole</vi>. <sc>springy</sc> stresses both the ease with which something yields to pressure and the quickness of its return to original shape <vi>the cake is done when the top is <it>springy</it></vi>. <sc>flexible</sc> applies to something which may or may not be resilient or elastic but which can be bent or folded without breaking <vi><it>flexible</it> plastic tubing</vi>. <sc>supple</sc> applies to something that can be readily bent, twisted, or folded without any sign of injury <vi><it>supple</it> leather</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="elastic[2]"><ew>elastic</ew><subj>TX-2</subj><hw hindex="2">elastic</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1847</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:easily stretched rubber usually prepared in cords, strings, or bands</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>rubber band</sx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:an elastic fabric usually made of yarns containing rubber</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:something made from this fabric</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="elastic fiber"><ew>elastic fiber</ew><subj>AN</subj><hw>elastic fiber</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1849</date><dt>:a thick very elastic smooth yellowish anastomosing fiber of connective tissue that contains elastin</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="elastic limit"><ew>elastic limit</ew><subj>PY</subj><hw>elastic limit</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1898</date><dt>:the greatest stress that an elastic solid can sustain without undergoing permanent deformation</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="elastic modulus"><ew>elastic modulus</ew><subj>PY#ME</subj><hw>elastic modulus</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1904</date><dt>:the ratio of the stress in a body to the corresponding strain</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="elastic scattering"><ew>elastic scattering</ew><subj>PY</subj><hw>elastic scattering</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1933</date><dt>:a scattering of particles as the result of an elastic collision</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>