<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="envelope"><ew>envelope</ew><subj>BI-4#MA-5#AE-3#PP-1#AE-6</subj><hw>en*ve*lope</hw><sound><wav>envelo04.wav</wav><wpr>!en-vu-+lOp</wpr><wav>envelo03.wav</wav><wpr>!@n-vu-+lOp</wpr></sound><pr>ˈen-və-ˌlōp, ˈän-</pr><fl>noun</fl><def><date>circa 1714</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a flat usually paper container (as for a letter)</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something that <fw>envelops</fw> :<sx>wrapper</sx> <vi>the <it>envelope</it> of air around the earth</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:the outer covering of an aerostat</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the bag containing the gas in a balloon or airship</dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:a natural enclosing covering (as a membrane, shell, or integument)</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a lipoprotein unit membrane that forms the outer layer of some virions</dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:a curve tangent to each of a family of curves</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a surface tangent to each of a family of surfaces</dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:a set of performance limits (as of an aircraft) that may not be safely exceeded</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:the set of operating parameters that exists within these limits</dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:a conventionally accepted limit <vi>new computers that push the <it>envelope</it></vi></dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt>The \ˈen-\ and \ˈän-\ pronunciations are used with about equal frequency, and both are fully acceptable, though the \ˈän-\ version is sometimes decried as “pseudo-French.” Actually \ˈän-\ is exactly what one would expect to hear when a French word like <it>entrepreneur</it> is becoming anglicized. <it>Envelope,</it> however, has been in English for nearly 300 years, plenty of time for it to become completely anglicized and for both of its pronunciations to win respectability.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="floral envelope"><ew>floral envelope</ew><subj>BT#BS</subj><hw>floral envelope</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>circa 1829</date><dt>:<sx>perianth</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="pay envelope"><ew>pay envelope</ew><subj>BZ</subj><hw>pay envelope</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1901</date><dt>:an envelope containing one's wages</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:<sx>wages</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="window envelope"><ew>window envelope</ew><subj>PP</subj><hw>window envelope</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1914</date><dt>:an envelope having an opening through which the address on the enclosure is visible</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>