<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="fate[1]"><ew>fate</ew><subj>MY-4#EM-3b</subj><hw hindex="1">fate</hw><sound><wav>fate0001.wav</wav></sound><pr>ˈfāt</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English, from Middle French or Latin; Middle French, from Latin <it>fatum,</it> literally, what has been spoken, from neuter of <it>fatus,</it> past participle of <it>fari</it> to speak <ma>ban</ma></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the will or principle or determining cause by which things in general are believed to come to be as they are or events to happen as they do :<sx>destiny</sx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:an <d_link>inevitable</d_link> and often adverse outcome, condition, or end</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>disaster</sx></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:<sx>death</sx></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:final outcome</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the expected result of normal development <vi>prospective <it>fate</it> of embryonic cells</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the <d_link>circumstances</d_link> that befall someone or something <vi>did not know the <it>fate</it> of her former classmates</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <sin><spl>plural</spl></sin> <slb>capitalized</slb> <dt>:the three goddesses who determine the course of human life in classical mythology</dt></def><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>fate</sc> <sc>destiny</sc> <sc>lot</sc> <sc>portion</sc> <sc>doom</sc> mean a predetermined state or end. <sc>fate</sc> implies an inevitable and usually an adverse outcome <vi>the <it>fate</it> of the submarine is unknown</vi>. <sc>destiny</sc> implies something foreordained and often suggests a great or noble course or end <vi>the country's <it>destiny</it> to be a model of liberty to the world</vi>. <sc>lot</sc> and <sc>portion</sc> imply a distribution by fate or destiny, <sc>lot</sc> suggesting blind chance <vi>it was her <it>lot</it> to die childless</vi>, <sc>portion</sc> implying the apportioning of good and evil <vi>remorse was his daily <it>portion</it></vi>. <sc>doom</sc> distinctly implies a grim or calamitous fate <vi>if the rebellion fails, his <it>doom</it> is certain</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="fate[2]"><ew>fate</ew><hw hindex="2">fate</hw><sound><wav>fate0001.wav</wav></sound><pr>ˈfāt</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>fat*ed</if></in><in><if>fat*ing</if></in><et><dx_ety>(see <dxt>fate</dxt>)</dx_ety></et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>1601</date><dt>:<sx>destine</sx></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:<sx>doom</sx></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>