<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="gift[1]"><ew>gift</ew><hw hindex="1">gift</hw><sound><wav>gift0001.wav</wav><wpr>!gift</wpr></sound><pr>ˈgift</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English, from Old Norse, something given, talent; akin to Old English <it>giefan</it> to give</et><def><date>12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a notable capacity, talent, or endowment</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something voluntarily transferred by one person to another without compensation</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:the act, right, or power of giving</dt></def><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>gift</sc> <sc>faculty</sc> <sc>aptitude</sc> <sc>bent</sc> <sc>talent</sc> <sc>genius</sc> <sc>knack</sc> mean a special ability for doing something. <sc>gift</sc> often implies special favor by God or nature <vi>the <it>gift</it> of singing beautifully</vi>. <sc>faculty</sc> applies to an innate or less often acquired ability for a particular accomplishment or function <vi>a <it>faculty</it> for remembering names</vi>. <sc>aptitude</sc> implies a natural liking for some activity and the likelihood of success in it <vi>a mechanical <it>aptitude</it></vi>. <sc>bent</sc> is nearly equal to <sc>aptitude</sc> but it stresses inclination perhaps more than specific ability <vi>a family with an artistic <it>bent</it></vi>. <sc>talent</sc> suggests a marked natural ability that needs to be developed <vi>has enough <it>talent</it> to succeed</vi>. <sc>genius</sc> suggests impressive inborn creative ability <vi>has no great <it>genius</it> for poetry</vi>. <sc>knack</sc> implies a comparatively minor but special ability making for ease and dexterity in performance <vi>the <it>knack</it> of getting along</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="gift[2]"><ew>gift</ew><hw hindex="2">gift</hw><fl>verb</fl><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>circa 1550</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to endow with some power, quality, or attribute</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>present</sx> <vi><it>gift</it><it>ed</it> her with flowers</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>gift*ee</ure><sound><wav>gifte01v.wav</wav><wpr>+gif-!tE</wpr></sound> <pr>ˌgif-ˈtē</pr> <fl>noun</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="GIFT"><ew>GIFT</ew><subj>MD</subj><hw>GIFT</hw><fl>abbreviation</fl><def><dt>gamete intrafallopian transfer; gamete intrafallopian tube transfer</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="gift card"><ew>gift card</ew><subj>EC</subj><hw>gift card</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1991</date><dt>:a card entitling the recipient to receive goods or services of a specified value from the issuer</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="gift certificate"><ew>gift certificate</ew><subj>BZ</subj><hw>gift certificate</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1942</date><dt>:a certificate entitling the recipient to receive goods or services of a specified value from the issuer</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="gift of gab"><ew>gift of gab</ew><grp>gift of</grp><grp>gift gab</grp><grp>of gab</grp><hw>gift of gab</hw><def><date>1839</date><dt>:the ability to talk glibly and persuasively</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="gift of tongues"><ew>gift of tongues</ew><grp>gift of</grp><grp>gift tongues</grp><grp>of tongues</grp><subj>RC#BB</subj><hw>gift of tongues</hw><et>from the gifts of the Spirit in 1 Corinthians 12:1–13</et><def><date>1560</date><dt>:a charisma identified by ecstatic usually unintelligible speech</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="gift wrap"><ew>gift wrap</ew><hw>gift wrap</hw><fl>verb</fl><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>1936</date><dt>:to wrap (merchandise intended as a gift) decoratively</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>