<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="habit[1]"><ew>habit</ew><subj>PS-7#PI-7a#PI-7b#MD-7c#AN-4#DG-7c#BI-8#CL-1#CL-2#EQ-2b#CH-9#MI-9</subj><hw hindex="1">hab*it</hw><sound><wav>habit001.wav</wav><wpr>!ha-but</wpr></sound><pr>ˈha-bət</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French, from Latin <it>habitus</it> condition, character, from <it>habēre</it> to have, hold <ma>give</ma></et><def><date>13th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:<sx>clothing</sx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a costume characteristic of a calling, rank, or function <vi>a nun's <it>habit</it></vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a costume worn for horseback riding</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:manner of conducting oneself :<sx>bearing</sx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:bodily appearance or makeup <vi>a man of fleshy <it>habit</it></vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:the prevailing disposition or character of a person's thoughts and feelings :mental makeup</dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:a settled tendency or usual manner of behavior <vi>her <it>habit</it> of taking a morning walk</vi></dt> <sn>7 a</sn> <dt>:a behavior pattern acquired by frequent repetition or physiologic exposure that shows itself in regularity or increased facility of performance</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an acquired mode of behavior that has become nearly or completely involuntary <vi>got up early from force of <it>habit</it></vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:<sx>addiction</sx> <vi>a drug <it>habit</it></vi></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:characteristic mode of growth or occurrence <vi>a grass similar to Indian corn in <it>habit</it></vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <ssl>of a crystal</ssl> <dt>:characteristic assemblage of forms at crystallization leading to a usual appearance</dt> <dt>:<sx>shape</sx></dt></def><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>habit</sc> <sc>practice</sc> <sc>usage</sc> <sc>custom</sc> <sc>wont</sc> mean a way of acting fixed through repetition. <sc>habit</sc> implies a doing unconsciously and often compulsively <vi>had a <it>habit</it> of tapping his fingers</vi>. <sc>practice</sc> suggests an act or method followed with regularity and usually through choice <vi>our <it>practice</it> is to honor all major credit cards</vi>. <sc>usage</sc> suggests a customary action so generally followed that it has become a social norm <vi>western-style dress is now common <it>usage</it> in international business</vi>. <sc>custom</sc> applies to a practice or usage so steadily associated with an individual or group as to have almost the force of unwritten law <vi>the <it>custom</it> of wearing black at funerals</vi>. <sc>wont</sc> usually applies to an habitual manner, method, or practice of an individual or group <vi>as was her <it>wont,</it> she slept until noon</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="habit[2]"><ew>habit</ew><hw hindex="2">habit</hw><fl>verb</fl><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>1594</date><dt>:<sx>clothe</sx> <sx>dress</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="habit-forming"><ew>habit-forming</ew><subj>DG#MD#PS</subj><hw>hab*it–form*ing</hw><sound><wav>habitf01.wav</wav><wpr>!ha-but-+for-miN</wpr></sound><pr>ˈha-bət-ˌfȯr-miŋ</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1913</date><dt>:inducing the formation of an addiction <vi>a <it>habit–forming</it> drug</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="force of habit"><ew>force of habit</ew><grp>force of</grp><grp>force habit</grp><grp>of habit</grp><subj>PS</subj><hw>force of habit</hw><def><date>1796</date><dt>:behavior made involuntary or automatic by repeated practice</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>