<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="important"><ew>important</ew><hw>im*por*tant</hw><sound><wav>import06.wav</wav><wpr>im-!por-t/unt</wpr></sound><pr>im-ˈpȯr-tᵊnt, <it>especially Southern &amp; New England</it> -tənt, -dənt</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English <it>importante,</it> from Medieval Latin <it>important-, importans,</it> present participle of <it>importare</it> to signify <ma>import</ma></et><def><date>15th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:marked by or indicative of significant worth or consequence :valuable in content or relationship</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>obsolete</ssl> <dt>:<sx>importunate</sx> <sx>urgent</sx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:giving evidence of a feeling of self-importance</dt><us>importantly</us></def></entry>
	<entry id="importantly"><ew>importantly</ew><hw>im*por*tant*ly</hw><sound><wav>import07.wav</wav><wpr>im-!por-t/unt-lE</wpr></sound><pr>-lē</pr><fl>adverb</fl><def><date>1611</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:in an <fw>important</fw> way <vi>contributed <it>importantly</it> to the language of the field <aq>Ernst Mayr</aq></vi> <vi>cleared his throat <it>importantly</it> and waited <aq>E. K. Gann</aq></vi> <vi>the real story is <it>importantly</it> different <aq>Alexander Woollcott</aq></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:it is important that <vi>more <it>importantly</it> he stands a chance of having his publication barred <aq>H. L. Mencken</aq></vi></dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt>A number of commentators have objected to <it>importantly</it> as a sentence modifier (sense 2) and have recommended <it>important</it> instead. Actually both the adverb and the adjective are in reputable standard use in this function. <it>Important</it> is always used with <it>more</it> or <it>most</it> <vi>had bronze weapons and composite bows; more <it>important,</it> they utilized the horse and war chariot <aq>Harry A. Gailey, Jr.</aq></vi> <vi>second and most <it>important,</it> the book contains no important woman character <aq>F. Scott Fitzgerald</aq></vi>. <it>Importantly</it> is somewhat more flexible in not requiring <it>more</it> or <it>most</it> <vi>sticks and, just as <it>importantly,</it> unsticks easily <aq>Phoebe Hawkins</aq></vi> <vi><it>importantly,</it> the leaven in the mixture is quality <aq>George O'Brien</aq></vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="all-important"><ew>all-important</ew><hw>all–im*por*tant</hw><sound><wav>allim01w.wav</wav><wpr>+o-lim-!por-t/unt</wpr></sound><pr>ˌȯl-im-ˈpȯr-tᵊnt, -tənt</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1787</date><dt>:of very great or greatest importance <vi>an <it>all–important</it> question</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="self-important"><ew>self-important</ew><hw>self–important</hw><sound><wav>selfim05.wav</wav><wpr>+self-im-!por-t/unt</wpr></sound><pr>-tᵊnt, -tənt</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1766</date><dt>:having or showing self-importance</dt></def><uro><ure>self–im*por*tant*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro></entry>
</entry_list>