<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="influence[1]"><ew>influence</ew><subj>SY-3b#GV-3b#OC-1#AL-R</subj><hw hindex="1">in*flu*ence</hw><sound><wav>influe02.wav</wav><wpr>!in-+flU-un(t)s</wpr><wav>influe01.wav</wav><wpr>in-!flU-un(t)s</wpr></sound><pr>ˈin-ˌflü-ən(t)s, <it>especially Southern</it> in-ˈ</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English, from Old French, from Medieval Latin <it>influentia,</it> from Latin <it>influent-, influens,</it> present participle of <it>influere</it> to flow in, from <it>in-</it> + <it>fluere</it> to flow <ma>fluid</ma></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:an ethereal fluid held to flow from the stars and to affect the actions of humans</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an emanation of occult power held to derive from stars</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an emanation of spiritual or moral force</dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:the act or power of producing an effect without apparent exertion of force or direct exercise of command</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:corrupt interference with authority for personal gain</dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:the power or capacity of causing an effect in indirect or intangible ways :<sx>sway</sx></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:one that exerts influence</dt></def><dro><drp>under the influence</drp> <def><dt>:affected by alcohol :<sx>drunk</sx> <vi>was arrested for driving <it>under the influence</it></vi></dt></def></dro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>influence</sc> <sc>authority</sc> <sc>prestige</sc> <sc>weight</sc> <sc>credit</sc> mean power exerted over the minds or behavior of others. <sc>influence</sc> may apply to a force exercised and received consciously or unconsciously <vi>used her <it>influence</it> to get the bill passed</vi>. <sc>authority</sc> implies the power of winning devotion or allegiance or of compelling acceptance and belief <vi>his opinions lacked <it>authority</it></vi>. <sc>prestige</sc> implies the ascendancy given by conspicuous excellence or reputation for superiority <vi>the <it>prestige</it> of the newspaper</vi>. <sc>weight</sc> implies measurable or decisive influence in determining acts or choices <vi>their wishes obviously carried much <it>weight</it></vi>. <sc>credit</sc> suggests influence that arises from the confidence of others <vi>his <it>credit</it> with the press</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="influence[2]"><ew>influence</ew><hw hindex="2">influence</hw><fl>verb</fl><in><if>influenced</if></in><in><if>influenc*ing</if></in><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>1658</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to affect or alter by indirect or intangible means</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to have an effect on the condition or development of</dt><ss>affect</ss></def><uro><ure>in*flu*ence*able</ure><sound><wav>influe03.wav</wav><wpr>!in-+flU-un(t)-su-bul</wpr></sound> <pr>-ən(t)-sə-bəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="sphere of influence"><ew>sphere of influence</ew><grp>sphere of</grp><grp>sphere influence</grp><grp>of influence</grp><subj>GV</subj><hw>sphere of influence</hw><def><date>1885</date><dt>:a territorial area within which the political influence or the interests of one nation are held to be more or less paramount</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>