<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="join[1]"><ew>join</ew><subj>ML-vt3</subj><hw hindex="1">join</hw><sound><wav>join0001.wav</wav><wpr>!join</wpr></sound><pr>ˈjȯin</pr><fl>verb</fl><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French <it>joindre,</it> from Latin <it>jungere</it> <ma>yoke</ma></et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>13th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to put or bring together so as to form a unit <vi><it>join</it> two blocks of wood with glue</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to connect (as points) by a line</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:<sx>adjoin</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to put or bring into close association or relationship <vi><it>join</it><it>ed</it> in marriage</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to engage in (battle)</dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to come into the company of <vi><it>join</it><it>ed</it> us for lunch</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to associate oneself with <vi><it>join</it><it>ed</it> the church</vi></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to come together so as to be connected <vi>nouns <it>join</it> to form compounds</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>adjoin</sx> <vi>the two estates <it>join</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt> :to come into close association or relationship: as</dt>  <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to form an alliance</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to become a member of a group</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to take part in a collective activity <vi><it>join</it> in singing</vi> </dt></def><uro><ure>join*able</ure><sound><wav>join0002.wav</wav><wpr>!joi-nu-bul</wpr></sound> <pr>ˈjȯi-nə-bəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>join</sc> <sc>combine</sc> <sc>unite</sc> <sc>connect</sc> <sc>link</sc> <sc>associate</sc> <sc>relate</sc> mean to bring or come together into some manner of union. <sc>join</sc> implies a bringing into contact or conjunction of any degree of closeness <vi><it>joined</it> forces in an effort to win</vi>. <sc>combine</sc> implies some merging or mingling with corresponding loss of identity of each unit <vi><it>combined</it> jazz and rock to create a new music</vi>. <sc>unite</sc> implies somewhat greater loss of separate identity <vi>the colonies <it>united</it> to form a republic</vi>. <sc>connect</sc> suggests a loose or external attachment with little or no loss of identity <vi>a mutual defense treaty <it>connected</it> the two nations</vi>. <sc>link</sc> may imply strong connection or inseparability of elements still retaining identity <vi>a name forever <it>linked</it> with liberty</vi>. <sc>associate</sc> stresses the mere fact of frequent occurrence or existence together in space or in logical relation <vi>opera is popularly <it>associated</it> with high society</vi>. <sc>relate</sc> suggests the existence of a real or presumed logical connection <vi><it>related</it> what he observed to what he already knew</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="join[2]"><ew>join</ew><subj>MA-2</subj><hw hindex="2">join</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1884</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>joint</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>union <sxn>2d</sxn></sx></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>