<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="loan[1]"><ew>loan</ew><subj>EC-1a#GR-3</subj><hw hindex="1">loan</hw><sound><wav>loan0001.wav</wav><wpr>!lOn</wpr></sound><pr>ˈlōn</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English <it>lon,</it> from Old Norse <it>lān;</it> akin to Old English <it>lǣn</it> loan, <it>lēon</it> to lend, Latin <it>linquere</it> to leave, Greek <it>leipein</it></et><def><date>12th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:money lent at interest</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:something lent usually for the borrower's temporary use</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:the grant of temporary use</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the temporary duty of a person transferred to another job for a limited time</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:<sx>loanword</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="loan[2]"><ew>loan</ew><subj>EC</subj><hw hindex="2">loan</hw><fl>verb</fl><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>13th century</date><dt>:<sx>lend</sx></dt></def><uro><ure>loan*able</ure><sound><wav>loan0002.wav</wav><wpr>!lO-nu-bul</wpr></sound> <pr>ˈlō-nə-bəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><pl>usage</pl><pt>The verb <it>loan</it> is one of the words English settlers brought to America and continued to use after it had died out in Britain. Its use was soon noticed by British visitors and somewhat later by the New England literati, who considered it a bit provincial. It was flatly declared wrong in 1870 by a popular commentator, who based his objection on etymology. A later scholar showed that the commentator was ignorant of Old English and thus unsound in his objection, but by then it was too late, as the condemnation had been picked up by many other commentators. Although a surprising number of critics still voice objections, <it>loan</it> is entirely standard as a verb. You should note that it is used only literally; <it>lend</it> is the verb used for figurative expressions, such as “lending a hand” or “lending enchantment.”</pt></entry>
	<entry id="loan shark"><ew>loan shark</ew><subj>SY</subj><hw>loan shark</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1905</date><dt>:one who lends money to individuals at exorbitant rates of interest</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="loan-sharking"><ew>loan-sharking</ew><subj>SY</subj><hw>loan–shark*ing</hw><sound><wav>loansh01.wav</wav><wpr>!lOn-+sh@r-kiN</wpr></sound><pr>-ˌshär-kiŋ</pr><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1914</date><dt>:the practice of lending money at exorbitant rates of interest</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="loan translation"><ew>loan translation</ew><subj>GR</subj><hw>loan translation</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1917</date><dt>:a compound, derivative, or phrase that is introduced into a language through translation of the constituents of a term in another language (as <it>superman</it> from German <it>Übermensch</it>)</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="bridge loan"><ew>bridge loan</ew><subj>EC#GV</subj><hw>bridge loan</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1975</date><dt>:a short-term loan used to finance an enterprise, investment, or government pending the receipt of other funds</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="call loan"><ew>call loan</ew><subj>EC</subj><hw>call loan</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1852</date><dt>:a loan payable at the discretion of the borrower or on demand of the lender</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="demand loan"><ew>demand loan</ew><subj>EC</subj><hw>demand loan</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1913</date><dt>:<sx>call loan</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="savings and loan association"><ew>savings and loan association</ew><grp>savings and</grp><grp>savings loan</grp><grp>savings association</grp><grp>loan association</grp><grp>and loan</grp><grp>and association</grp><grp>loan association</grp><subj>EC</subj><hw>savings and loan association</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1884</date><dt>:a cooperative association organized to hold savings of members in the form of dividend-bearing shares and to invest chiefly in home mortgage loans <ca>called also <cat>savings and loan</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>