<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="mass[1]"><ew>mass</ew><subj>RC#MU-3</subj><hw hindex="1">mass</hw><sound><wav>mass0001.wav</wav><wpr>!mas</wpr></sound><pr>ˈmas</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>mæsse,</it> modification of Vulgar Latin <it>*messa,</it> literally, dismissal at the end of a religious service, from Late Latin <it>missa,</it> from Latin, feminine of <it>missus,</it> past participle of <it>mittere</it> to send</et><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <slb>capitalized</slb> <dt>:the liturgy of the Eucharist especially in accordance with the traditional Latin rite</dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>often capitalized</slb> <dt>:a celebration of the Eucharist <vi>Sunday <it>mass</it><it>es</it> held at three different hours</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a musical setting for the ordinary of the Mass</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="mass[2]"><ew>mass</ew><subj>CH-1c#PY-1c</subj><hw hindex="2">mass</hw><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English <it>masse,</it> from Anglo-French, from Latin <it>massa,</it> from Greek <it>maza;</it> akin to Greek <it>massein</it> to knead <ma>mingle</ma></et><def><date>15th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a quantity or aggregate of matter usually of considerable size</dt>  <sn>b <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:<sx>expanse</sx> <sx>bulk</sx></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:<fw>massive</fw> quality or effect <vi>impressed me with such <it>mass</it> and such vividness <aq>F. M. Ford</aq></vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(3)</snp></sn> <dt>:the principal part or main body <vi>the great <it>mass</it> of the continent is buried under an ice cap <aq>Walter Sullivan</aq></vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(4)</snp></sn> <dt>:<sx>aggregate</sx> <sx>whole</sx> <vi>men in the <it>mass</it></vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the property of a body that is a measure of its inertia and that is commonly taken as a measure of the amount of material it contains and causes it to have weight in a gravitational field</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a large quantity, amount, or number <vi>a great <it>mass</it> of material</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:a large body of persons in a compact group :a body of persons regarded as an aggregate</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the great body of the people as contrasted with the elite <un>often used in plural <vi>the underprivileged and disadvantaged <it>mass</it><it>es</it> <aq>C. A. Buss</aq></vi></un></dt><ss>bulk</ss></def></entry>
	<entry id="mass[3]"><ew>mass</ew><hw hindex="3">mass</hw><fl>verb</fl><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>14th century</date><dt>:to form or collect into a mass</dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <dt>:to assemble in a mass <vi>three thousand students had <it>mass</it><it>ed</it> in the plaza <aq>A. E. Neville</aq></vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="mass[4]"><ew>mass</ew><hw hindex="4">mass</hw><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1733</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:of or relating to the mass of the people <vi><it>mass</it> market</vi> <vi><it>mass</it> education</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:being one of or at one with the mass :<sx>average</sx> <sx>commonplace</sx> <vi><it>mass</it> man</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:participated in by or affecting a large number of individuals <vi><it>mass</it> destruction</vi> <vi><it>mass</it> demonstrations</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:having a large-scale character <vi><it>mass</it> plantings of tulips</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:viewed as a whole :<sx>total</sx> <vi>the <it>mass</it> effect of a design</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="Mass"><ew>Mass</ew><subj>GZ</subj><hw>Mass</hw><fl>abbreviation</fl><def><dt><fw>Massachusetts</fw></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="mass card"><ew>mass card</ew><subj>RC</subj><hw>mass card</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1930</date><dt>:a card notifying the recipient (as a bereaved family) that a mass is to be offered for the repose of the soul of a specified deceased person</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="mass driver"><ew>mass driver</ew><subj>AE#ME</subj><hw>mass driver</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1975</date><dt>:a large electromagnetic catapult designed to hurl material (as from an asteroid) into space</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="mass-market"><ew>mass-market</ew><subj>PU-1</subj><hw>mass–mar*ket</hw><sound><wav>massma01.wav</wav><wpr>!mas-!m@r-kut</wpr></sound><pr>ˈmas-ˈmär-kət</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1952</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:sold through such retail outlets as supermarkets and drugstores as well as through bookstores <vi>a <it>mass–market</it> paperback</vi></dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:of, relating to, or publishing mass-market materials</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:appealing or sold to a general audience</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="mass medium"><ew>mass medium</ew><subj>BR#PU</subj><hw>mass medium</hw><fl>noun</fl><in><il>plural</il> <if>mass media</if></in><def><date>1923</date><dt>:a medium of communication (as newspapers, radio, or television) that is designed to reach the mass of the people <un>usually used in plural</un></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="mass noun"><ew>mass noun</ew><subj>GR</subj><hw>mass noun</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1933</date><dt>:a noun (as <it>sand</it> or <it>water</it>) that characteristically denotes in many languages a homogeneous substance or a concept without subdivisions and that in English is preceded in indefinite singular constructions by <it>some</it> rather than <it>a</it> or <it>an</it> <dx>compare <dxt>count noun</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>