<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="mercy"><ew>mercy</ew><subj>LW-1b#RC-2a#RE-2a#RJ-2a</subj><hw>mer*cy</hw><sound><wav>mercy001.wav</wav><wpr>!mur-sE</wpr></sound><pr>ˈmər-sē</pr><fl>noun</fl><in><il>plural</il> <if>mercies</if></in><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French <it>merci,</it> from Medieval Latin <it>merced-, merces,</it> from Latin, price paid, wages, from <it>merc-, merx</it> merchandise</et><def><date>13th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:compassion or forbearance shown especially to an offender or to one subject to one's power</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:lenient or compassionate treatment <vi>begged for <it>mercy</it></vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:imprisonment rather than death imposed as penalty for first-degree murder</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:a blessing that is an act of divine favor or compassion</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a fortunate circumstance <vi>it was a <it>mercy</it> they found her before she froze</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:compassionate treatment of those in distress <vi>works of <it>mercy</it> among the poor</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>mercy</ure> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><dro><drp>at the mercy of</drp> <def><dt>:wholly in the power of :with no way to protect oneself against</dt></def></dro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>mercy</sc> <sc>charity</sc> <sc>clemency</sc> <sc>grace</sc> <sc>leniency</sc> mean a disposition to show kindness or compassion. <sc>mercy</sc> implies compassion that forbears punishing even when justice demands it <vi>threw himself on the <it>mercy</it> of the court</vi>. <sc>charity</sc> stresses benevolence and goodwill shown in broad understanding and tolerance of others <vi>show a little <it>charity</it> for the less fortunate</vi>. <sc>clemency</sc> implies a mild or merciful disposition in one having the power or duty of punishing <vi>the judge refused to show <it>clemency</it></vi>. <sc>grace</sc> implies a benign attitude and a willingness to grant favors or make concessions <vi>by the <it>grace</it> of God</vi>. <sc>leniency</sc> implies lack of severity in punishing <vi>criticized the courts for excessive <it>leniency</it></vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="mercy killing"><ew>mercy killing</ew><subj>MD#SY</subj><hw>mercy killing</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1935</date><dt>:<sx>euthanasia</sx></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>