<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="model[1]"><ew>model</ew><subj>BI-8#PY-11#CL-10a#FA-6#JB-9#AV-10b#MA-12#BI-14#MD-14#CP-12</subj><hw hindex="1">mod*el</hw><sound><wav>model001.wav</wav><wpr>!m@-d/ul</wpr></sound><pr>ˈmä-dᵊl</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle French <it>modelle,</it> from Old Italian <it>modello,</it> from Vulgar Latin <it>*modellus,</it> from Latin <it>modulus</it> small measure, from <it>modus</it></et><def><date>1575</date> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>obsolete</ssl> <dt>:a set of plans for a building</dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>dialect British</ssl> <dt>:<sx>copy</sx> <sx>image</sx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:structural design <vi>a home on the <it>model</it> of an old farmhouse</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:a usually miniature representation of something</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:a pattern of something to be made</dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:an example for imitation or emulation</dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:a person or thing that serves as a pattern for an artist</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:one who poses for an artist</dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:<sx>archetype</sx></dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:an organism whose appearance a mimic imitates</dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:one who is employed to display clothes or other merchandise</dt> <sn>10 a</sn> <dt>:a type or design of clothing</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a type or design of product (as a car)</dt> <sn>11</sn> <dt>:a description or analogy used to help visualize something (as an atom) that cannot be directly observed</dt> <sn>12</sn> <dt>:a system of postulates, data, and inferences presented as a mathematical description of an entity or state of affairs</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:a computer simulation based on such a system <vi>climate <it>model</it><it>s</it></vi></dt> <sn>13</sn> <dt>:<sx>version <sxn>3</sxn></sx></dt> <sn>14</sn> <dt>:<sx>animal model</sx></dt></def><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>model</sc> <sc>example</sc> <sc>pattern</sc> <sc>exemplar</sc> <sc>ideal</sc> mean someone or something set before one for guidance or imitation. <sc>model</sc> applies to something taken or proposed as worthy of imitation <vi>a decor that is a <it>model</it> of good taste</vi>. <sc>example</sc> applies to a person to be imitated or in some contexts on no account to be imitated but to be regarded as a warning <vi>children tend to follow the <it>example</it> of their parents</vi>. <sc>pattern</sc> suggests a clear and detailed archetype or prototype <vi>American industry set a <it>pattern</it> for others to follow</vi>. <sc>exemplar</sc> suggests either a faultless example to be emulated or a perfect typification <vi>cited Joan of Arc as the <it>exemplar</it> of courage</vi>. <sc>ideal</sc> implies the best possible exemplification either in reality or in conception <vi>never found a job that matched his <it>ideal</it></vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="model[2]"><ew>model</ew><subj>FA-vt3a#FA-vi1#CP-vt3b#FA-vi#CL-vt5#CL-vi2</subj><hw hindex="2">model</hw><fl>verb</fl><in><if>modeled</if> <il>or</il> <if>modelled</if></in><in><if>model*ing</if> <il>or</il> <if>model*ling</if> <pr>ˈmäd-liŋ, ˈmä-dᵊl-iŋ</pr></in><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>1625</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to plan or form after a pattern :<sx>shape</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:to make into an organization (as an army, government, or parish)</dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to shape or fashion in a plastic material</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to produce a representation or simulation of <vi>using a computer to <it>model</it> a problem</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to construct or fashion in imitation of a particular model <vi><it>model</it><it>ed</it> its constitution on that of the United States</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to display by wearing, using, or posing with <vi><it>model</it><it>ed</it> gowns</vi></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to design or imitate forms :make a pattern <vi>enjoys <it>model</it><it>ing</it> in clay</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to work or act as a fashion or art model</dt></def><uro><ure>mod*el*er</ure><sound><wav>model003.wav</wav><wpr>!m@-d/ul-ur</wpr></sound> <vr><vl>also</vl> <va>mod*el*ler</va> <pr>ˈmäd-lər, ˈmä-dᵊl-ər</pr></vr> <fl>noun</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="model[3]"><ew>model</ew><hw hindex="3">model</hw><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1844</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:serving as or capable of serving as a pattern <vi>a <it>model</it> student</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:being a usually miniature representation of something <vi>a <it>model</it> airplane</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="animal model"><ew>animal model</ew><subj>MD#VT#BI</subj><hw>animal model</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1973</date><dt>:an animal sufficiently like humans in its anatomy, physiology, or response to a pathogen to be used in medical research in order to obtain results that can be extrapolated to human medicine</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:a pathological or physiological condition that occurs in such an animal and is similar to one occurring in humans</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="role model"><ew>role model</ew><subj>PS</subj><hw>role model</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1957</date><dt>:a person whose behavior in a particular role is imitated by others</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="Watson-Crick model"><ew>Watson-Crick model</ew><subj>GN#BC</subj><hw>Watson–Crick model</hw><fl>noun</fl><et>J. D. <it>Watson</it> &amp; F. H. C. <it>Crick</it></et><def><date>1958</date><dt>:a model of DNA structure in which the molecule is a cross-linked double-stranded helix, each strand is composed of alternating links of phosphate and deoxyribose, and the strands are cross-linked by pairs of purine and pyrimidine bases projecting inward from the deoxyribose sugars and joined by hydrogen bonds with adenine paired with thymine and with cytosine paired with guanine <dx>compare <dxt>double helix</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>