<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="mystery[1]"><ew>mystery</ew><subj>RC-1a,b RJ-1a#RE-1a,c#LT-2d</subj><hw hindex="1">mys*tery</hw><sound><wav>myster02.wav</wav><wpr>!mis-t(u-)rE</wpr></sound><pr>ˈmis-t(ə-)rē</pr><fl>noun</fl><in><il>plural</il> <if>mys*ter*ies</if></in><et>Middle English <it>mysterie,</it> from Latin <it>mysterium,</it> from Greek <it>mystērion,</it> from <it>mystēs</it> initiate</et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a religious truth that one can know only by revelation and cannot fully understand</dt>  <sn>b <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:any of the 15 events (as the Nativity, the Crucifixion, or the Assumption) serving as a subject for meditation during the saying of the rosary</dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <slb>capitalized</slb> <dt>:a Christian sacrament</dt> <sd>specifically</sd> <dt>:<sx>eucharist</sx></dt>  <sn>c <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:a secret religious rite believed (as in Eleusinian and Mithraic cults) to impart enduring bliss to the initiate</dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:a cult devoted to such rites</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:something not understood or beyond understanding :<sx>enigma</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <ssl>obsolete</ssl> <dt>:a private secret</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the secret or specialized practices or ritual peculiar to an occupation or a body of people <vi>the <it>mysteries</it> of the tailor's craft</vi></dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:a piece of fiction dealing usually with the solution of a <fw>mysterious</fw> crime</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:profound, inexplicable, or secretive quality or character <vi>the <it>mystery</it> of her smile</vi></dt></def><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>mystery</sc> <sc>problem</sc> <sc>enigma</sc> <sc>riddle</sc> <sc>puzzle</sc> mean something which baffles or perplexes. <sc>mystery</sc> applies to what cannot be fully understood by reason or less strictly to whatever resists or defies explanation <vi>the <it>mystery</it> of the stone monoliths</vi>. <sc>problem</sc> applies to a question or difficulty calling for a solution or causing concern <vi><it>problems</it> created by high technology</vi>. <sc>enigma</sc> applies to utterance or behavior that is very difficult to interpret <vi>his suicide remains an <it>enigma</it></vi>. <sc>riddle</sc> suggests an enigma or problem involving paradox or apparent contradiction <vi>the <it>riddle</it> of the reclusive pop star</vi>. <sc>puzzle</sc> applies to an enigma or problem that challenges ingenuity for its solution <vi>the thief's motives were a <it>puzzle</it> for the police</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="mystery[2]"><ew>mystery</ew><subj>LT-3#BZ-1#BZ-2</subj><hw hindex="2">mystery</hw><fl>noun</fl><in><il>plural</il> <if>myster*ies</if></in><et>Middle English ministry, office, craft, from Anglo-French <it>mesterie</it>, from Late Latin <it>misterium, mysterium,</it> alteration of <it>ministerium</it> service, occupation, from <it>minister</it> servant <ma>minister</ma></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:<sx>trade</sx> <sx>craft</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:a body of persons engaged in a particular trade, business, or profession :<sx>guild</sx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:<sx>mystery play</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="mystery play"><ew>mystery play</ew><subj>LT</subj><hw>mystery play</hw><fl>noun</fl><et><it>mystery</it></et><def><date>1852</date><dt>:a medieval drama based on scriptural incidents (as the creation of the world, the Flood, or the life, death, and resurrection of Christ) <dx>compare <dxt>miracle play</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>