<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="native[1]"><ew>native</ew><subj>BI-6#BI-9#BT-6#BT-9#ZO-6#ZO-9#MI-8b#MN-8b#AG-6#AI-10</subj><hw hindex="1">na*tive</hw><sound><wav>native01.wav</wav><wpr>!nA-tiv</wpr></sound><pr>ˈnā-tiv</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English <it>natif,</it> from Middle French, from Latin <it>nativus,</it> from <it>natus,</it> past participle of <it>nasci</it> to be born <ma>nation</ma></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>inborn</sx> <sx>innate</sx> <vi><it>native</it> talents</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:belonging to a particular place by birth</dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:closely related</dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:belonging to or associated with one by birth</dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:<sx>natural</sx> <sx>normal</sx></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:grown, produced, or originating in a particular place or in the vicinity :<sx>local</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:living or growing naturally in a particular region :<sx>indigenous</sx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:<sx>simple</sx> <sx>unaffected</sx></dt> <sn>8 a</sn> <dt>:constituting the original substance or source</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:found in nature especially in an unadulterated form <vi>mining <it>native</it> silver</vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <ssl>chiefly Australian</ssl> <dt>:having a usually superficial resemblance to a specified English plant or animal</dt> <sn>10</sn> <slb>capitalized</slb> <dt>:of, relating to, or being a member of an aboriginal people of North or South America :<sx>native american</sx></dt></def><uro><ure>na*tive*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><uro><ure>na*tive*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>native</sc> <sc>indigenous</sc> <sc>endemic</sc> <sc>aboriginal</sc> mean belonging to a locality. <sc>native</sc> implies birth or origin in a place or region and may suggest compatibility with it <vi><it>native</it> tribal customs</vi>. <sc>indigenous</sc> applies to species or races and adds to <sc>native</sc> the implication of not having been introduced from elsewhere <vi>maize is <it>indigenous</it> to America</vi>. <sc>endemic</sc> implies being peculiar to a region <vi>edelweiss is <it>endemic</it> in the Alps</vi>. <sc>aboriginal</sc> implies having no known race preceding in occupancy of the region <vi>the <it>aboriginal</it> peoples of Australia</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="native[2]"><ew>native</ew><subj>AG-2b</subj><hw hindex="2">native</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1535</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:one born or reared in a particular place</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:an original or indigenous inhabitant</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:something indigenous to a particular locality</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a local resident</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a person who has always lived in a place as distinguished from a visitor or a temporary resident</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="Native American"><ew>Native American</ew><subj>AI</subj><hw>Native American</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1737</date><dt>:a member of any of the aboriginal peoples of the western hemisphere</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a Native American of North America and especially the United States <dx>compare <dxt>american indian</dxt></dx></dt></def><uro><ure>Native American</ure> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>
</entry_list>