<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="offense"><ew>offense</ew><subj>SP-3b#SP-3c#SP-3d#LW-5b#LW-3a</subj><hw>of*fense</hw><sound><wav>offens02.wav</wav><wpr>u-!fen(t)s</wpr><wav>offens01.wav</wav><wpr>!@-+fen(t)s</wpr></sound><vr><vl>or</vl> <va>of*fence</va> <sound><wav>offens02.wav</wav><wpr>u-!fen(t)s</wpr><wav>offens01.wav</wav><wpr>!@-+fen(t)s</wpr></sound> <pr>ə-ˈfen(t)s, <it>especially for 3</it> ˈä-ˌfen(t)s, ˈȯ-</pr></vr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French, from Latin <it>offensa,</it> from feminine of <it>offensus,</it> past participle of <it>offendere</it></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>obsolete</ssl> <dt>:an act of stumbling</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:a cause or occasion of sin :<sx>stumbling block</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something that outrages the moral or physical senses</dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:the act of attacking :<sx>assault</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the means or method of attacking or of attempting to score</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the <fw>offensive</fw> team or members of a team playing offensive positions</dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:scoring ability</dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:the act of displeasing or affronting</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the state of being insulted or morally outraged <vi>takes <it>offense</it> at the slightest criticism</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:a breach of a moral or social code :<sx>sin</sx> <sx>misdeed</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an infraction of law</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:<sx>misdemeanor</sx></dt></def><uro><ure>of*fense*less</ure><sound><wav>offens03.wav</wav><wpr>u-!fen(t)s-lus</wpr></sound> <pr>-ləs</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>offense</sc> <sc>resentment</sc> <sc>umbrage</sc> <sc>pique</sc> <sc>dudgeon</sc> <sc>huff</sc> mean an emotional response to or an emotional state resulting from a slight or indignity. <sc>offense</sc> implies hurt displeasure <vi>takes deep <it>offense</it> at racial slurs</vi>. <sc>resentment</sc> suggests lasting indignation or ill will <vi>harbored a lifelong <it>resentment</it> of his brother</vi>. <sc>umbrage</sc> may suggest hurt pride, resentment, or suspicion of another's motives <vi>took <it>umbrage</it> at the offer of advice</vi>. <sc>pique</sc> applies to a transient feeling of wounded vanity <vi>in a <it>pique</it> I foolishly declined the invitation</vi>. <sc>dudgeon</sc> suggests an angry fit of indignation <vi>stormed out of the meeting in high <it>dudgeon</it></vi>. <sc>huff</sc> implies a peevish short-lived spell of anger usually at a petty cause <vi>in a <it>huff</it> he slammed the door</vi>.</pt><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>offense</sc> <sc>sin</sc> <sc>vice</sc> <sc>crime</sc> <sc>scandal</sc> mean a transgression of law. <sc>offense</sc> applies to the infraction of any law, rule, or code <vi>at that school no <it>offense</it> went unpunished</vi>. <sc>sin</sc> implies an offense against moral or religious law <vi>the <it>sin</it> of blasphemy</vi>. <sc>vice</sc> applies to a habit or practice that degrades or corrupts <vi>regarded gambling as a <it>vice</it></vi>. <sc>crime</sc> implies a serious offense punishable by the law of the state <vi>the <it>crime</it> of murder</vi>. <sc>scandal</sc> applies to an offense that outrages the public conscience <vi>a career ruined by a sex <it>scandal</it></vi>.</pt></entry>
</entry_list>