<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="opinion"><ew>opinion</ew><subj>LW-3b</subj><hw>opin*ion</hw><sound><wav>opinio01.wav</wav><wpr>u-!pin-yun</wpr></sound><pr>ə-ˈpin-yən</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French, from Latin <it>opinion-, opinio,</it> from <it>opinari</it></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a view, judgment, or appraisal formed in the mind about a particular matter</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>approval</sx> <sx>esteem</sx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:belief stronger than impression and less strong than positive knowledge</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a generally held view</dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:a formal expression of judgment or advice by an expert</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the formal expression (as by a judge, court, or referee) of the legal reasons and principles upon which a legal decision is based</dt></def><uro><ure>opin*ioned</ure><sound><wav>opinio02.wav</wav><wpr>u-!pin-yund</wpr></sound> <pr>-yənd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>opinion</sc> <sc>view</sc> <sc>belief</sc> <sc>conviction</sc> <sc>persuasion</sc> <sc>sentiment</sc> mean a judgment one holds as true. <sc>opinion</sc> implies a conclusion thought out yet open to dispute <vi>each expert seemed to have a different <it>opinion</it></vi>. <sc>view</sc> suggests a subjective opinion <vi>very assertive in stating his <it>views</it></vi>. <sc>belief</sc> implies often deliberate acceptance and intellectual assent <vi>a firm <it>belief</it> in her party's platform</vi>. <sc>conviction</sc> applies to a firmly and seriously held belief <vi>the <it>conviction</it> that animal life is as sacred as human</vi>. <sc>persuasion</sc> suggests a belief grounded on assurance (as by evidence) of its truth <vi>was of the <it>persuasion</it> that everything changes</vi>. <sc>sentiment</sc> suggests a settled opinion reflective of one's feelings <vi>her feminist <it>sentiments</it> are well-known</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="self-opinion"><ew>self-opinion</ew><hw>self–opin*ion</hw><sound><wav>selfop01.wav</wav><wpr>+self-u-!pin-yun</wpr></sound><pr>-ə-ˈpin-yən</pr><fl>noun</fl><def><date>circa 1580</date><dt>:high or exaggerated opinion of oneself :<sx>self-conceit</sx></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>