<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="pity[1]"><ew>pity</ew><hw hindex="1">pity</hw><sound><wav>pity0001.wav</wav><wpr>!pi-tE</wpr></sound><pr>ˈpi-tē</pr><fl>noun</fl><in><il>plural</il> <if>pit*ies</if></in><et>Middle English <it>pite,</it> from Anglo-French <it>pité,</it> from Latin <it>pietat-, pietas</it> piety, pity, from <it>pius</it> pious</et><def><date>13th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:sympathetic sorrow for one suffering, distressed, or unhappy</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:capacity to feel pity</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something to be regretted <vi>it's a <it>pity</it> you can't go</vi></dt></def><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>pity</sc> <sc>compassion</sc> <sc>commiseration</sc> <sc>condolence</sc> <sc>sympathy</sc> mean the act or capacity for sharing the painful feelings of another. <sc>pity</sc> implies tender or sometimes slightly contemptuous sorrow for one in misery or distress <vi>felt <it>pity</it> for the captives</vi>. <sc>compassion</sc> implies pity coupled with an urgent desire to aid or to spare <vi>treats the homeless with great <it>compassion</it></vi>. <sc>commiseration</sc> suggests pity expressed outwardly in exclamations, tears, or words of comfort <vi>murmurs of <it>commiseration</it> filled the loser's headquarters</vi>. <sc>condolence</sc> applies chiefly to formal expression of grief to one who has suffered loss <vi>expressed their <it>condolences</it> to the widow</vi>. <sc>sympathy</sc> often suggests a tender concern but can also imply a power to enter into another's emotional experience of any sort <vi>went to my best friend for <it>sympathy</it></vi> <vi>in <it>sympathy</it> with her desire to locate her natural parents</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="pity[2]"><ew>pity</ew><hw hindex="2">pity</hw><fl>verb</fl><in><if>pit*ied</if></in><in><if>pity*ing</if></in><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>15th century</date> <dt>:to feel pity for</dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <dt>:to feel pity</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="self-pity"><ew>self-pity</ew><hw>self–pity</hw><sound><wav>selfpi01.wav</wav><wpr>!self-!pi-tE</wpr></sound><pr>ˈself-ˈpi-tē</pr><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1621</date><dt>:pity for oneself</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a self-indulgent dwelling on one's own sorrows or misfortunes</dt></def><uro><ure>self–pity*ing</ure><sound><wav>selfpi02.wav</wav><wpr>!self-!pi-tE-iN</wpr></sound> <pr>-tē-iŋ</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><uro><ure>self–pity*ing*ly</ure><sound><wav>selfpi03.wav</wav><wpr>!self-!pi-tE-iN-lE</wpr></sound> <pr>-iŋ-lē</pr> <fl>adverb</fl></uro></entry>
</entry_list>