<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="plenty[1]"><ew>plenty</ew><hw hindex="1">plen*ty</hw><sound><wav>plenty01.wav</wav><wpr>!plen-tE</wpr></sound><pr>ˈplen-tē</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English <it>plente,</it> from Anglo-French <it>plenté,</it> from Late Latin <it>plenitat-, plenitas,</it> from Latin, fullness, from <it>plenus</it> full <ma>full</ma></et><def><date>13th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a full or more than adequate amount or supply <vi>had <it>plenty</it> of time to finish the job</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a large number or amount <vi>in <it>plenty</it> of trouble</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the quality or state of being copious :<sx>plentifulness</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="plenty[2]"><ew>plenty</ew><hw hindex="2">plenty</hw><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:<fw>plentiful</fw> in amount, number, or supply <vi>if reasons were as <it>plenty</it> as blackberries <aq>Shakespeare</aq></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>ample</sx> <vi><it>plenty</it> work to be done <aq><it>Time</it></aq></vi></dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt>Many commentators object to use of sense 2 in writing; it appears to be limited chiefly to spoken English. Sense 1 is literary but is no longer in common use.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="plenty[3]"><ew>plenty</ew><hw hindex="3">plenty</hw><fl>adverb</fl><def><date>1842</date><dt>:more than sufficiently :to a considerable degree <vi>the nights were <it>plenty</it> cold <aq>F. B. Gipson</aq></vi></dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt>Many handbooks advise avoiding the adverb <it>plenty</it> in writing; “use <it>very, quite,</it> or a more precise word,” they advise. Actually <it>plenty</it> is often a more precise word than its recommended replacements; <it>very, fully,</it> or <it>quite</it> will not work as well in these typical quotations <vi>it's already <it>plenty</it> hot for us in the kitchen without some dolt opening the oven <aq>C. H. Bridges</aq></vi> <vi>may not be rising quite as rapidly as other health costs, but it is going up <it>plenty</it> fast <aq><it>Changing Times</it></aq></vi>. It is not used in more formal writing.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="horn of plenty"><ew>horn of plenty</ew><grp>horn of</grp><grp>horn plenty</grp><grp>of plenty</grp><hw>horn of plenty</hw><def><date>circa 1586</date><dt>:<sx>cornucopia</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="Plenty, Bay of"><ew>Plenty, Bay of</ew><grp>Plenty Bay</grp><grp>Plenty of</grp><grp>Bay of</grp><hw>Plenty, Bay of</hw><fl>geographical name</fl><def><dt>inlet of the S. Pacific <g>N</g> New Zealand on <g>NE</g> coast of North Island</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>