<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="quarrel[1]"><ew>quarrel</ew><subj>HF#WX</subj><hw hindex="1">quar*rel</hw><sound><wav>quarre02.wav</wav><wpr>!kwor(-u)l</wpr><wav>quarre01.wav</wav><wpr>!kw@r(-u)l</wpr></sound><pr>ˈkwȯr(-ə)l, ˈkwär(-ə)l</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French, square block of stone, bolt, from Vulgar Latin <it>*quadrellum,</it> diminutive of Latin <it>quadrum</it> square <ma>quadrate</ma></et><def><date>13th century</date><dt>:a square-headed bolt or arrow especially for a crossbow</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="quarrel[2]"><ew>quarrel</ew><hw hindex="2">quarrel</hw><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English <it>querele,</it> from Anglo-French, from Latin <it>querela</it> grievance, complaint, from <it>queri</it> to complain</et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a ground of dispute or complaint <vi>have no <it>quarrel</it> with a different approach</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a usually verbal conflict between antagonists :<sx>altercation</sx></dt></def><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>quarrel</sc> <sc>wrangle</sc> <sc>altercation</sc> <sc>squabble</sc> mean a noisy dispute usually marked by anger. <sc>quarrel</sc> implies heated verbal contention, stressing strained or severed relations which may persist beyond the contention <vi>a <it>quarrel</it> nearly destroyed the relationship</vi>. <sc>wrangle</sc> suggests undignified and often futile disputation with a noisy insistence on differing opinions <vi><it>wrangle</it> interminably about small issues</vi>. <sc>altercation</sc> implies fighting with words as the chief weapon, although it may also connote blows <vi>a loud public <it>altercation</it></vi>. <sc>squabble</sc> stresses childish and unseemly dispute over petty matters, but it need not imply bitterness or anger <vi>a brief <it>squabble</it> over what to do next</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="quarrel[3]"><ew>quarrel</ew><hw hindex="3">quarrel</hw><fl>verb</fl><in><if>quarreled</if> <il>or</il> <if>quarrelled</if></in><in><if>quarrel*ing</if> <il>or</il> <if>quarrel*ling</if></in><def><vt>intransitive verb</vt><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to find fault <vi>many people <it>quarrel</it> with the idea <aq><it>Johns Hopkins Magazine</it></aq></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to contend or dispute actively <vi><it>quarrel</it><it>ed</it> frequently with his superiors <aq><it>London Calling</it></aq></vi></dt></def><uro><ure>quar*rel*er</ure> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>quar*rel*ler</va> </vr> <fl>noun</fl></uro></entry>
</entry_list>