<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="regular[1]"><ew>regular</ew><subj>MA-2b#BT-2c#ML-5#GR-4c#RJ-1#RC-1#PI-3b</subj><hw hindex="1">reg*u*lar</hw><sound><wav>regula01.wav</wav><wpr>!re-gyu-lur</wpr></sound><pr>ˈre-gyə-lər, ˈre-g(ə-)lər <it>also</it> ˈrā-</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English <it>reguler,</it> from Anglo-French, from Late Latin <it>regularis</it> regular, from Latin, of a bar, from <it>regula</it> rule <ma>rule</ma></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:belonging to a religious order</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:formed, built, arranged, or ordered according to some established rule, law, principle, or type</dt>  <sn>b <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:both equilateral and equiangular <vi>a <it>regular</it> polygon</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:having faces that are congruent regular polygons and all the polyhedral angles congruent <vi>a <it>regular</it> polyhedron</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <ssl>of a flower</ssl> <dt>:having the arrangement of floral parts exhibiting radial symmetry with members of the same whorl similar in form</dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:<sx>orderly</sx> <sx>methodical</sx> <vi><it>regular</it> habits</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:recurring, attending, or functioning at fixed, uniform, or normal intervals <vi>a <it>regular</it> income</vi> <vi>a <it>regular</it> churchgoer</vi> <vi><it>regular</it> bowel movements</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:constituted, conducted, scheduled, or done in conformity with established or prescribed usages, rules, or discipline</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt> :<sx>normal</sx> <sx>standard</sx>: as</dt>  <sn><snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:<sx>absolute</sx> <sx>complete</sx> <vi>a <it>regular</it> fool</vi> <vi>the office seemed like a <it>regular</it> madhouse</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:thinking or behaving in an acceptable, normal, or agreeable manner <vi>was a <it>regular</it> guy</vi> </dt>  <sn>c <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:conforming to the normal or usual manner of inflection</dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:<sx>weak <sxn>7</sxn></sx></dt>  <sn>d</sn> <ssl>of a postage stamp</ssl> <dt>:issued in large numbers over a long period for general use in prepayment of postage</dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:of, relating to, or constituting the permanent standing military force of a state <vi>the <it>regular</it> army</vi> <vi><it>regular</it> soldiers</vi></dt></def><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>regular</sc> <sc>normal</sc> <sc>typical</sc> <sc>natural</sc> mean being of the sort or kind that is expected as usual, ordinary, or average. <sc>regular</sc> stresses conformity to a rule, standard, or pattern <vi>the club's <it>regular</it> monthly meeting</vi>. <sc>normal</sc> implies lack of deviation from what has been discovered or established as the most usual or expected <vi><it>normal</it> behavior for a two-year-old</vi>. <sc>typical</sc> implies showing all important traits of a type, class, or group and may suggest lack of strong individuality <vi>a <it>typical</it> small town</vi>. <sc>natural</sc> applies to what conforms to a thing's essential nature, function, or mode of being <vi>the <it>natural</it> love of a mother for her child</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="regular[2]"><ew>regular</ew><subj>RC-1a#ML-1b#SP-1d#CL-2</subj><hw hindex="2">regular</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>15th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt> :one who is regular: as</dt>  <sn>a</sn> <dt>:one of the regular clergy</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a soldier in a regular army</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:one who can be trusted or depended on <vi>a party <it>regular</it></vi></dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:a player on an athletic team who usually starts every game</dt>  <sn>e</sn> <dt>:one who is usually present or participating</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a long-standing regular customer </dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:something of average or medium size</dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:a clothing size designed to fit a person of average height</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="regular solid"><ew>regular solid</ew><subj>MA</subj><hw>regular solid</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1785</date><dt>:any of the five possible regular polyhedrons that include the regular forms of the tetrahedron, hexahedron, octahedron, dodecahedron, and icosahedron</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="canon regular"><ew>canon regular</ew><subj>RC</subj><hw>canon regular</hw><fl>noun</fl><in><il>plural</il> <if>canons regular</if></in><def><date>14th century</date><dt>:a member of one of several Roman Catholic religious institutes of regular priests living in community under a usually Augustinian rule</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>