<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="relieve"><ew>relieve</ew><subj>SB-vi3#ML-vt3a#FA-vt5b#PR-vt5b#PI-vt6#MD-vt2a</subj><hw>re*lieve</hw><sound><wav>reliev01.wav</wav><wpr>ri-!lEv</wpr></sound><pr>ri-ˈlēv</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>re*lieved</if></in><in><if>re*liev*ing</if></in><et>Middle English <it>releven,</it> from Anglo-French <it>relever</it> to raise, relieve, from Latin <it>relevare,</it> from <it>re-</it> + <it>levare</it> to raise <ma>lever</ma></et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to free from a burden :give aid or help to</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to set free from an obligation, condition, or restriction</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to ease of a burden, wrong, or oppression by judicial or legislative interposition</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to bring about the removal or alleviation of :<sx>mitigate</sx> <vi>helps <it>relieve</it> stress</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>rob</sx> <sx>deprive</sx> <vi><it>relieved</it> us of our belongings</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to release from a post, station, or duty</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to take the place of <vi>will <it>relieve</it> the starting pitcher</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to remove or lessen the monotony of <vi>a park <it>relieve</it><it>s</it> the urban landscape</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:to set off by contrast</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to raise in <fw>relief</fw></dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to discharge the bladder or bowels of (oneself)</dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to bring or give relief</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to stand out in relief</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to serve as a relief pitcher</dt></def><uro><ure>re*liev*able</ure><sound><wav>reliev02.wav</wav><wpr>ri-!lE-vu-bul</wpr></sound> <pr>-ˈlē-və-bəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>relieve</sc> <sc>alleviate</sc> <sc>lighten</sc> <sc>assuage</sc> <sc>mitigate</sc> <sc>allay</sc> mean to make something less grievous. <sc>relieve</sc> implies a lifting of enough of a burden to make it tolerable <vi>took an aspirin to <it>relieve</it> the pain</vi>. <sc>alleviate</sc> implies temporary or partial lessening of pain or distress <vi>the lotion <it>alleviated</it> the itching</vi>. <sc>lighten</sc> implies reducing a burdensome or depressing weight <vi>good news would <it>lighten</it> our worries</vi>. <sc>assuage</sc> implies softening or sweetening what is harsh or disagreeable <vi>ocean breezes <it>assuaged</it> the intense heat</vi>. <sc>mitigate</sc> suggests a moderating or countering of the effect of something violent or painful <vi>the need to <it>mitigate</it> barbaric laws</vi>. <sc>allay</sc> implies an effective calming or soothing of fears or alarms <vi><it>allayed</it> their fears</vi>.</pt></entry>
</entry_list>