<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="rescue"><ew>rescue</ew><subj>ML-c</subj><hw>res*cue</hw><sound><wav>rescue01.wav</wav><wpr>!res-(+)kyU</wpr></sound><pr>ˈres-(ˌ)kyü</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>res*cued</if></in><in><if>res*cu*ing</if></in><et>Middle English <it>rescouen, rescuen,</it> from Anglo-French <it>rescure,</it> from <it>re-</it> + <it>escure</it> to shake off, from Latin <it>excutere,</it> from <it>ex-</it> + <it>quatere</it> to shake</et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>14th century</date><dt> :to free from confinement, danger, or evil :<sx>save</sx> <sx>deliver</sx>: as</dt>  <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to take (as a prisoner) forcibly from custody</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to recover (as a prize) by force</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to deliver (as a place under siege) by armed force </dt></def><uro><ure>res*cu*able</ure><sound><wav>rescue02.wav</wav><wpr>!res-(+)kyU-u-bul</wpr></sound> <pr>-ə-bəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><uro><ure>rescue</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><uro><ure>res*cu*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>rescue</sc> <sc>deliver</sc> <sc>redeem</sc> <sc>ransom</sc> <sc>reclaim</sc> <sc>save</sc> mean to set free from confinement or danger. <sc>rescue</sc> implies freeing from imminent danger by prompt or vigorous action <vi><it>rescued</it> the crew of a sinking ship</vi>. <sc>deliver</sc> implies release usually of a person from confinement, temptation, slavery, or suffering <vi><it>delivered</it> his people from bondage</vi>. <sc>redeem</sc> implies releasing from bondage or penalties by giving what is demanded or necessary <vi>job training designed to <it>redeem</it> school dropouts from chronic unemployment</vi>. <sc>ransom</sc> specifically applies to buying out of captivity <vi>tried to <it>ransom</it> the kidnap victim</vi>. <sc>reclaim</sc> suggests a bringing back to a former state or condition of someone or something abandoned or debased <vi><it>reclaimed</it> long-abandoned farms</vi>. <sc>save</sc> may replace any of the foregoing terms; it may further imply a preserving or maintaining for usefulness or continued existence <vi>an operation that <it>saved</it> my life</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="rescue mission"><ew>rescue mission</ew><subj>RC</subj><hw>rescue mission</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1902</date><dt>:a city religious mission seeking to convert and rehabilitate the down-and-out</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>