<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="secret[1]"><ew>secret</ew><subj>GV-5</subj><hw hindex="1">se*cret</hw><sound><wav>secret01.wav</wav><wpr>!sE-krut</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsē-krət</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French <it>secré, secret,</it> from Latin <it>secretus,</it> from past participle of <it>secernere</it> to separate, distinguish, from <it>se-</it> apart + <it>cernere</it> to sift <ma>secede, certain</ma></et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:kept from knowledge or view :<sx>hidden</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:marked by the habit of discretion :<sx>closemouthed</sx></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:working with hidden aims or methods :<sx>undercover</sx> <vi>a <it>secret</it> agent</vi></dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:not acknowledged :<sx>unavowed</sx> <vi>a <it>secret</it> bride</vi></dt>  <sn>e</sn> <dt>:conducted in secret <vi>a <it>secret</it> trial</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:remote from human frequentation or notice :<sx>secluded</sx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:revealed only to the initiated :<sx>esoteric</sx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:designed to elude observation or detection <vi>a <it>secret</it> panel</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:containing information whose unauthorized disclosure could endanger national security <dx>compare <dxt>confidential</dxt> <dxt>top secret</dxt></dx></dt></def><uro><ure>se*cret*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>secret</sc> <sc>covert</sc> <sc>stealthy</sc> <sc>furtive</sc> <sc>clandestine</sc> <sc>surreptitious</sc> <sc>underhanded</sc> mean done without attracting observation. <sc>secret</sc> implies concealment on any grounds for any motive <vi>met at a <it>secret</it> location</vi>. <sc>covert</sc> stresses the fact of not being open or declared <vi><it>covert</it> intelligence operations</vi>. <sc>stealthy</sc> suggests taking pains to avoid being seen or heard especially in some misdoing <vi>the <it>stealthy</it> step of a burglar</vi>. <sc>furtive</sc> implies a sly or cautious stealthiness <vi>lovers exchanging <it>furtive</it> glances</vi>. <sc>clandestine</sc> implies secrecy usually for an evil, illicit, or unauthorized purpose and often emphasizes the fear of being discovered <vi>a <it>clandestine</it> meeting of conspirators</vi>. <sc>surreptitious</sc> applies to action or behavior done secretly often with skillful avoidance of detection and in violation of custom, law, or authority <vi>the <it>surreptitious</it> stockpiling of weapons</vi>. <sc>underhanded</sc> stresses fraud or deception <vi>an <it>underhanded</it> trick</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="secret[2]"><ew>secret</ew><subj>RC-2</subj><hw hindex="2">secret</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:something kept hidden or unexplained :<sx>mystery</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:something kept from the knowledge of others or shared only confidentially with a few</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:a method, formula, or process used in an art or operation and divulged only to those of one's own company or craft :<sx>trade secret</sx></dt>  <sn>d</sn> <sin><spl>plural</spl></sin> <dt>:the practices or knowledge making up the shared discipline or culture of an esoteric society</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a prayer traditionally said inaudibly by the celebrant just before the preface of the mass</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:something taken to be a specific or key to a desired end <vi>the <it>secret</it> of longevity</vi></dt></def><dro><drp>in secret</drp> <def><dt>:in a private place or manner</dt></def></dro></entry>
	<entry id="secret ballot"><ew>secret ballot</ew><subj>GV</subj><hw>secret ballot</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1917</date><dt>:<sx>australian ballot</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="secret partner"><ew>secret partner</ew><subj>BZ</subj><hw>secret partner</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1844</date><dt>:a partner whose membership in a partnership is kept secret from the public</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="secret police"><ew>secret police</ew><subj>LW#GV</subj><hw>secret police</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1823</date><dt>:a police organization operating for the most part in secrecy and especially for the political purposes of its government often with terroristic methods</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="secret service"><ew>secret service</ew><subj>LW#GV</subj><hw>secret service</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1706</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a governmental service of a secret nature</dt> <sn>2</sn> <slb>capitalized both Ss</slb> <dt>:a division of the United States Treasury Department charged chiefly with the suppression of counterfeiting and the protection of the president</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="secret society"><ew>secret society</ew><subj>OR</subj><hw>secret society</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1821</date><dt>:any of various oath-bound societies often devoted to brotherhood, moral discipline, and mutual assistance</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="open secret"><ew>open secret</ew><hw>open secret</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1828</date><dt>:a supposedly secret but generally known matter</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="top secret"><ew>top secret</ew><subj>GV-2</subj><hw>top secret</hw><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1944</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:protected by a high degree of secrecy <vi>a <it>top secret</it> weapon</vi> <vi>a <it>top secret</it> meeting</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:containing or being information whose unauthorized disclosure could result in exceptionally grave danger to the nation <vi><it>top secret</it> messages</vi> <dx>compare <dxt>confidential</dxt> <dxt>secret</dxt></dx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:of or relating to top secret documents <vi>a <it>top secret</it> clearance</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="trade secret"><ew>trade secret</ew><subj>BZ</subj><hw>trade secret</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1862</date><dt>:something (as a formula) which has economic value to a business because it is not generally known or easily discoverable by observation and for which efforts have been made to maintain secrecy</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>