<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="shall"><ew>shall</ew><hw>shall</hw><sound><wav>shall001.wav</wav><wpr>!shal</wpr></sound><pr>shəl, ˈshal</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><il>past</il> <if>should</if><sound><wav>shall002.wav</wav><wpr>!sh2d</wpr></sound> <pr>shəd, ˈshu̇d</pr></in><in><il>present singular &amp; plural</il> <if>shall</if></in><et>Middle English <it>shal</it> (1st &amp; 3d singular present indicative), from Old English <it>sceal;</it> akin to Old High German <it>scal</it> (1st &amp; 3d singular present indicative) ought to, must, Lithuanian <it>skola</it> debt</et><def><vt>verbal auxiliary</vt><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl>  <sn>a</sn> <dt>:will have to :<sx>must</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:will be able to :<sx>can</sx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt><un>used to express a command or exhortation <vi>you <it>shall</it> go</vi></un></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used in laws, regulations, or directives to express what is mandatory <vi>it <it>shall</it> be unlawful to carry firearms</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt><un>used to express what is inevitable or seems likely to happen in the future <vi>we <it>shall</it> have to be ready</vi> <vi>we <it>shall</it> see</vi></un></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used to express simple futurity <vi>when <it>shall</it> we expect you</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used to express determination <vi>they <it>shall</it> not pass</vi></un></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt><ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:will go <vi>he to England <it>shall</it> along with you <aq>Shakespeare</aq></vi></dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt>From the reams of pronouncements written about the distinction between <it>shall</it> and <it>will</it>—dating back as far as the 17th century—it is clear that the rules laid down have never very accurately reflected actual usage. The nationalistic statements of 18th and 19th century British grammarians, who commonly cited the misuses of the Irish, the Scots, and occasionally the Americans, suggest that the traditional rules may have come closest to the usage of southern England. Some modern commentators believe that English usage is still the closest to the traditionally prescribed norms. Most modern commentators allow that <it>will</it> is more common in nearly all uses. The entries for <it>shall</it> and <it>will</it> in this dictionary show current usage.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="shalt"><ew>shalt</ew><hw>shalt</hw><sound><wav>shalt001.wav</wav><wpr>!shalt</wpr></sound><pr>shəlt, ˈshalt</pr><cx><cl>archaic present 2d singular of</cl> <ct>shall</ct></cx></entry>
	<entry id="should"><ew>should</ew><hw>should</hw><sound><wav>should01.wav</wav><wpr>!sh2d</wpr></sound><pr>shəd, ˈshu̇d</pr><fl>verbal auxiliary</fl><cx><cl>past of</cl> <ct>shall</ct></cx><et>Middle English <it>sholde,</it> from Old English <it>sceolde</it> owed, was obliged to, ought to</et><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used in auxiliary function to express condition <vi>if he <it>should</it> leave his father, his father would die <aq>Genesis 44:22(Revised Standard Version)</aq></vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt><un>used in auxiliary function to express obligation, propriety, or expediency <vi>'tis commanded I <it>should</it> do so <aq>Shakespeare</aq></vi> <vi>this is as it <it>should</it> be <aq>H. L. Savage</aq></vi> <vi>you <it>should</it> brush your teeth after each meal</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used in auxiliary function to express futurity from a point of view in the past <vi>realized that she <it>should</it> have to do most of her farm work before sunrise <aq>Ellen Glasgow</aq></vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt><un>used in auxiliary function to express what is probable or expected <vi>with an early start, they <it>should</it> be here by noon</vi></un></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt><un>used in auxiliary function to express a request in a polite manner or to soften direct statement <vi>I <it>should</it> suggest that a guide … is the first essential <aq>L. D. Reddick</aq></vi></un></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="shouldest"><ew>shouldest</ew><hw>should*est</hw><sound><wav>should05.wav</wav><wpr>!sh2-dust</wpr></sound><pr>ˈshu̇-dəst</pr><cx><cl>archaic past 2d singular of</cl> <ct>shall</ct></cx></entry>
	<entry id="shouldst"><ew>shouldst</ew><hw>shouldst</hw><sound><wav>should07.wav</wav><wpr>!sh2dst</wpr></sound><pr>shədst, ˈshu̇dst, shətst, ˈshu̇tst</pr><cx><cl>archaic past 2d singular of</cl> <ct>shall</ct></cx></entry>
</entry_list>