<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="share[1]"><ew>share</ew><subj>AG</subj><hw hindex="1">share</hw><sound><wav>share001.wav</wav><wpr>!shar</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsher</pr><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English <it>schare,</it> from Old English <it>scear;</it> akin to Old High German <it>scaro</it> plowshare, Old English <it>scieran</it> to cut <ma>shear</ma></et><def><date>before 12th century</date><dt>:<sx>plowshare</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="share[2]"><ew>share</ew><subj>EC-2</subj><hw hindex="2">share</hw><fl>noun</fl><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>scearu</it> cutting, tonsure; akin to Old English <it>scieran</it> to cut</et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a portion belonging to, due to, or contributed by an individual or group</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:one's full or fair portion <vi>has had his <it>share</it> of bad luck</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:the part allotted or belonging to one of a number owning together property or interest</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:any of the equal portions into which property or invested capital is divided</dt> <sd>specifically</sd> <dt>:any of the equal interests or rights into which the entire stock of a corporation is divided and ownership of which is regularly evidenced by one or more certificates</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <sin><spl>plural</spl></sin> <ssl>chiefly British</ssl> <dt>:<sx>stock <sxn>7c(1)</sxn></sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="share[3]"><ew>share</ew><hw hindex="3">share</hw><fl>verb</fl><in><if>shared</if></in><in><if>shar*ing</if></in><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>1590</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to divide and distribute in <fw>shares</fw> :<sx>apportion</sx> <un>usually used with <it>out</it> <vi><it>shared</it> out the land among his heirs</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to partake of, use, experience, occupy, or enjoy with others</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to have in common <vi>they <it>share</it> a passion for opera</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to grant or give a share in <un>often used with <it>with</it> <vi><it>shared</it> the last of her water with us</vi></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to tell (as thoughts, feelings, or experiences) to others <un>often used with <it>with</it></un></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to have a share <un>used with <it>in</it> <vi>we all <it>shared</it> in the fruits of our labor</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to apportion and take shares of something</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to talk about one's thoughts, feelings, or experiences with others</dt></def><uro><ure>shar*er</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>share</sc> <sc>participate</sc> <sc>partake</sc> mean to have, get, or use in common with another or others. <sc>share</sc> usually implies that one as the original holder grants to another the partial use, enjoyment, or possession of a thing <vi><it>shared</it> my toys with the others</vi>. <sc>participate</sc> implies a having or taking part in an undertaking, activity, or discussion <vi><it>participated</it> in sports</vi>. <sc>partake</sc> implies accepting or acquiring a share especially of food or drink <vi><it>partook</it> freely of the refreshments</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="lion's share"><ew>lion's share</ew><hw>lion's share</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1742</date><dt>:the largest portion <vi>received the <it>lion's share</it> of the research money</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="market share"><ew>market share</ew><subj>BZ</subj><hw>market share</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1954</date><dt>:the percentage of the market for a product or service that a company supplies</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="ordinary share"><ew>ordinary share</ew><subj>EC</subj><hw>ordinary share</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1891</date><sl>British</sl><dt>:a share of common stock</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="time-sharing"><ew>time-sharing</ew><subj>CP-1#EC-2</subj><hw>time–shar*ing</hw><sound><wav>timesh01.wav</wav><wpr>!tIm-+shar-iN</wpr></sound><pr>ˈtīm-ˌsher-iŋ</pr><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1953</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:simultaneous use of a central computer by many users at remote locations</dt> <sn>2</sn> <svr><vl>or</vl> <va>time–share</va> <sound><wav>timesh02.wav</wav><wpr>!tIm-+shar</wpr></sound> <pr>-ˌsher</pr></svr> <dt>:joint ownership or rental of a vacation lodging (as a condominium) by several persons with each occupying the premises in turn for short periods</dt></def><uro><ure>time–share</ure> <fl>transitive verb</fl></uro></entry>
</entry_list>