<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="some[1]"><ew>some</ew><subj>LG-4</subj><hw hindex="1">some</hw><sound><wav>some0001.wav</wav><wpr>!sum</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsəm, <it>for 2 without stress</it></pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English <it>som,</it> adjective &amp; pron., from Old English <it>sum;</it> akin to Old High German <it>sum</it> some, Greek <it>hamē</it> somehow, <it>homos</it> same <ma>same</ma></et><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:being an unknown, undetermined, or unspecified unit or thing <vi><it>some</it> person knocked</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:being one, a part, or an unspecified number of <fw>something</fw> (as a class or group) named or implied <vi><it>some</it> gems are hard</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:being of an unspecified amount or number <vi>give me <it>some</it> water</vi> <vi>have <it>some</it> apples</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:<sx>remarkable</sx> <sx>striking</sx> <vi>that was <it>some</it> party</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:being at least one <un>used to indicate that a logical proposition is asserted only of a subclass or certain members of the class denoted by the term which it modifies</un></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="some[2]"><ew>some</ew><hw hindex="2">some</hw><sound><wav>some0001.wav</wav><wpr>!sum</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsəm</pr><fl>pronoun, singular or plural in construction</fl><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:one indeterminate quantity, portion, or number as distinguished from the rest</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:an indefinite additional amount <vi>ran a mile and then <it>some</it></vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="some[3]"><ew>some</ew><hw hindex="3">some</hw><sound><wav>some0001.wav</wav><wpr>!sum</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsəm, ˌsəm</pr><fl>adverb</fl><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>about</sx> <vi><it>some</it> 80 houses</vi> <vi>twenty-<it>some</it> people</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:in some degree :<sx>somewhat</sx> <vi>felt <it>some</it> better</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to some degree or extent :a little <vi>the cut bled <it>some</it></vi> <vi>I need to work on it <it>some</it> more</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt><un>used as a mild intensive <vi>that's going <it>some</it></vi></un></dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt>When <it>some</it> is used to modify a number, it is almost always a round number <vi>a community of <it>some</it> 150,000 inhabitants</vi> but because <it>some</it> is slightly more emphatic than <it>about</it> or <it>approximately</it> it is occasionally used with a more exact number in an intensive function <vi>an expert parachutist, he has <it>some</it> 115 jumps to his credit <aq><it>Current Biography</it></aq></vi>. When <it>some</it> is used without a number, most commentators feel that <it>somewhat</it> is to be preferred. Their advice is an oversimplification, however; only when <it>some</it> modifies an adjective, usually a comparative, will <it>somewhat</it> always substitute smoothly. When <it>some</it> modifies a verb or adverb, and especially when it follows a verb, substitution of <it>somewhat</it> may prove awkward <vi>Italy forced me to grow up <it>some</it> <aq>E. W. Brooke</aq></vi> <vi>I'm not a prude; I've been around <it>some</it> in my day <aq>Roy Rogers</aq></vi> <vi>here in Newport, both Southern Cross and Courageous practiced <it>some</it> more <aq>W. N. Wallace</aq></vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="-some[1]"><ew>-some</ew><hw hindex="1">-some</hw><fl>adjective suffix</fl><et>Middle English <it>-som,</it> from Old English <it>-sum;</it> akin to Old High German <it>-sam</it> -some, Old English <it>sum</it> some</et><def><dt>:characterized by a (specified) thing, quality, state, or action <vi>awe<it>some</it></vi> <vi>burden<it>some</it></vi> <vi>cuddle<it>some</it></vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="-some[2]"><ew>-some</ew><subj>NB</subj><hw hindex="2">-some</hw><fl>noun suffix</fl><et>Middle English (northern dialect) <it>-sum,</it> from Middle English <it>sum,</it> pron., one, some</et><def><dt>:group of (so many) members and especially persons <vi>four<it>some</it></vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="-some[3]"><ew>-some</ew><subj>BI#GN#CB</subj><hw hindex="3">-some</hw><fl>noun combining form</fl><et>New Latin <it>-somat-, -soma,</it> from Greek <it>sōmat-, sōma</it></et><def> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:body <vi>chromo<it>some</it></vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:chromosome <vi>mono<it>some</it></vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="then[1]"><ew>then</ew><hw hindex="1">then</hw><sound><wav>then0001.wav</wav><wpr>!Den</wpr></sound><pr>ˈt͟hen</pr><fl>adverb</fl><et>Middle English <it>than, then</it> then, than, from Old English <it>thonne, thænne;</it> akin to Old High German <it>denne</it> then, than, Old English <it>thæt</it> that</et><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:at that time</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:soon after that :next in order of time <vi>walked to the door, <it>then</it> turned</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:following next after in order of position, narration, or enumeration :being next in a series <vi>first came the clowns, and <it>then</it> came the elephants</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:in addition :<sx>besides</sx> <vi><it>then</it> there is the interest to be paid</vi></dt> <sn>3 a <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:in that case <vi>take it, <it>then</it>, if you want it so much</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt><un>used after <it>but</it> to qualify or offset a preceding statement <vi>she lost the race, but <it>then</it> she never really expected to win</vi></un></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:according to that :as may be inferred <vi>your mind is made up, <it>then</it></vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:as it appears :by way of summing up <vi>the cause of the accident, <it>then</it>, is established</vi></dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:as a necessary consequence <vi>if the angles are equal, <it>then</it> the complements are equal</vi></dt></def><dro><drp>and then some</drp> <def><dt>:with much more in addition <vi>would require all his strength <it>and then some</it></vi></dt></def></dro></entry>
</entry_list>