<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="split[1]"><ew>split</ew><subj>PY-vt2a(2)#GV-3c#EC-3e#CH-vt3d</subj><hw hindex="1">split</hw><sound><wav>split001.wav</wav><wpr>!split</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsplit</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>split</if></in><in><if>split*ting</if></in><et>Dutch <it>splitten,</it> from Middle Dutch; akin to Middle High German <it>splīzen</it> to split and probably to Old High German <it>spaltan</it> to split</et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>1567</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to divide lengthwise usually along a grain or seam or by layers</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to affect as if by cleaving or forcing apart <vi>the river <it>split</it><it>s</it> the town in two</vi></dt> <sn>2 a <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:to tear or rend apart :<sx>burst</sx></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:to subject (an atom or atomic nucleus) to artificial disintegration by fission</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to affect as if by breaking up or tearing apart :<sx>shatter</sx> <vi>a roar that <it>split</it> the air</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt> :to divide into parts or portions: as</dt>  <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to divide between persons :<sx>share</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to divide into factions, parties, or groups</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to mark (a ballot) or cast or register (a vote) so as to vote for candidates of different parties</dt>  <sn>d <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:to divide or break down (a chemical compound) into constituents <vi><it>split</it> a fat into glycerol and fatty acids</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:to remove by such separation <vi><it>split</it> off carbon dioxide</vi></dt>  <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to divide (stock) by issuing a larger number of shares to existing shareholders usually without increase in total par value </dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to separate (the parts of a whole) by interposing something <vi><it>split</it> an infinitive</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:<sx>leave</sx> <vi><it>split</it> the party</vi> <vi><it>split</it> town</vi></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to become split lengthwise or into layers</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to break apart :<sx>burst</sx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to become divided up or separated off <vi><it>split</it> into factions</vi> <vi><it>split</it> from the group</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to sever relations or connections :<sx>separate</sx></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:<sx>leave</sx></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:to leave without delay <vi><it>split</it> for the coast</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <ssl>British</ssl> <dt>:to betray confidence :act as an informer <un>usually used with <it>on</it></un></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to apportion shares</dt><ss>tear</ss></def><dro><drp>split hairs</drp> <def><dt>:to make oversubtle or trivial distinctions</dt></def></dro><dro><drp>split one's sides</drp> <def><dt>:to laugh heartily</dt></def></dro><dro><drp>split the difference</drp> <def><dt>:to arrive at a compromise</dt></def></dro></entry>
	<entry id="split[2]"><ew>split</ew><subj>GN-3#AH-3</subj><hw hindex="2">split</hw><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1593</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>divided</sx> <sx>fractured</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:prepared for use by <fw>splitting</fw> <vi><it>split</it> bamboo</vi> <vi><it>split</it> hides</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:<sx>heterozygous</sx> <un>used especially by breeders of cage birds sometimes with <it>for</it></un></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="split[3]"><ew>split</ew><subj>SP-1b#EC-4a#DA-4b#SG-4b#AL-6#FD-7#SR-8</subj><hw hindex="3">split</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1597</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:a narrow break made by or as if by <fw>splitting</fw></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an arrangement of bowling pins left standing with space for pins between them</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a piece split off or made thin by splitting</dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:a division into or between divergent or antagonistic elements or forces <vi>a cultural <it>split</it></vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:a faction formed in this way</dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:the act or process of splitting (as the stock of a corporation)</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the act of lowering oneself to the floor or leaping into the air with legs extended at right angles to the trunk</dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:a product of division by or as if by splitting</dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:a wine bottle holding one quarter the usual amount or about .1875 liters (6 to 6.5 ounces)</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:the quantity held by a split</dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:an ice cream sundae served over slices of fruit (as banana)</dt> <sn>8</sn> <dt>:the recorded time at or for a specific part of a race</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="Split"><ew>Split</ew><hw>Split</hw><sound><wav>ggspli01.wav</wav></sound><pr>ˈsplit</pr><fl>geographical name</fl><def><dt>city &amp; port <g>S</g> Croatia on Dalmatian coast <it>pop</it> 200,459</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="split-brain"><ew>split-brain</ew><subj>MD</subj><hw>split–brain</hw><sound><wav>splitb01.wav</wav><wpr>!split-!brAn</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsplit-ˈbrān</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1958</date><dt>:having the optic chiasma and corpus callosum severed <vi>behavior in <it>split–brain</it> animals</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="split decision"><ew>split decision</ew><subj>SM</subj><hw>split decision</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1952</date><dt>:a decision in a boxing match reflecting a division of opinion among the referee and judges</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="split end"><ew>split end</ew><subj>SF-1#FH-2</subj><hw>split end</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1955</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:an offensive football end who lines up usually several yards to the side of the formation</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a hair tip that has become frayed (as from dryness) <un>usually used in plural</un></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="split-fingered fastball"><ew>split-fingered fastball</ew><subj>SB</subj><hw>split–fingered fastball</hw><sound><wav>splitf01.wav</wav><wpr>!split-!fiN-gurd-!fas(t)-+bol</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsplit-ˈfiŋ-gərd-</pr><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1979</date><dt>:a fastball thrown with the ball gripped as for a forkball so that it drops rapidly as it nears the plate <ca>called also <cat>split-finger</cat> <cat>splitter</cat></ca></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="split infinitive"><ew>split infinitive</ew><subj>GR</subj><hw>split infinitive</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1897</date><dt>:an infinitive with <it>to</it> having a modifier between the <it>to</it> and the verbal (as in “to really start”)</dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt>The split infinitive was discovered and named in the 19th century. 19th century writers seem to have made greater use of this construction than earlier writers; the frequency of occurrence attracted the disapproving attention of grammarians, many of whom thought it to be a modern corruption. The construction had in fact been in occasional use since the 14th century; only its frequency had changed. Even though there has never been a rational basis for objecting to the split infinitive, the subject has become a fixture of folk belief about grammar. You can hardly publish a sentence containing one without hearing about it from somebody. Modern commentators know the split infinitive is not a vice, but they are loath to drop such a popular subject. They usually say it's all right to split an infinitive in the interest of clarity. Since clarity is the usual reason for splitting, this advice means merely that you can split them whenever you need to.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="split-level"><ew>split-level</ew><subj>AC</subj><hw>split–lev*el</hw><sound><wav>splitl01.wav</wav><wpr>!split-!le-vul</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsplit-ˈle-vəl</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1946</date><dt>:divided vertically so that the floor level of rooms in one part is approximately midway between the levels of two successive stories in an adjoining part <vi>a <it>split–level</it> house</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>split–lev*el</ure><sound><wav>splitl02.wav</wav><wpr>!split-+le-vul</wpr></sound> <pr>-ˌle-vəl</pr> <fl>noun</fl></uro></entry>
</entry_list>