<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="strange[1]"><ew>strange</ew><subj>PY-5</subj><hw hindex="1">strange</hw><sound><wav>strang01.wav</wav><wpr>!strAnj</wpr></sound><pr>ˈstrānj</pr><fl>adjective</fl><in><if>strang*er</if></in><in><if>strang*est</if></in><et>Middle English, from Anglo-French <it>estrange,</it> from Latin <it>extraneus,</it> literally, external, from <it>extra</it> outside <ma>extra-</ma></et><def><date>13th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:of, relating to, or characteristic of another country :<sx>foreign</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not native to or naturally belonging in a place :of external origin, kind, or character</dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:not before known, heard, or seen :<sx>unfamiliar</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:exciting wonder or awe :<sx>extraordinary</sx></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:discouraging familiarities :<sx>reserved</sx> <sx>distant</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>ill at ease</sx></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:<sx>unaccustomed <sxn>2</sxn></sx> <vi>she was <it>strange</it> to his ways</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>strange*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>strange</sc> <sc>singular</sc> <sc>unique</sc> <sc>peculiar</sc> <sc>eccentric</sc> <sc>erratic</sc> <sc>odd</sc> <sc>quaint</sc> <sc>outlandish</sc> mean departing from what is ordinary, usual, or to be expected. <sc>strange</sc> stresses unfamiliarity and may apply to the foreign, the unnatural, the unaccountable <vi>a journey filled with <it>strange</it> sights</vi>. <sc>singular</sc> suggests individuality or puzzling strangeness <vi>a <it>singular</it> feeling of impending disaster</vi>. <sc>unique</sc> implies singularity and the fact of being without a known parallel <vi>a career <it>unique</it> in the annals of science</vi>. <sc>peculiar</sc> implies a marked distinctiveness <vi>the <it>peculiar</it> status of America's first lady</vi>. <sc>eccentric</sc> suggests a wide divergence from the usual or normal especially in behavior <vi>the <it>eccentric</it> eating habits of preschoolers</vi>. <sc>erratic</sc> stresses a capricious and unpredictable wandering or deviating <vi>a friend's suddenly <it>erratic</it> behavior</vi>. <sc>odd</sc> applies to a departure from the regular or expected <vi>an <it>odd</it> sense of humor</vi>. <sc>quaint</sc> suggests an old-fashioned but pleasant oddness <vi>a <it>quaint</it> fishing village</vi>. <sc>outlandish</sc> applies to what is uncouth, bizarre, or barbaric <vi><it>outlandish</it> fashions of the time</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="strange[2]"><ew>strange</ew><subj>PY</subj><hw hindex="2">strange</hw><fl>noun</fl><lb>often attributive</lb><def><date>1974</date><dt>:a fundamental quark that has an electric charge of −<frac>1/3</frac> and a measured energy of approximately 150 MeV</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:the flavor characterizing this particle</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="strange woman"><ew>strange woman</ew><hw>strange woman</hw><fl>noun</fl><et>from the expression frequently used in Provençal (Authorized Version)</et><def><date>1535</date><dt>:<sx>prostitute</sx></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>