<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="sure[1]"><ew>sure</ew><hw hindex="1">sure</hw><sound><wav>sure0001.wav</wav><wpr>!sh2r</wpr></sound><pr>ˈshu̇r, <it>especially Southern</it> ˈshȯr</pr><fl>adjective</fl><in><if>sur*er</if></in><in><if>sur*est</if></in><et>Middle English <it>seur, sure,</it> from Anglo-French <it>seur,</it> from Latin <it>securus</it> secure</et><def><date>13th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>obsolete</ssl> <dt>:safe from danger or harm</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:firmly established :<sx>steadfast</sx> <vi>a <it>sure</it> hold</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:<sx>reliable</sx> <sx>trustworthy</sx> <vi>a <it>sure</it> friend</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:marked by or given to feelings of confident certainty <vi>I'm <it>sure</it> I'm right</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:characterized by a lack of wavering or hesitation <vi><it>sure</it> brush strokes</vi> <vi>a <it>sure</it> hand</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:admitting of no doubt :<sx>indisputable</sx> <vi>spoke from <it>sure</it> knowledge</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:bound to happen :<sx>inevitable</sx> <vi><it>sure</it> disaster</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>bound</sx> <sx>destined</sx> <vi>is <it>sure</it> to win</vi></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:careful to remember, attend to, or find out something <vi>be <it>sure</it> to lock the door</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>sure*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><dro><drp>for sure</drp> <def><dt>:without doubt or question :<sx>certainly</sx></dt></def></dro><dro><drp>to be sure</drp> <def><dt>:it must be acknowledged :<sx>admittedly</sx></dt></def></dro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>sure</sc> <sc>certain</sc> <sc>positive</sc> <sc>cocksure</sc> mean having no doubt or uncertainty. <sc>sure</sc> usually stresses the subjective or intuitive feeling of assurance <vi>felt <it>sure</it> that I had forgotten something</vi>. <sc>certain</sc> may apply to a basing of a conclusion or conviction on definite grounds or indubitable evidence <vi>police are <it>certain</it> about the cause of the fire</vi>. <sc>positive</sc> intensifies sureness or certainty and may imply opinionated conviction or forceful expression of it <vi>I'm <it>positive</it> that's the person I saw</vi>. <sc>cocksure</sc> implies presumptuous or careless positiveness <vi>you're always so <it>cocksure</it> about everything</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="sure[2]"><ew>sure</ew><hw hindex="2">sure</hw><fl>adverb</fl><def><date>14th century</date><dt>:<sx>surely</sx></dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt>Most commentators consider the adverb <it>sure</it> to be something less than completely standard; <it>surely</it> is usually recommended as a substitute. Our current evidence shows, however, that <it>sure</it> and <it>surely</it> have become differentiated in use. <it>Sure</it> is used in much more informal contexts than <it>surely.</it> It is used as a simple intensive <vi>I can never know how much I bored her, but, be certain, she <it>sure</it> amused me <aq>Norman Mailer</aq></vi> and, because it connotes strong affirmation, it is used when the speaker or writer expects to be agreed with <vi>it's a moot point whether politicians are less venal than in Twain's day. But they're <it>sure</it> as the devil more intrusive <aq>Alan Abelson</aq></vi> <vi>he <it>sure</it> gets them to play <aq>D. S. Looney</aq></vi>. <it>Surely,</it> like <it>sure,</it> is used as a simple intensive <vi>I <it>surely</it> don't want to leave the impression that I had an unhappy childhood <aq>E. C. Welsh</aq></vi> but it occurs in more formal contexts than <it>sure.</it> Unlike <it>sure</it> it may be used neutrally—the reader or hearer may or may not agree <vi>it would <it>surely</it> be possible, within a few years, to program a computer to construct a grammar <aq>Noam Chomsky</aq></vi> and it is often used when the writer is trying to persuade <vi><it>surely</it> a book on the avant-garde cannot be so conventional <aq>Karl Shapiro</aq></vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="sure enough"><ew>sure enough</ew><hw>sure enough</hw><fl>adverb</fl><def><date>circa 1545</date><dt>:as one might expect :<sx>certainly</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="sure-enough"><ew>sure-enough</ew><hw>sure–enough</hw><sound><wav>sureen01.wav</wav><wpr>!sh2r-u-!nuf</wpr></sound><pr>ˈshu̇r-ə-ˈnəf</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>circa 1846</date><dt>:<sx>actual</sx> <sx>genuine</sx> <sx>real</sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="sure-footed"><ew>sure-footed</ew><hw>sure–foot*ed</hw><sound><wav>surefo01.wav</wav><wpr>!sh2r-!f2-tud</wpr></sound><pr>-ˈfu̇-təd</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1633</date><dt>:not liable to stumble, fall, or err</dt></def><uro><ure>sure–foot*ed*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><uro><ure>sure–foot*ed*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="sure-handed"><ew>sure-handed</ew><hw>sure–hand*ed</hw><sound><wav>sureha01.wav</wav><wpr>!sh2r-!han-dud</wpr></sound><pr>-ˈhan-dəd</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1930</date><dt>:proficient and confident in performance especially using the hands</dt></def><uro><ure>sure–hand*ed*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="sure thing"><ew>sure thing</ew><hw>sure thing</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1767</date><dt>:one that is certain to succeed :a sure bet</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>