<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="than[1]"><ew>than</ew><hw hindex="1">than</hw><sound><wav>than0001.wav</wav><wpr>!Dan</wpr></sound><pr>t͟hən, ˈt͟han</pr><fl>conjunction</fl><et>Middle English <it>than, then</it> then, than <ma>then</ma></et><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to indicate the second member or the member taken as the point of departure in a comparison expressive of inequality</un> <un>used with comparative adjectives and comparative adverbs <vi>older <it>than</it> I am</vi> <vi>easier said <it>than</it> done</vi></un></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to indicate difference of kind, manner, or identity</un> <un>used especially with some adjectives and adverbs that express diversity <vi>anywhere else <it>than</it> at home</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:rather than <un>usually used only after <it>prefer, preferable,</it> and <it>preferably</it></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:other than</dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:<sx>when <sxn>1b</sxn></sx> <un>used especially after <it>scarcely</it> and <it>hardly</it></un></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="than[2]"><ew>than</ew><hw hindex="2">than</hw><fl>preposition</fl><def><date>1560</date><dt>:in comparison with <vi>you are older <it>than</it> me</vi></dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt>After 200 years of innocent if occasional use, the preposition <it>than</it> was called into question by 18th century grammarians. Some 200 years of elaborate reasoning have led to these present-day inconsistent conclusions: <it>than whom</it> is standard but clumsy <vi>T. S. Eliot, <it>than</it> whom nobody could have been more insularly English <aq>Anthony Burgess</aq></vi>; <it>than me</it> may be acceptable in speech <vi>a man no mightier <it>than</it> thyself or me <aq>Shakespeare</aq></vi> <vi>why should a man be better <it>than</it> me because he's richer <it>than</it> me <aq>William Faulkner, in a talk to students</aq></vi>; <it>than</it> followed by a third-person objective pronoun (<it>her, him, them</it>) is usually frowned upon. Surveyed opinion tends to agree with these conclusions. Our evidence shows that <it>than</it> is used as a conjunction more commonly than as a preposition, that <it>than whom</it> is chiefly limited to writing, and that <it>me</it> is more common after the preposition than the third-person objective pronouns. In short, you can use <it>than</it> either as a conjunction or as a preposition.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="other than[1]"><ew>other than</ew><hw hindex="1">other than</hw><fl>preposition</fl><def><date>14th century</date><dt>:with the exception of :<sx>except for</sx> <sx>besides</sx> <vi><it>other than</it> that, nothing happened</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="other than[2]"><ew>other than</ew><hw hindex="2">other than</hw><fl>conjunction</fl><def><date>1605</date><dt>:<sx>except</sx> <sx>but</sx> <vi>cannot be changed <it>other than</it> by judicial order</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="rather than[1]"><ew>rather than</ew><hw hindex="1">rather than</hw><fl>conjunction</fl><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used with the infinitive form of a verb to indicate negation as a contrary choice or wish <vi><it>rather than</it> continue the argument, he walked away</vi> <vi>chose to sing <it>rather than</it> play violin</vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:and not <vi>obscures <it>rather than</it> resolves the problem</vi> <vi>why do one thing <it>rather than</it> another?</vi> <vi>happy <it>rather than</it> sad</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="rather than[2]"><ew>rather than</ew><hw hindex="2">rather than</hw><fl>preposition</fl><def><date>1595</date><dt>:<sx>instead of</sx> <vi><it>rather than</it> being pleased, she was angry</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="less[2]"><ew>less</ew><hw hindex="2">less</hw><fl>adverb</fl><cx><cl>comparative of</cl> <ct>little</ct></cx><def><date>before 12th century</date><dt>:to a <fw>lesser</fw> extent or degree</dt></def><dro><drp>less and less</drp> <def><dt>:to a progressively smaller size or extent</dt></def></dro><dro><drp>less than</drp> <def><dt>:by no means :not at all <vi><it>less than</it> honest in his replies</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>
</entry_list>