<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="that[1]"><ew>that</ew><hw hindex="1">that</hw><sound><wav>that0001.wav</wav><wpr>!Dat</wpr></sound><pr>ˈt͟hat, t͟hət</pr><fl>pronoun</fl><in><il>plural</il> <if>those</if><sound><wav>that0002.wav</wav><wpr>!DOz</wpr></sound> <pr>ˈt͟hōz</pr></in><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>thæt,</it> neuter demonstrative pron. &amp; definite article; akin to Old High German <it>daz,</it> neuter demonstrative pron. &amp; definite article, Greek <it>to,</it> Latin is<it>tud,</it> neuter demonstrative pron.</et><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:the person, thing, or idea indicated, mentioned, or understood from the situation <vi><it>that</it> is my father</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the time, action, or event specified <vi>after <it>that</it> I went to bed</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:the kind or thing specified as follows <vi>the purest water is <it>that</it> produced by distillation</vi></dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:one or a group of the indicated kind <vi><it>that</it>'<it>s</it> a cat — quick and agile</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:the one farther away or less immediately under observation or discussion <vi><it>those</it> are maples and these are elms</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:the former one</dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt><un>used as a function word after <it>and</it> to indicate emphatic repetition of the idea expressed by a previous word or phrase <vi>he was helpful, and <it>that</it> to an unusual degree</vi></un></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used as a function word immediately before or after a word group consisting of a verbal auxiliary or a form of the verb <it>be</it> preceded by <it>there</it> or a personal pronoun subject to indicate emphatic repetition of the idea expressed by a previous verb or predicate noun or predicate adjective <vi>is she capable? She is <it>that</it></vi></un></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:the one :the thing :the kind :<sx>something</sx> <sx>anything</sx> <vi>the truth of <it>that</it> which is true</vi> <vi>the senses are <it>that</it> whereby we experience the world</vi> <vi>what's <it>that</it> you say</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <sin><spl>plural</spl></sin> <dt>:some persons <vi><it>those</it> who think the time has come</vi></dt></def><dro><drp>all that</drp> <def><dt>:everything of the kind indicated <vi>tact, discretion, and <it>all that</it></vi></dt></def></dro><dro><drp>at that</drp> <def> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:in spite of what has been said or implied</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:in addition :<sx>besides</sx></dt></def></dro></entry>
	<entry id="that[2]"><ew>that</ew><hw hindex="2">that</hw><sound><wav>that0003.wav</wav><wpr>!Dat</wpr></sound><pr>t͟hət, ˈt͟hat</pr><fl>conjunction</fl><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1 a <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to introduce a noun clause that is usually the subject or object of a verb or a predicate nominative <vi>said <it>that</it> he was afraid</vi></un></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to introduce a subordinate clause that is anticipated by the expletive <it>it</it> occurring as subject of the verb <vi>it is unlikely <it>that</it> he'll be in</vi></un></dt>  <sn><snp>(3)</snp></sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to introduce a subordinate clause that is joined as complement to a noun or adjective <vi>we are certain <it>that</it> this is true</vi> <vi>the fact <it>that</it> you are here</vi></un></dt>  <sn><snp>(4)</snp></sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to introduce a subordinate clause modifying an adverb or adverbial expression <vi>will go anywhere <it>that</it> he is invited</vi></un></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to introduce an exclamatory clause expressing a strong emotion especially of surprise, sorrow, or indignation <vi><it>that</it> it should come to this!</vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to introduce a subordinate clause expressing purpose or desired result <vi>cutting down expenses <it>that</it> her son might inherit an unencumbered estate <aq>W. B. Yeats</aq></vi></un></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to introduce a subordinate clause expressing a reason or cause <vi>rejoice <it>that</it> you are lightened of a load <aq>Robert Browning</aq></vi></un></dt>  <sn><snp>(3)</snp></sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to introduce a subordinate clause expressing consequence, result, or effect <vi>are of sufficient importance <it>that</it> they cannot be neglected <aq>Hannah Wormington</aq></vi></un></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to introduce an exclamatory clause expressing a wish <vi>oh, <it>that</it> he would come</vi></un></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used as a function word after a subordinating conjunction without modifying its meaning <vi>if <it>that</it> thy bent of love be honorable <aq>Shakespeare</aq></vi></un></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="that[3]"><ew>that</ew><hw hindex="3">that</hw><fl>adjective</fl><in><il>plural</il> <if>those</if></in><def><date>12th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:being the person, thing, or idea specified, mentioned, or understood</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:being the one specified <un>usually used for emphasis <vi><it>that</it> rarity among leaders</vi> <vi><it>that</it> brother of yours</vi></un></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:so great a :<sx>such</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the farther away or less immediately under observation or discussion <vi>this chair or <it>that</it> one</vi></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="that[4]"><ew>that</ew><hw hindex="4">that</hw><sound><wav>that0004.wav</wav><wpr>!Dat</wpr></sound><pr>t͟hət, ˈt͟hat</pr><fl>pronoun</fl><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>thæt,</it> neuter relative pron., from <it>thæt,</it> neuter demonstrative pron.</et><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to introduce a restrictive relative clause and to serve as a substitute within that clause for the substantive modified by the clause <vi>the house <it>that</it> Jack built</vi> <vi>I'll make a ghost of him <it>that</it> lets me <aq>Shakespeare</aq></vi></un></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:at which :in which :on which :by which :with which :to which <vi>each year <it>that</it> the lectures are given</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:according to what :to the extent of what <un>used after a negative <vi>has never been here <it>that</it> I know of</vi></un></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:that which</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <ssl>obsolete</ssl> <dt>:the person who</dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt><it>That, which, who:</it> In current usage <it>that</it> refers to persons or things, <it>which</it> chiefly to things and rarely to subhuman entities, <it>who</it> chiefly to persons and sometimes to animals. The notion that <it>that</it> should not be used to refer to persons is without foundation; such use is entirely standard. Because <it>that</it> has no genitive form or construction, <it>of which</it> or <it>whose</it> must be substituted for it in contexts that call for the genitive.</pt><pl>usage</pl><pt><it>That, which:</it> Although some handbooks say otherwise, <it>that</it> and <it>which</it> are both regularly used to introduce restrictive clauses in edited prose. <it>Which</it> is also used to introduce nonrestrictive clauses. <it>That</it> was formerly used to introduce nonrestrictive clauses; such use is virtually nonexistent in present-day edited prose, though it may occasionally be found in poetry.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="that[5]"><ew>that</ew><hw hindex="5">that</hw><sound><wav>that0005.wav</wav><wpr>!Dat</wpr></sound><pr>ˈt͟hat</pr><fl>adverb</fl><def><date>13th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to such an extent <vi>a nail about <it>that</it> long</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>very</sx> <sx>extremely</sx> <un>usually used with the negative <vi>did not take the festival <it>that</it> seriously <aq>Eric Goldman</aq></vi></un></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="that'n[1]"><hw>that'n[1]</hw><fl>teaser entry</fl></entry>
	<entry id="that'n[2]"><hw>that'n[2]</hw><fl>teaser entry</fl></entry>
	<entry id="say[1]"><ew>say</ew><hw hindex="1">say</hw><sound><wav>say00001.wav</wav><wpr>!sA</wpr></sound><pr>ˈsā, <it>Southern also</it> ˈse</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>said</if><sound><wav>say00002.wav</wav><wpr>!sed</wpr></sound> <pr>ˈsed, <it>especially when subject follows</it> səd</pr></in><in><if>say*ing</if><sound><wav>say00003.wav</wav><wpr>!sA-iN</wpr></sound> <pr>ˈsā-iŋ</pr></in><in><if>says</if><sound><wav>say00004.wav</wav><wpr>!sez</wpr><wav>say00006.wav</wav><wpr>!sAz</wpr></sound> <pr>ˈsez, <it>sometimes</it> ˈsāz, <it>especially when subject follows</it> səz</pr></in><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>secgan;</it> akin to Old High German <it>sagēn</it> to say, Lithuanian <it>sakyti,</it> Greek en<it>nepein</it> to speak, tell</et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to express in words :<sx>state</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to state as opinion or belief :<sx>declare</sx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:<sx>utter</sx> <sx>pronounce</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>recite</sx> <sx>repeat</sx> <vi><it>say</it> your prayers</vi></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:<sx>indicate</sx> <sx>show</sx> <vi>the clock <it>say</it><it>s</it> five minutes after twelve</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to give expression to :<sx>communicate</sx> <vi>a glance that <it>said</it> all that was necessary</vi></dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:<sx>suppose</sx> <sx>assume</sx> <vi>let's <it>say</it> you're right</vi></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <dt>:to express oneself :<sx>speak</sx></dt></def><uro><ure>say*er</ure><sound><wav>say00005.wav</wav><wpr>!sA-ur</wpr></sound> <pr>ˈsā-ər, ˈser</pr> <fl>noun</fl></uro><dro><drp>say uncle</drp> <def><dt>:to admit defeat</dt></def></dro><dro><drp>that is to say</drp> <def><dt>:in other words :in effect</dt></def></dro><dro><drp>to say nothing of</drp> <def><dt>:not to mention :and notably in addition <vi>will need more time, <it>to say nothing of</it> money</vi></dt></def></dro></entry>
	<entry id="those"><ew>those</ew><hw>those</hw><cx><cl>plural of</cl> <ct>that</ct></cx><et>Middle English, from <it>those</it> these, from Old English <it>thās,</it> plural of <it>thes</it> this <ma>this</ma></et></entry>
	<entry id="all that"><ew>all that</ew><hw>all that</hw><fl>adverb</fl><def><date>1945</date><dt>:to an indicated or suggested extent or degree :<sx>so</sx> <vi>didn't take his threats <it>all that</it> seriously</vi></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>