<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="they"><ew>they</ew><hw>they</hw><sound><wav>they0001.wav</wav><wpr>!DA</wpr></sound><pr>ˈt͟hā</pr><fl>pronoun, plural in construction</fl><et>Middle English, from Old Norse <it>their,</it> masculine plural demonstrative &amp; personal pron.; akin to Old English <it>thæt</it> that</et><def><date>13th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:those ones <un>used as third person pronoun serving as the plural of <it>he, she,</it> or <it>it</it> or referring to a group of two or more individuals not all of the same sex <vi><it>they</it> dance well</vi></un></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>he <sxn>2</sxn></sx> <un>often used with an indefinite third person singular antecedent <vi>everyone knew where <it>they</it> stood <aq>E. L. Doctorow</aq></vi> <vi>nobody has to go to school if <it>they</it> don't want to <aq><it>N. Y. Times</it></aq></vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>people <sxn>2</sxn></sx> <un>used in a generic sense <vi>as lazy as <it>they</it> come</vi></un></dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt><it>They</it> used as an indefinite subject (sense 2) is sometimes objected to on the grounds that it does not have an antecedent. Not every pronoun requires an antecedent, however. The indefinite <it>they</it> is used in all varieties of contexts and is standard.</pt><pl>usage</pl><pt><it>They, their, them, themselves:</it> English lacks a common-gender third person singular pronoun that can be used to refer to indefinite pronouns (as <it>everyone, anyone, someone</it>). Writers and speakers have supplied this lack by using the plural pronouns <vi>and every one to rest <it>themselves</it> betake <aq>Shakespeare</aq></vi> <vi>I would have everybody marry if <it>they</it> can do it properly <aq>Jane Austen</aq></vi> <vi>it is too hideous for anyone in <it>their</it> senses to buy <aq>W. H. Auden</aq></vi>. The plural pronouns have also been put to use as pronouns of indefinite number to refer to singular nouns that stand for many persons <vi>'tis meet that some more audience than a mother, since nature makes <it>them</it> partial, should o'erhear the speech <aq>Shakespeare</aq></vi> <vi>a person can't help <it>their</it> birth <aq>W. M. Thackeray</aq></vi> <vi>no man goes to battle to be killed. — But <it>they</it> do get killed <aq>G. B. Shaw</aq></vi>. The use of <it>they, their, them,</it> and <it>themselves</it> as pronouns of indefinite gender and indefinite number is well established in speech and writing, even in literary and formal contexts. This gives you the option of using the plural pronouns where you think they sound best, and of using the singular pronouns (as <it>he, she, he or she,</it> and their inflected forms) where you think they sound best.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="they'd"><ew>they'd</ew><hw>they'd</hw><sound><wav>theyd001.wav</wav><wpr>!DAd</wpr></sound><pr>ˈt͟hād</pr><def><date>1599</date><dt>:they had :they would</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="they'll"><ew>they'll</ew><hw>they'll</hw><sound><wav>theyll01.wav</wav><wpr>!DA(u)l</wpr></sound><pr>ˈt͟hāl, ˈt͟hel</pr><def><date>1567</date><dt>:they will :they shall</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="they're"><ew>they're</ew><hw>they're</hw><sound><wav>theyre01.wav</wav><wpr>!Der</wpr></sound><pr>t͟hər, ˈt͟her</pr><def><date>circa 1595</date><dt>:they are</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="they've"><ew>they've</ew><hw>they've</hw><sound><wav>theyve01.wav</wav><wpr>!DAv</wpr></sound><pr>ˈt͟hāv</pr><def><date>1611</date><dt>:they have</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="them[1]"><ew>them</ew><hw hindex="1">them</hw><sound><wav>them0001.wav</wav><wpr>!Dem</wpr></sound><pr>(t͟h)əm, ˈt͟hem, <it>after</it> p, b, v, f, <it>also</it> ᵊm</pr><fl>pronoun</fl><cx><cl>objective case of</cl> <ct>they</ct></cx><def><date>bef 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:<sx>they <sxn>1</sxn></sx> <un>used as object of a verb or preposition <vi>took <it>them</it> back</vi> <vi>gave it to <it>them</it></vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:<sx>those</sx> <un>used especially as antecedent to a relative pronoun <vi>the best of <it>them</it> that speak this speech <aq>Shakespeare</aq></vi></un> <un>used as the subject of a verb chiefly in nonstandard speech and for humorous effect <vi><it>them</it> is fighting words</vi></un></dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>