<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="understand"><ew>understand</ew><hw>un*der*stand</hw><sound><wav>unders23.wav</wav><wpr>+un-dur-!stand</wpr></sound><pr>ˌən-dər-ˈstand</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>un*der*stood</if><sound><wav>unders34.wav</wav><wpr>+un-dur-!st2d</wpr></sound> <pr>-ˈstu̇d</pr></in><in><if>un*der*stand*ing</if></in><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>understandan,</it> from <it>under</it> + <it>standan</it> to stand</et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to grasp the meaning of <vi><it>understand</it> Russian</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to grasp the reasonableness of <vi>his behavior is hard to <it>understand</it></vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to have thorough or technical acquaintance with or expertness in the practice of <vi><it>understand</it> finance</vi></dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to be thoroughly familiar with the character and propensities of <vi><it>understand</it><it>s</it> children</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to accept as a fact or truth or regard as plausible without utter certainty <vi>we <it>understand</it> that he is returning from abroad</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to interpret in one of a number of possible ways</dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to supply in thought as though expressed <vi>“to be married” is commonly <it>understood</it> after the word <it>engaged</it></vi></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to have <fw>understanding</fw> :have the power of comprehension</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to achieve a grasp of the nature, significance, or explanation of something</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to believe or infer something to be the case</dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to show a sympathetic or tolerant attitude toward something</dt></def><uro><ure>un*der*stand*abil*i*ty</ure><sound><wav>unders24.wav</wav><wpr>+un-dur-+stan-du-!bi-lu-tE</wpr></sound> <pr>-ˌstan-də-ˈbi-lə-tē</pr> <fl>noun</fl></uro><uro><ure>un*der*stand*able</ure><sound><wav>unders25.wav</wav><wpr>+un-dur-!stan-du-bul</wpr></sound> <pr>-ˈstan-də-bəl</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>understand</sc> <sc>comprehend</sc> <sc>appreciate</sc> mean to have a clear or complete idea of. <sc>understand</sc> and <sc>comprehend</sc> are very often interchangeable. <sc>understand</sc> may, however, stress the fact of having attained a firm mental grasp of something <vi>orders that were fully <it>understood</it> and promptly obeyed</vi>. <sc>comprehend</sc> may stress the process of coming to grips with something intellectually <vi>I have trouble <it>comprehending</it> your reasons for doing this</vi>. <sc>appreciate</sc> implies a just evaluation or judgment of a thing's value or nature <vi>failed to <it>appreciate</it> the risks involved</vi>.</pt></entry>
</entry_list>