<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="wander"><ew>wander</ew><subj>PS-vi3c</subj><hw>wan*der</hw><sound><wav>wander01.wav</wav><wpr>!w@n-dur</wpr></sound><pr>ˈwän-dər</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>wan*dered</if></in><in><if>wan*der*ing</if><sound><wav>wander20.wav</wav><wpr>!w@n-d(u-)riN</wpr></sound> <pr>-d(ə-)riŋ</pr></in><et>Middle English <it>wandren,</it> from Old English <it>wandrian;</it> akin to Middle High German <it>wandern</it> to wander, Old English <it>windan</it> to wind, twist</et><def><vt>intransitive verb</vt><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:to move about without a fixed course, aim, or goal</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to go idly about :<sx>ramble</sx> <vi><it>wander</it><it>ing</it> around the house</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to follow a winding course :<sx>meander</sx></dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to go astray (as from a course) :<sx>stray</sx> <vi><it>wander</it><it>ed</it> away from the group</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to go astray morally :<sx>err</sx></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to lose normal mental contact :stray in thought <vi>his mind <it>wander</it><it>ed</it></vi></dt><vt>transitive verb</vt> <dt>:to roam over <vi><it>wander</it><it>ed</it> the halls</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>wander</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro><uro><ure>wan*der*er</ure><sound><wav>wander02.wav</wav><wpr>!w@n-dur-ur</wpr></sound> <pr>-dər-ər</pr> <fl>noun</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>wander</sc> <sc>roam</sc> <sc>ramble</sc> <sc>rove</sc> <sc>traipse</sc> <sc>meander</sc> mean to go about from place to place usually without a plan or definite purpose. <sc>wander</sc> implies an absence of or an indifference to a fixed course <vi>fond of <it>wandering</it> about the square just watching the people</vi>. <sc>roam</sc> suggests wandering about freely and often far afield <vi>liked to <it>roam</it> through the woods</vi>. <sc>ramble</sc> stresses carelessness and indifference to one's course or objective <vi>the speaker <it>rambled</it> on without ever coming to the point</vi>. <sc>rove</sc> suggests vigorous and sometimes purposeful roaming <vi>armed brigands <it>roved</it> over the countryside</vi>. <sc>traipse</sc> implies a course that is erratic but may sometimes be purposeful <vi><it>traipsed</it> all over town looking for the right dress</vi>. <sc>meander</sc> implies a winding or intricate course suggestive of aimless or listless wandering <vi>the river <it>meanders</it> for miles through rich farmland</vi>.</pt></entry>
</entry_list>