<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="weak"><ew>weak</ew><subj>GR-7#GR-8#EC-9#CH-10#MD-1a#MB-5b#PS-2a#GV-6a</subj><hw>weak</hw><sound><wav>weak0001.wav</wav><wpr>!wEk</wpr></sound><pr>ˈwēk</pr><fl>adjective</fl><et>Middle English <it>weike,</it> from Old Norse <it>veikr;</it> akin to Old English <it>wīcan</it> to yield, Greek <it>eikein</it> to give way, Sanskrit <it>vijate</it> he speeds, flees</et><def><date>14th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt> :lacking strength: as</dt>  <sn>a</sn> <dt>:deficient in physical vigor :<sx>feeble</sx> <sx>debilitated</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not able to sustain or exert much weight, pressure, or strain</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:not able to resist external force or withstand attack </dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:easily upset or nauseated <vi>a <it>weak</it> stomach</vi></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:mentally or intellectually deficient</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:not firmly decided :<sx>vacillating</sx></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:resulting from or indicating lack of judgment or discernment</dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:not able to withstand temptation or persuasion <vi>the spirit is willing but the flesh is <it>weak</it></vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:not factually grounded or logically presented <vi>a <it>weak</it> argument</vi></dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:not able to function properly <vi><it>weak</it> eyes</vi></dt>  <sn>b <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:lacking skill or proficiency <vi>tutoring for <it>weak</it><it>er</it> students</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:indicative of a lack of skill or aptitude <vi>history was my <it>weak</it><it>est</it> subject</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:wanting in vigor of expression or effect <vi>a <it>weak</it> translation of the poem</vi></dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:deficient in the usual or required ingredients :<sx>dilute</sx> <vi><it>weak</it> coffee</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:lacking normal intensity or potency <vi>a <it>weak</it> radio signal</vi> <vi>a <it>weak</it> strain of virus</vi></dt> <sn>6 a</sn> <dt>:not having or exerting authority or political power <vi><it>weak</it> government</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>ineffective</sx> <sx>impotent</sx></dt> <sn>7</sn> <dt>:of, relating to, or constituting a verb or verb conjugation that in English forms the past tense and past participle by adding the suffix <it>-ed</it> or <it>-d</it> or <it>-t</it></dt> <sn>8 a</sn> <dt>:bearing the minimal degree of stress occurring in the language <vi>a <it>weak</it> syllable</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:having little or no stress and obscured vowel sound <vi><it>'d</it> in <it>he'd</it> is the <it>weak</it> form of <it>would</it></vi></dt> <sn>9</sn> <dt>:tending toward a lower price or value <vi>a <it>weak</it> market</vi> <vi>a <it>weak</it> dollar</vi></dt> <sn>10</sn> <dt>:ionizing only slightly in solution <vi><it>weak</it> acids and bases</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>weak*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>weak</sc> <sc>feeble</sc> <sc>frail</sc> <sc>fragile</sc> <sc>infirm</sc> <sc>decrepit</sc> mean not strong enough to endure strain, pressure, or strenuous effort. <sc>weak</sc> applies to deficiency or inferiority in strength or power of any sort <vi>felt <it>weak</it> after the surgery</vi>. <sc>feeble</sc> suggests extreme weakness inviting pity or contempt <vi>a <it>feeble</it> attempt to walk</vi>. <sc>frail</sc> implies delicacy and slightness of constitution or structure <vi>a <it>frail</it> teenager unable to enjoy sports</vi>. <sc>fragile</sc> suggests frailty and brittleness unable to resist rough usage <vi>a reclusive poet too <it>fragile</it> for the rigors of this world</vi>. <sc>infirm</sc> suggests instability, unsoundness, and insecurity due to old age or crippling illness <vi><it>infirm</it> residents requiring constant care</vi>. <sc>decrepit</sc> implies being worn-out or broken-down from long use or old age <vi>the dowager's <it>decrepit</it> retainers</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="weak anthropic principle"><ew>weak anthropic principle</ew><grp>weak anthropic</grp><grp>weak principle</grp><grp>anthropic principle</grp><subj>PH#AS</subj><hw>weak anthropic principle</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1985</date><dt>:<sx>anthropic principle <sxn>a</sxn></sx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="weak force"><ew>weak force</ew><subj>PY</subj><hw>weak force</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1968</date><dt>:a fundamental physical force that governs interactions between hadrons and leptons (as in the emission and absorption of neutrinos) and is responsible for particle decay processes (as beta decay) in radioactivity, that is 10<sup>-5</sup> times the strength of the strong force, and that acts over distances smaller than those between nucleons in an atomic nucleus <ca>called also <cat>weak interaction</cat> <cat>weak nuclear force</cat></ca> <dx>compare <dxt>electromagnetism <dxn>2a</dxn></dxt> <dxt>gravity <dxn>3a(2)</dxn></dxt> <dxt>strong force</dxt></dx></dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="weak-kneed"><ew>weak-kneed</ew><hw>weak–kneed</hw><sound><wav>weakk01w.wav</wav><wpr>!wEk-!nEd</wpr></sound><pr>ˈwēk-ˈnēd</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1863</date><dt>:lacking willpower or resolution</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="weak-minded"><ew>weak-minded</ew><hw>weak–mind*ed</hw><sound><wav>weakm01w.wav</wav><wpr>!wEk-!mIn-dud</wpr></sound><pr>ˈwēk-ˈmīn-dəd</pr><fl>adjective</fl><def><date>1592</date><dt> :having or indicating a weak mind:</dt>  <sn>a</sn> <dt>:lacking in judgment or good sense :<sx>foolish</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:<sx>feebleminded</sx> </dt></def><uro><ure>weak–mind*ed*ness</ure> <fl>noun</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="weak side"><ew>weak side</ew><subj>SF</subj><hw>weak side</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1940</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:the side of a football formation having the smaller number of players</dt> <sd>specifically</sd> <dt>:the side of a formation away from the tight end</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the side of a court or field (as in basketball or soccer) away from the ball</dt></def><uro><ure>weak*side</ure><sound><wav>weaksi01.wav</wav><wpr>!wEk-+sId</wpr></sound> <pr>ˈwēk-ˌsīd</pr> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>
	<entry id="weak sister"><ew>weak sister</ew><hw>weak sister</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1857</date><dt>:a member of a group who needs aid</dt> <sd>also</sd> <dt>:something weak and ineffective as compared with others in a group</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>