<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="who"><ew>who</ew><hw>who</hw><sound><wav>who00001.wav</wav><wpr>!hU</wpr></sound><pr>ˈhü, ü</pr><fl>pronoun</fl><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>hwā;</it> akin to Old High German <it>hwer,</it> interrog. pron., who, Latin <it>quis,</it> Greek <it>tis,</it> Latin <it>qui,</it> relative pron., who</et><def><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:what or which person or persons <un>used as an interrogative <vi><it>who</it> was elected?</vi> <vi>find out <it>who</it> they are</vi></un> <un>used by speakers on all educational levels and by many reputable writers, though disapproved by some grammarians, as the object of a verb or a following preposition <vi><it>who</it> did I see but a Spanish lady <aq>Padraic Colum</aq></vi> <vi>do not know <it>who</it> the message is from <aq>G. K. Chesterton</aq></vi></un></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the person or persons that :<sx>whoever</sx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt><un>used as a function word to introduce a relative clause</un> <un>used especially in reference to persons <vi>my father, <it>who</it> was a lawyer</vi> but also in reference to groups <vi>a generation <it>who</it> had known nothing but war <aq>R. B. West</aq></vi> or to animals <vi>dogs <it>who</it>…fawn all over tramps <aq>Nigel Balchin</aq></vi> or to inanimate objects especially with the implication that the reference is really to a person <vi>earlier sources <it>who</it> maintain a Davidic ancestry <aq>F. M. Cross</aq></vi></un> <un>used by speakers on all educational levels and by many reputable writers, though disapproved by some grammarians, as the object of a verb or a following preposition <vi>a character <it>who</it> we are meant to pity <aq><it>Times Literary Supplement</it></aq></vi></un></dt><us>whom, that</us></def><dro><drp>as who</drp> <def><ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:as one that :as if someone</dt></def></dro><dro><drp>as who should say</drp> <def><ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:so to speak</dt></def></dro><dro><drp>who is who</drp> <vr><vl>or</vl> <va>who's who</va> <vl>or</vl> <va>who was who</va> </vr> <def><dt>:the identity of or the noteworthy facts about each of a number of persons</dt></def></dro></entry>
	<entry id="WHO"><ew>WHO</ew><subj>MD</subj><hw>WHO</hw><fl>abbreviation</fl><def><dt>World Health Organization</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="who'd"><ew>who'd</ew><hw>who'd</hw><sound><wav>whod0001.wav</wav><wpr>!hUd</wpr></sound><pr>ˈhüd</pr><def><date>1640</date><dt>:who had :who would</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="whom"><ew>whom</ew><hw>whom</hw><sound><wav>whom0001.wav</wav><wpr>!hUm</wpr></sound><pr>ˈhüm, üm</pr><fl>pronoun</fl><cx><cl>objective case of</cl> <ct>who</ct></cx><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>hwām,</it> dative of <it>hwā</it> who</et><def><date>before 12th century</date><dt><un>used as an interrogative or relative</un> <un>used as object of a verb or a preceding preposition <vi>to know for <it>whom</it> the bell tolls <aq>John Donne</aq></vi> or less frequently as the object of a following preposition <vi>the man <it>whom</it> you wrote to</vi> though now often considered stilted especially as an interrogative and especially in oral use</un> <un>occasionally used as predicate nominative with a copulative verb or as subject of a verb especially in the vicinity of a preposition or a verb of which it might mistakenly be considered the object <vi><it>whom</it> say ye that I am <aq>Matthew 16:15 (Authorized Version)</aq></vi> <vi>people…<it>whom</it> you never thought would sympathize <aq>Shea Murphy</aq></vi></un></dt></def><pl>usage</pl><pt>Observers of the language have been predicting the demise of <it>whom</it> from about 1870 down to the present day <vi>one of the pronoun cases is visibly disappearing—the objective case <it>whom</it> <aq>R. G. White (1870)</aq></vi> <vi><it>whom</it> is dying out in England, where “Whom did you see?” sounds affected <aq>Anthony Burgess (1980)</aq></vi>. Our evidence shows that no one—English or not—should expect <it>whom</it> to disappear momentarily; it shows every indication of persisting quite a while yet. Actual usage of <it>who</it> and <it>whom</it>—accurately described at the entries in this dictionary—does not appear to be markedly different from the usage of Shakespeare's time. But the 18th century grammarians, propounding rules and analogies, rejecting other rules and analogies, and usually justifying both with appeals to Latin or Greek, have intervened between us and Shakespeare. It seems clear that the grammarians' rules have had little effect on the traditional uses. One thing they have accomplished is to encourage hypercorrect uses of <it>whom</it> <vi><it>whom</it> shall I say is calling?</vi>. Another is that they have made some people unsure of themselves <vi>said he was asked to step down, although it is not known exactly <it>who</it> or <it>whom</it> asked him <aq><it>Redding (Connecticut) Pilot</it></aq></vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="who's who"><ew>who's who</ew><subj>IS-1#PU-1#IS-3#PU-3</subj><hw>who's who</hw><sound><wav>whos0001.wav</wav><wpr>+hUz-!hU</wpr></sound><pr>ˌhüz-ˈhü</pr><fl>noun</fl><lb>often capitalized both Ws</lb><def><date>1917</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:a compilation of brief biographical sketches of prominent persons in a particular field <vi>a <it>who's who</it> of sports figures</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the leaders of a group :<sx>elite</sx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:a listing or grouping of notable persons or things</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>