<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="worry[1]"><ew>worry</ew><subj>MD-vt1#MD-vi1</subj><hw hindex="1">wor*ry</hw><sound><wav>worry001.wav</wav><wpr>!wur-E</wpr></sound><pr>ˈwər-ē, ˈwə-rē</pr><fl>verb</fl><in><if>wor*ried</if></in><in><if>wor*ry*ing</if></in><et>Middle English <it>worien,</it> from Old English <it>wyrgan;</it> akin to Old High German <it>wurgen</it> to strangle, Lithuanian <it>veržti</it> to constrict</et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>dialect British</ssl> <dt>:<sx>choke</sx> <sx>strangle</sx></dt> <sn>2 a</sn> <dt>:to harass by tearing, biting, or snapping especially at the throat</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to shake or pull at with the teeth <vi>a terrier <it>worry</it><it>ing</it> a rat</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to touch or disturb something repeatedly</dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to change the position of or adjust by repeated pushing or hauling</dt> <sn>3 a</sn> <dt>:to assail with rough or aggressive attack or treatment :<sx>torment</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to subject to persistent or nagging attention or effort</dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to afflict with mental distress or agitation :make anxious</dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>dialect British</ssl> <dt>:<sx>strangle</sx> <sx>choke</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to move, proceed, or progress by unceasing or difficult effort :<sx>struggle</sx></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to feel or experience concern or anxiety :<sx>fret</sx> <vi><it>worry</it><it>ing</it> about his health</vi></dt></def><uro><ure>wor*ried*ly</ure><sound><wav>worrie01.wav</wav><wpr>!wu-(r)Ed-lE</wpr></sound> <pr>-(r)ēd-lē, -(r)əd-</pr> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><uro><ure>wor*ri*er</ure><sound><wav>worrie02.wav</wav><wpr>!wu-(r)E-ur</wpr></sound> <pr>-(r)ē-ər</pr> <fl>noun</fl></uro><uro><ure>wor*ry*ing*ly</ure> <fl>adverb</fl></uro><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>worry</sc> <sc>annoy</sc> <sc>harass</sc> <sc>harry</sc> <sc>plague</sc> <sc>pester</sc> <sc>tease</sc> mean to disturb or irritate by persistent acts. <sc>worry</sc> implies an incessant goading or attacking that drives one to desperation <vi>pursued a policy of <it>worrying</it> the enemy</vi>. <sc>annoy</sc> implies disturbing one's composure or peace of mind by intrusion, interference, or petty attacks <vi>you're doing that just to <it>annoy</it> me</vi>. <sc>harass</sc> implies petty persecutions or burdensome demands that exhaust one's nervous or mental power <vi><it>harassed</it> on all sides by creditors</vi>. <sc>harry</sc> may imply heavy oppression or maltreatment <vi>the strikers had been <it>harried</it> by thugs</vi>. <sc>plague</sc> implies a painful and persistent affliction <vi><it>plagued</it> all her life by poverty</vi>. <sc>pester</sc> stresses the repetition of petty attacks <vi>constantly <it>pestered</it> with trivial complaints</vi>. <sc>tease</sc> suggests an attempt to break down one's resistance or rouse to wrath <vi>children <it>teased</it> the dog</vi>.</pt></entry>
	<entry id="worry[2]"><ew>worry</ew><hw hindex="2">worry</hw><fl>noun</fl><in><il>plural</il> <if>worries</if></in><def><date>1804</date> <sn>1 a</sn> <dt>:mental distress or agitation resulting from concern usually for something impending or anticipated :<sx>anxiety</sx></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:an instance or occurrence of such distress or agitation</dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:a cause of worry :<sx>trouble</sx> <sx>difficulty</sx></dt><ss>care</ss></def></entry>
	<entry id="worry beads"><ew>worry beads</ew><hw>worry beads</hw><fl>noun plural</fl><def><date>1956</date><dt>:a string of beads that can be fingered to keep one's hands occupied</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="worry line"><ew>worry line</ew><subj>MD#FH</subj><hw>worry line</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>1972</date><dt>:a crease or wrinkle on the forehead or between the eyebrows</dt></def></entry>
</entry_list>