<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<entry_list version="1.0">
	<entry id="yield[1]"><ew>yield</ew><subj>EC-vt4c#SB-vt5#GV-vi6#BI-vt4a,b#AG-vt4a,b#BI-vi1#AG-vi1</subj><hw hindex="1">yield</hw><sound><wav>yield001.wav</wav><wpr>!yE(u)ld</wpr></sound><pr>ˈyēld</pr><fl>verb</fl><et>Middle English, from Old English <it>gieldan;</it> akin to Old High German <it>geltan</it> to pay</et><def><vt>transitive verb</vt><date>before 12th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <ssl>archaic</ssl> <dt>:<sx>recompense</sx> <sx>reward</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to give or render as fitting, rightfully owed, or required</dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt> :to give up possession of on claim or demand: as</dt>  <sn>a</sn> <dt>:to give up (as one's breath) and so die</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to surrender or relinquish to the physical control of another :hand over possession of</dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to surrender or submit (oneself) to another</dt>  <sn>d</sn> <dt>:to give (oneself) up to an inclination, temptation, or habit</dt>  <sn>e</sn> <dt>:to relinquish one's possession of (as a position of advantage or point of superiority) <vi><it>yield</it> precedence</vi> </dt> <sn>4 a</sn> <dt>:to bear or bring forth as a natural product especially as a result of cultivation <vi>the tree always <it>yield</it><it>s</it> good fruit</vi></dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to produce or furnish as return <vi>this soil should <it>yield</it> good crops</vi></dt>  <sn>c <snp>(1)</snp></sn> <dt>:to produce as return from an expenditure or investment :furnish as profit or interest <vi>a bond that <it>yield</it><it>s</it> 12 percent</vi></dt>  <sn><snp>(2)</snp></sn> <dt>:to produce as revenue :<sx>bring in</sx> <vi>the tax is expected to <it>yield</it> millions</vi></dt> <sn>5</sn> <dt>:to give up (as a hit or run) in baseball <vi><it>yield</it><it>ed</it> two runs in the third inning</vi></dt><vt>intransitive verb</vt> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:to be fruitful or productive :<sx>bear</sx> <sx>produce</sx></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:to give up and cease resistance or contention :<sx>submit</sx> <sx>succumb</sx> <vi>facing an enemy who would not <it>yield</it></vi> <vi><it>yield</it><it>ing</it> to temptation</vi></dt> <sn>3</sn> <dt>:to give way to pressure or influence :submit to urging, persuasion, or entreaty</dt> <sn>4</sn> <dt>:to give way under physical force (as bending, stretching, or breaking)</dt> <sn>5 a</sn> <dt>:to give place or precedence :acknowledge the superiority of someone else</dt>  <sn>b</sn> <dt>:to be inferior <vi>our dictionary <it>yield</it><it>s</it> to none</vi></dt>  <sn>c</sn> <dt>:to give way to or become succeeded by someone or something else</dt> <sn>6</sn> <dt>:to relinquish the floor of a legislative assembly</dt></def><pl>syn</pl><pt><sc>yield</sc> <sc>submit</sc> <sc>capitulate</sc> <sc>succumb</sc> <sc>relent</sc> <sc>defer</sc> mean to give way to someone or something that one can no longer resist. <sc>yield</sc> may apply to any sort or degree of giving way before force, argument, persuasion, or entreaty <vi><it>yields</it> too easily in any argument</vi>. <sc>submit</sc> suggests full surrendering after resistance or conflict to the will or control of another <vi>a repentant sinner vowing to <it>submit</it> to the will of God</vi>. <sc>capitulate</sc> stresses the fact of ending all resistance and may imply either a coming to terms (as with an adversary) or hopelessness in the face of an irresistible opposing force <vi>officials <it>capitulated</it> to the protesters' demands</vi>. <sc>succumb</sc> implies weakness and helplessness to the one that gives way or an overwhelming power to the opposing force <vi>a stage actor <it>succumbing</it> to the lure of Hollywood</vi>. <sc>relent</sc> implies a yielding through pity or mercy by one who holds the upper hand <vi>finally <it>relented</it> and let the children stay up late</vi>. <sc>defer</sc> implies a voluntary yielding or submitting out of respect or reverence for or deference and affection toward another <vi>I <it>defer</it> to your expertise in these matters</vi>.</pt><sa>relinquish</sa></entry>
	<entry id="yield[2]"><ew>yield</ew><subj>CH-1#BI#AG</subj><hw hindex="2">yield</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>15th century</date> <sn>1</sn> <dt>:something <fw>yielded</fw> :<sx>product</sx></dt> <sd>especially</sd> <dt>:the amount or quantity produced or returned <vi><it>yield</it> of wheat per acre</vi></dt> <sn>2</sn> <dt>:the capacity of <fw>yielding</fw> produce</dt></def></entry>
	<entry id="sustained yield"><ew>sustained yield</ew><subj>WP#AH#EO</subj><hw>sustained yield</hw><fl>noun</fl><def><date>circa 1905</date><dt>:production of a biological resource (as timber or fish) under management procedures which ensure replacement of the part harvested by regrowth or reproduction before another harvest occurs</dt></def><uro><ure>sustained–yield</ure> <fl>adjective</fl></uro></entry>
</entry_list>